<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>info on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/categories/info/</link>
    <description>Recent content in info on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jasoneckert.github.io/categories/info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1. Operating Systems</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/operatingsystems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/operatingsystems/</guid>
      <description>UNIX UNIX is the grandfather of all modern operating systems, and today it still remains the most powerful and least known. But if you use an Apple computer running macOS, or an iPhone or iPad running iOS, you are using a UNIX operating system. And if you do online banking, somewhere tucked away in the bank is likely a series of UNIX systems running Oracle Solaris UNIX, HP-UX UNIX, or AIX UNIX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Retro Computers</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/retrocomputers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/retrocomputers/</guid>
      <description>Apple Apple Computer was founded by Steve Wozniak and Steve Jobs in 1976. Steve Wozniak provided the technical genius for computer creation, while Steve Jobs provided the expertise in marketing and design. Their first major commercially adopted product was the Apple II in 1977, which had a MOS 6502 CPU (also used in Commodore computers such as the Commodore 64) and shipped with BASIC and the DOS operating system (later versions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Arcade Games</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/arcadegames/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/arcadegames/</guid>
      <description>Growing up in the 80s was awesome! One of the best things about growing up in the 80s for me was that I developed a love of video games. I loved spending time at the arcade playing the classics like Tempest, Missile Command and Galaga. At home, we had an Atari 2600 and later a Nintendo NES. I loved it all.
In recent years, I purchased my absolute favourite arcade games of all time&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Tech Flicks</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techflicks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techflicks/</guid>
      <description>100 Yen: The Japanese Arcade Experience (2012)
2001: Space Odyssey (1968)
8 Bit Generation: The Commodore Wars (2016)
Antitrust (2001)
Blade Runner (1982)
Bright (2017)
Chasing Ghosts: Beyond the Arcade (2007)
Cloak and Dagger (1984)
Contact (1997)
Die Hard 4: Live Free or Die Hard (2007)
Every Star Wars and Star Trek movie (from the 1970s+)
Fanboys (2008)
Freedom Downtime (2001)
Funspot: A Small Documentary on the World&amp;rsquo;s Largest Video Game Arcade (2016)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Tech T-Shirt Slogans</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techshirts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techshirts/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t Anthropomorphize computers. They hate that.
I void warranties
I read your email
Linux isn&amp;rsquo;t magic. It&amp;rsquo;s sudo-science.
Kids: Don&amp;rsquo;t try this at ~
Code poet
Byte Me
I see dead pixels
cd /pub; more beer
No, I will not fix your computer
There is no place like 127.0.0.1
There is no place like ::1
Bow before me for I am root
Dilbert is NOT fiction
It must be user error</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6. Tech Humour and Puns</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techhumour/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techhumour/</guid>
      <description>I feel someone needs to start a house-call backup business where someone could pull up to your home (or business) in a car that has a big NAS box in the back, and then perform off-site backups across Ethernet for a fee. They could call it NASCAR.
If I was Voldemort I would have hidden a horcrux in HP&amp;rsquo;s documentation.
NFTs make excellent gifts. After all, they&amp;rsquo;re GIF certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7. The RISCy Hipster</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/theriscyhipster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/theriscyhipster/</guid>
      <description>RISC (reduced instruction set computer) is a computer processor design that performs fewer instructions at higher speeds compared to CISC (complex instruction set computer). In the early days of computing, CISC allowed developers to rapidly create software with fewer instructions that would additionally consume less disk space. However, by the late 1980s, many argued that advances in software development tools and technology made these benefits irrelevant, and that RISC designs would be necessary to advance computer performance in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
