<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200627" date="2020-06-28 02:22:04 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;SSDs - You have no excuse not to buy one...&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Thursday, June 23, 2016&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;In my classroom, we use removable hard drives in our Corei7 PCs to run our software and virtual machines (e.g. Microsoft Exchange Server, Windows Server 2012, etc.).  My instructor computer is connected to two overhead projectors that both sides of the room can see to allow me to walk students through how to configure key technologies.&#xD;&#xD;However, when I&#x2019;m walking students through something on my projectors, I often have to keep a particular configuration screen open on my computer so that all students can enter the same settings before I move on.  This means that by the time I move on, most of my students have moved on already and I&#x2019;m often stuck waiting for my computer to apply the changes (which could take seconds or even minutes depending on what I&#x2019;m configuring).&#xD;&#xD;Then, about a month ago, I saw the 120GB ADATA SSD shown above at Canada Computers for under $45 (the 480GB model was $135).  So I picked one up and put it in my removable hard drive caddy and installed my class software on it with the hopes that it would be MUCH faster than the hard drive I was using previously so that I could keep pace with my students when configuring software on my projector ;-)&#xD;&#xD;And, yes......it did exactly that....plus more.  Moving from a hard drive to an SSD means that my machine is lightning fast!  Tasks that take student computers 30 seconds to apply typically take my computer about 2 seconds.  I can now leave my configuration screens open for students without fear that students will be waiting for my computer to finish applying the changes when I get around to pressing Next.&#xD;&#xD;Now....I should mention that this drive is NOT a high-end SSD like the screaming fast Samsung 950Pro SSD that I have in my home computer.  In fact, ADATA it&#x2019;s the cheapest one on the market.  But online reviews gave it a stellar rating for it&#x2019;s performance and price point (mainly due to its well-performing Hynix NAND chips), and the difference it made in my classroom is quite simply, incredible.  &#xD;&#xD;With cheap SSDs making such a big difference to computer performance, there&#x2019;s no reason for anyone to second-thing buying an SSD for their own computer.  At very high capacities (1TB+), they are still far more expensive than a hard disk, but you can get the best of both worlds by using both an SSD and a hard drive. Simply buy a low capacity SSD (120GB, for example) to install your operating system and applications on.  Then, you can use your existing hard drive (2TB, for example) to store all of your data, movies, music, games, and so on.  In other words, your SSD will be your C:\, and your hard drive will be your D:\.  Your machine will run incredibly fast because the &#x201C;frequently-accessed&#x201D; operating system and applications are running from the SSD, and all of the other data (that is accessed &#x201C;on-demand&#x201D; only) is stored on the hard drive.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="23_SSDs_-_You_have_no_excuse_not_to_buy_one..._files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
