<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FSF on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/fsf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FSF on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/fsf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario Linux Fest</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/ontario-linux-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/ontario-linux-fest/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I teamed up with and old friend of mine (Scott Elliott) and went to the Ontario Linux Fest at the Toronto Congress Centre. For those who do not know Scott, he is a VMWare guru (you can join his Southwestern Ontario VMWare user’s group @ www.vmware.com), as well as a master in the 8th layer of the OSI Model (the political layer). Although he won’t admit it, he knows UNIX very well and is an advocate of the Open Source movement even though he works mainly with Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More about Open Source Software and Linux</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/more-about-open-source-software-and-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/more-about-open-source-software-and-linux/</guid>
      <description>In light of the upcoming Ontario Linux Fest, I decided to use this blog entry to reflect on Open Source Software and Linux.
Free Software and the Free Software Foundation (FSF) were pioneered by the famous Richard Stallman. Free Software does not mean “at no monetary cost”&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;..it means that the source code is free to anyone who wants to use it (source code freedom). In the words of Stallman, think “free” as in “freedom”, not “free” as in “free beer”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Richard Stallman talk at UW</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/richard-stallman-talk-at-uw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/richard-stallman-talk-at-uw/</guid>
      <description>On July 6th, Richard Stallman gave a talk at the University of Waterloo regarding copyright and its evils. Although slow at the beginning (perhaps because Richard was still finishing his Pepsi and introducing the features of copyright), it turned out to be a powerful and enlightening educational experience.
I decided not to write a blog about it until I was able to view it again on video after my vacation and make specific notes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>