<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CompTIA on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/comptia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CompTIA on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/comptia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 in review...</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2019-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2019-in-review/</guid>
      <description>This year was flat-out awesome! I can’t think of many years in the past decade that had the same amount of academic, physical, and personal fulfillment all in one year!
On the academic side, I presented a 12-week Linux+ webinar series at night to IT instructors worldwide for the Computing Technology Industry Association (CompTIA) Instructor Network.
This, of course, fit well since I just finished writing the 5th edition of my Linux textbook for Cengage (Linux+ &amp;amp; LPIC Guide to Linux Certification).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 in review...</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2018-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2018-in-review/</guid>
      <description>At the end of each year, I take some time to reflect on the previous year - it provides perspective, and is a lot of fun!
For me, 2018 was the year I spent a lot of time improving myself physically, challenging myself mentally, and most importantly, enjoying life!
On the personal side, I cut out the bad foods from my diet:
 breads starches alcohol  On top of this, I upped my indoor and outdoor exercise to lose a whopping 85 pounds since mid 2017 - I feel great, have loads of energy, and no longer have any back pain whatsoever!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>