<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200627" date="2020-06-28 02:21:46 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Game ON 2.0&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Saturday, March 2, 2013&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;In one week, the world&#x2019;s largest video game exhibition is coming to the Ontario Science Centre for 6 months (March 9th to September 2nd).  In essence, Game ON 2.0 showcases the history and evolution of video games over the past 50 years, as well as their cultural impact.&#xD;&#xD;I run the technology faculties at triOS College, and our Video Game Development faculty provides the best video game programming education in all of Ontario!&#xA0; As a result, our college is the official presentation sponsor, and I&#x2019;ve been very busy these past months designing our part of the exhibition.....a section where people can explore game development!&#xD;&#xD;We&#x2019;ll have interactive displays and stations where visitors can explore virtually everything about video game development, as well as a section that is manned by our video game programming students in Toronto who are currently developing an independent (or &#x201C;indie&#x201D;) game.&#xA0; Visitors will be able to see them in action on their Alienware, as well as playtest parts of their game as it is being developed! &#xD;&#xD;We&#x2019;ll also have two people at our booth at all times who can answer visitors questions, as well as provide additional information about game development, video game history, the exhibits in Game ON 2.0, and more!&#xA0; If you are there, say Hi to them - their names are Chris and Felicia.&#xD;&#xD;These next 6 months are going to be absolutely awesome, and you can definitely expect many more blog posts from me about the event.&#xA0;&#xA0; But for now, I&#x2019;ll leave it at that.&#xA0; Just remember that next week........it&#x2019;s on like Donkey Kong!&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="2_Game_ON_2.0_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
