<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:55:40 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;How to please your IT department...&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Monday, August 4, 2008&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;1. When you call us to have your computer moved, be sure to leave it buried under half a ton of postcards, baby pictures, stuffed animals, dried flowers, bowling trophies and children&#x2019;s art. We don&#x2019;t have a life, and we find it deeply moving to catch a fleeting glimpse of yours.&#xD;&#xD;2. Don&#x2019;t write anything down. Ever. We can play back the error messages from here.&#xD;&#xD;3. When an IT person says he&#x2019;s coming right over, go for coffee. That way you won&#x2019;t be there when we need your password. It&#x2019;s nothing for us to remember 700 screen saver passwords.&#xD;&#xD;4. When you call the help desk, state what you want, not what&#x2019;s keeping you from getting it. We don&#x2019;t need to know that you can&#x2019;t get into your mail because your computer won&#x2019;t power on at all.&#xD;&#xD;5. When IT support sends you an e-mail with high importance, delete it at once. We&#x2019;re just testing.&#xD;&#xD;6. When an IT person is eating lunch at his desk, walk right in and spill your guts right out. We exist only to serve.&#xD;&#xD;7. Send urgent e-mail all in uppercase. The mail server picks it up and flags it as a rush delivery.&#xD;&#xD;8. When the photocopier doesn&#x2019;t work, call computer support. There are electronics in it.&#xD;&#xD;9. When something&#x2019;s wrong with your home PC, dump it on an IT person&#x2019;s chair with no name, no phone number and no description of the problem. We love a puzzle.&#xD;&#xD;10. When an IT person tells you that computer screens don&#x2019;t have cartridges in them, argue. We love a good argument.&#xD;&#xD;11. When an IT person tells you that he&#x2019;ll be there shortly, reply in a scathing tone of voice: &#x201C;And just how many weeks do you mean by shortly?&#x201D; That motivates us.&#xD;&#xD;12. When the printer won&#x2019;t print, re-send the job at least 20 times. Print jobs frequently get sucked into black holes.&#xD;&#xD;13. When the printer still won&#x2019;t print after 20 tries, send the job to all 68 printers in the company. One of them is bound to work.&#xD;&#xD;14. Don&#x2019;t learn the proper term for anything technical. We know exactly what you mean by &#x201C;My thingy blew up.&#x201D;&#xD;&#xD;15. Don&#x2019;t use on-line help. On-line help is for wimps.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="4_How_to_please_your_IT_department..._files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
