<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:57:37 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Apple turns 40 today&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, April 1, 2016&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Apple Computer (now just &#x201C;Apple&#x201D;) started on April 1st, 1976.&#xD;&#xD;Now, you may be wondering &#x201C;Why dedicate a blog post to some computer company that turned 40 years old?!?&#x201D;  And, honestly, I must admit that I rarely like to personify corporations......but Apple is a different story altogether, and it&#x2019;s history is worth reflecting on in a blog post.&#xD;&#xD;Apple mainly started with the two Steves:  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (marketing/sales/vision), and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Steve Wozniak&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (engineer). &#xD;&#xD;Their first wildly-successful product (the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Apple II &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;computer, shown right) quickly became the most famous personal computer (PC) used everywhere (alongside Commodore, of course).  &#xD;&#xD;In Grade 2, my school got a whole lab full of Commodore 64s, but it was the Apple IIs that we had in the library that I spent most of my time on.  There were a multitude of games and learning software available for it. In fact, you could find Apple IIs in most classrooms up until the early 1990s (it was an incredibly long-lived PC).  My favorite model of the Apple II was the Apple IIc, and I still have one of them in my basement - due to rugged Apple manufacturing, it works like new and will probably still work in 20 years!&#xD; &#xD;In 1984, Apple released the famous graphical PC, the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Macintosh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, which was incredibly revolutionary for it&#x2019;s time.  If you use a vintage Macintosh from the 1980s today, you&#x2019;ll be shocked at how much it feels like a modern operating system.  That&#x2019;s because it basically paved the way for modern operating systems ;-)&#xD;&#xD;The Macintosh (or Mac) line was Apple&#x2019;s main product line from that point onwards.  By the late 80s, Apple had grown into a massive multi-billion-dollar company.  The two Steves had left by this time, and Apple found itself competing with the massive onslaught of IBM-compatible PCs and clones (e.g. Intel 386, 486 and Pentium PCs).  By the mid 1990s, all of the other computer vendors of the 80s had died out (including Commodore and Tandy), and you had only two choices when buying a computer: an Apple Mac, or an IBM-compatible PC (which were just called &#x201C;PCs&#x201D; by this time).  PCs had 10 times the market share and software than a Mac had, so Apple was dying a quick death.  &#xD;&#xD;I saw this too - by the early 1990s, I had a Twinhead 386 PC that was far more powerful and far cheaper than the state-of-the-art Macs we had in our math computer labs at the University of Waterloo.  We used to call Mac computers &#x201C;beige toasters&#x201D; back in the early 90s because they were beige in color and about as powerful as a toaster.   It&#x2019;s worth mentioning, however, that Apple had the best laptops of the early-mid 1990s - Apple definitely led the way when it came to laptop innovations.  However, with an average price tag of $5000, laptops of any brand in the 90s were a luxury item that most people couldn&#x2019;t afford.  Bottom line - if you were into computers in the 1990s, you probably forgot about Apple.&#xD;&#xD;By 1997, everyone thought Apple would soon be dead.  When asked what he'd do with Apple, Michael Dell (of Dell Computer) said &#x201C;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;What would I do? I'd shut it down&#xA0;and give the money back to the shareholders.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#x201D;&#xD;&#xD;However, Apple had one last reprieve, and it was a good one.  In 1997, Steve Jobs returned to a near-bankrupt Apple after running a few other businesses, including the successful Pixar animation company, and the not-so-successful UNIX computer company called NeXT.  With his return, NeXT was purchased by Apple and the powerful NeXTStep UNIX operating system eventually became the Mac OS X operating system we have today.&#xD;&#xD;After Steve Jobs&#x2019; return, Apple started innovating again - Jobs made it clear that he was now the only one in strict control of the company vision. In 1998, they released the&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; iMac&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - an all-in-one and easy-to-use Mac that was meant for browsing the Internet, ripping music, and so on.  Although it ran the old Mac OS (called OS 9), it was a massive success, and software vendors started flocking back to the platform.  By 2000, there were more educational software titles for Mac than for PC, and pretty much every school purchased iMacs in droves. &#xD;&#xD;When the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;OS X&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; operating system was released in 2001 on Macs, it caught my attention....finally, Macs had a really good operating system, and you could run all of your OS 9 software in it using something called the Classic Environment.  I stood in line for 3 hours to get an eMac (the educational version of an iMac) on Boxing Day in 2002.  My daughter used that computer the most, because I bought some great educational games for it (Dinosaur Adventure 3D and Uncle Albert&#x2019;s Magical Adventure).&#xD;&#xD;In 2005, I got an iMac G5 as my main workstation (it was very powerful compared to PCs at the time) and fell in love with OS X - it is an elegant, powerful, and easy-to-use operating system, and for every PC app, you could always find a Mac equivalent that was usually free! The same year I also got a 12&#x201D; Mac PowerBook G4 laptop - it was the first laptop that I owned myself, and I still use it today to show PowerPoint presentations at talks (thanks to rugged Apple manufacturing). &#xD;&#xD;Also during this time, the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;iPod&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; was taking the world by storm.  It originally came out in 2001, but quickly became the only way to listen to music by 2005.  I got the 80GB model in 2006 and it still works flawlessly today to play my music while I&#x2019;m working out at the gym. &#xD;&#xD;In short, by the mid-2000s, Apple was known as the company who made high-quality, easy-to-use products that augmented our lifestyle.  &#xD;&#xD;And in fine tradition, Apple didn&#x2019;t stop there.  In 2007, they released the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;iPhone&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - the first mobile smartphone that was also a full-featured OS X computer that could run apps and browse the Internet.  The definition of a smartphone changed overnight.  In 2010, they released the iPad, which redefined what a tablet should be.  Both were and continue to be wildly successful because they augment our lifestyle and jobs.  I got an &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;iPad&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; in 2012, and was shocked at how useful it was - I still use it to keep email and social media open on my desk while I&#x2019;m working.  Doctors use them to access information - teachers use them to run educational apps for children - warehouses use them to take inventory - and we use them to browse the Web and check Facebook on the couch ;-)&#xD;&#xD;After Steve Jobs&#x2019; death in 2011, people speculated that Apple may lose it&#x2019;s edge.  And, yes, some products that Apple released after seem to be dull (e.g. the Apple watch and Apple TV) .  But the iPhone, iPad and Mac remain incredibly strong.  &#xD;&#xD;My main computer today is a Xeon-based Mac Pro tube (shown left).  Although it&#x2019;s small, it&#x2019;s the most powerful computer I&#x2019;ve ever owned, and the best computer on the market today for professionals (see my other blog post on it &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/FA3760C7-1A9F-4D3D-9043-051921047CC7"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;). I&#x2019;m writing this blog post on it ;-)&#xD;&#xD;Today, Apple is the world&#x2019;s largest technology company - with $290 billion in assets, they are almost twice as large as both Microsoft and Google.  How did they get there when they were almost dead in 1997?  The answer should be simple - they brought innovative technology to the masses, and by doing so changed how we use technology in our daily lives.  The iPod, iPhone, and iPad were all radical &#x201C;firsts&#x201D; in the industry, and Mac computers running OS X are still the easiest computers to use today by a long shot.&#xD;&#xD;Happy 40th Apple!  Here&#x2019;s hoping that you continue to release products that make my life easier for the next 40 years.....&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_Entry_1_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
