<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:39:36 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;iPhone first impressions&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Saturday, June 30, 2007&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The iPhone went on sale in the US yesterday.&#xA0; And yes, for the past several months since its introduction, I wanted one badly.....but after hearing from those who have one, I am not so upset now that the iPhone is not available in Canada until later this year.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Basically, those who have one say that it &#x201C;feels like a 1.0 device&#x201D;, which it is.&#xA0;&#xA0; It uses the old EDGE service rather than new and fast 3G Mobile service in order to save battery power (Apple rationalizes that most will use the iPhone&#x2019;s WiFi to browse the Internet instead).&#xA0; Plus, Flash and Java are not supported on the iPhone (too much processing/bandwidth?). And my biggest problem with the iPhone is that it only has 4 or 8 GB of storage (bad). &#xD;&#xD;And to make things worse, AT&amp;T is charging lots of hidden fees (such as an extra $29/month for unlimited Internet, which was to come free with all iPhone plans), and many users are having activation problems (all iPhone features are disabled prior to activation).&#xA0;&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;On the flip side, those who say that the iPhone &#x201C;feels like a 1.0 device&#x201D; are also saying that the amazing experience of using one far outweighs the cons.&#xA0; And the praise is very consistent on the Internet - everyone is saying &#x201C;you just have to hold one and you will be in awe with its interface&#x201D;.&#xD;&#xD;I think the iPhone will be a great product, but in a revision or two when Apple works out the kinks and revises the tech specs.&#xA0; So it is not a bad thing that the iPhone will take a while to get to Canada.....by that time, perhaps the kinks will be worked out :-)&#xD;&#xD;Right now, I am perfectly happy with my 80GB iPod Video (a 5th generation product that doesn&#x2019;t have any kinks).&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="30_Entry_1_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
