<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:41:45 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Donkey Kong arcade restoration&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, December 20, 2015&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;I&#x2019;ve been collecting and restoring arcade games for almost 4 years now - I love the look of them, and more importantly, I love playing them!&#xD;&#xD;Donkey Kong was one of my favorite games, but Donkey Kong arcade cabinets are a bit of a rarity today as most of them have been converted (poorly) to other games, and are insanely popular amongst collectors (thanks to movies like &#x201C;The King of Kong&#x201D;).  &#xD;&#xD;So when someone I knew was selling their original, dedicated and 100% working Donkey Kong, I was like &#x201C;It&#x2019;s ON like Donkey Kong!&#x201D; and scooped it up pretty quick!  I took the picture to the left as soon as it landed in my driveway.&#xD;&#xD;The machine came from a bowling alley in Goderich (the owner had it on location making money but since decided to get out of the arcade business).  As a result, I knew that I had to restore some of the artwork on it as well as some of the small nicks and scratches on the sides.  &#xD;&#xD;However, aside from that, the inside of the machine needed no work - below left is a picture of the inside BEFORE I vacuumed the small amount of dust in the bottom.  It also has the oldest revision of the 2-board Donkey Kong boardset (TKG4-11), as shown in the picture below right.  This was a nice surprise, since most Donkey Kong boardsets are the fourth revision (TKG4-14), which means this was an early machine.&#xD;&#xD; &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;I also learned that there are two versions of the cabinet itself - the Japanese-made version (made entirely of plywood), and the US-made version (made of cheap pressboard and particle board).  Luckily, I have the Japanese-made version, since the US-made version wasn&#x2019;t made to withstand 30 years of use and are often difficult to restore.&#xD;&#xD;To restore my cabinet, I&#x2019;ve removed the boardset, control panel, bezel and marquee and repainted or touched up all parts of the cabinet (this was a lot of work) as well as applied brand new t-molding to the edges (as shown in the picture to the left).&#xD;&#xD;Next, I tackled the control panel, which had cigarette marks on the plastic overlay above the start buttons and just to the left of them too.  It also looked as if someone had applied black paint to the outer area, but a large amount of black paint had leaked into the instruction window, obscuring the instructions.  So I took it all apart, and was surprised to see that the original instruction paper was intact and in excellent shape.  I managed to remove the black paint from the instruction window on the plastic overlay and touch up areas where the paint had worn off under the cigarette marks.  After it was done, it was 95% perfect, so I decided not to get a new overlay (yay!).  I then sanded the control panel and applied new black paint, re-added the controls and white t-molding for the front.  I put it in the cab, and positioned a new vinyl instruction decal above it - overall, it  ended up looking pretty slick:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;After this, I cleaned up the marquee and bezel - both cleaned up incredibly well when scrubbed with some mild detergent and a cloth!  I then re-added the internals, marquee and bezel (there are no marks on the bezel - that&#x2019;s just the flash picking up the bottom of a picture on the adjacent wall):&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Finally, I added brand new side art to finish it off, and then played some Donkey Kong (I&#x2019;m better at it than I remember :D)!&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="20_Donkey_Kong_arcade_restoration_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="410px" height="394px"/>
</content>
