<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:42:17 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The Canadian Identity Crisis&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, October 22, 2017&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;What does it mean to be a Canadian?  What do Canadians value?  What do Canadians strive for?  If you ask the average Canadian, they&#x2019;ll typically list these four things, none of which have anything to do with values or identity:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Beer (a drink)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Hockey (a sport)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Tim Hortons (a donut &amp; coffee chain)&#xD;	&#x2022;	The Tragically Hip (a Canadian rock band)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;That&#x2019;s right....the average Canadian has been devoid of a central identity for so long that they associate Canada with:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Beer that is about as good as American beer, but far worse than most European beers&#xD;	&#x2022;	A sport that a minority of Canadians play, mainly because it has to be played in an expensive arena or outside in the winter if you have enough cold and ice&#xD;	&#x2022;	A business that has been foreign owned for over 20 years that serves weak, overpriced coffee and food that tastes like a wet mop&#xD;	&#x2022;	A really shitty rock band that has a popular following only in Canada due to their inclusion of Canadian events and locations in their lyrics &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;It&#x2019;s tragic (pun intended).&#xD;&#xD;What about our American neighbors to the south?  If you ask the average American what America stands for, they&#x2019;ll say &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;freedom and opportunity&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  Whether every American agrees with the validity of these values is another matter entirely - the simple fact is that America has propagated these values to the *average* American for the last century.   The American Dream, the bald eagle, guns, &#x2018;murica.  It worked.&#xD;&#xD;When I was growing up, the Canadian Dream was to win the lottery.  Then, when I excelled in school and entered the enrichment program (yes, I was one of the smart kids), I learned a whole new side to Canada.  The Canadian Government and the school system went through great effort to show us what Canada was about by sending us on a large number of enrichment activities all over the country, involving people from every subculture and region of the Canada. We learned from professors, First Nations leaders, special figures and even a retired Canadian textile mill worker who was born in India (wisdom comes from many places).  We learned about art, humanities, law, culture, promoting innovation on the world stage, the importance of protecting the environment, as well as the strength of diversity, understanding and cooperation.  &#xD;&#xD;In other words, at an early age I learned what Canada stands for at its core from those that were the most passionate about it.  Canada stands for &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;peace, progression and equality&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  But we were the smart kids given a learning opportunity, not the average Joe.  And while the intent of the Canadian government and educational system at the time was for us to spread our knowledge (which I&#x2019;m sure we all do still today), it clearly wasn&#x2019;t as effective as the American approach to spreading values.  &#xD;&#xD;Interestingly enough, the average Canadian understands these values regardless of whether they associate them with Canadian identity.  From my life experience, I can reliably say that the average Canadian today supports environmental policies, multi-culturalism (more than most other countries at least), and equality (including gender/LGBT equality, universal healthcare, and just being polite to one another).  But when asked what Canadians value, the majority of people will still answer beer, hockey, Timmies (Tim Hortons) and The Hip (The Tragically Hip).&#xD;&#xD;What we really need to do more of in Canada is separate our real values of peace, progression and equality from those things that have nothing to do with them.  Sorry beer, hockey, Tim Hortons and The Tragically Hip.....but you&#x2019;re all impostors that are distracting from, rather than promoting, the Canadian identity.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="22_The_Canadian_Identity_Crisis_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
