<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SUN on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/sun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SUN on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/sun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SPARCbook teardown</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/sparcbook-teardown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/sparcbook-teardown/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2019, I picked up a rare SPARC-based laptop from the 1990s running Solaris UNIX (marketed as the ultimate UNIX portable on the Tadpole website in 1997). You can read my blog post on it here: SPARCbook 3000ST: The coolest 90s laptop. It occasionally shows up on Hacker News, and I get plenty of comments whenever I post it on Reddit.
However, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been curious as to the internals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halt and Catch Fire</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/halt-and-catch-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/halt-and-catch-fire/</guid>
      <description>Halt and Catch Fire is an AMC television series that ran for four seasons from 2014-2017, and covers the culture and pivotal aspects of the computing industry from 1983 (just after the release of the IBM PC) to 1994 (when the Internet and World Wide Web exploded).
You can binge watch it on Netflix if you like today, and trust me - you won’t be disappointed! Halt and Catch Fire is the best drama I’ve ever seen - an emotional rollercoaster like no other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP Solaris</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/rip-solaris/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/rip-solaris/</guid>
      <description>The 80s and 90s was a period of intense development in the computer hardware and software worlds. On the hardware side, processors started to become much more powerful, and the word on the streets was that RISC (Reduced Instruction Set Computing) was going to be the way of the future. Powerful RISC platforms emerged during this time, including Sun Microsystems SPARC, HP PA-RISC, SGI MIPS, IBM PowerPC, and the DEC Alpha - these platforms were very powerful, and ushered in 64-bit computing over a decade before it became common in home computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>50 shades of Cray</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/50-shades-of-cray/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/50-shades-of-cray/</guid>
      <description>If you wanted a fast computer back in 1976, you bought the 5.5 ton, $9 million Cray-1 made by Cray Research. The Cray-1 was dubbed the first supercomputer as it was designed to be much faster than other (more massive) computers of the time.
It was incredibly successful in the large computing space and Cray subsequently released a much faster model called the Cray X-MP in 1983 (shown in the picture at the top of this post).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Futuretech &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/futuretech-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/futuretech-92/</guid>
      <description>This year marks Canada’s 150th anniversary (1867-2017), and while there are some cool events happening this year (e.g. National Parks have free admission), there really isn’t a lot of hoopla surrounding it.
However, I have very fond memories of Canada’s 125th anniversary in 1992, because that’s when I got to go to Alberta as part of a student enrichment event.
In the summer of 1992, the Canadian government hosted an event called Futuretech ’92, where 125 of the top students from Eastern Canada were flown to Calgary for a week of educational motivation, and 125 of the top students from Western Canada were flown to Montreal for the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Retro Computers</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/retrocomputers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/retrocomputers/</guid>
      <description>Apple Apple Computer was founded by Steve Wozniak and Steve Jobs in 1976. Steve Wozniak provided the technical genius for computer creation, while Steve Jobs provided the expertise in marketing and design. Their first major commercially adopted product was the Apple II in 1977, which had a MOS 6502 CPU (also used in Commodore computers such as the Commodore 64) and shipped with BASIC and the DOS operating system (later versions).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
