<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200627" date="2020-06-28 02:22:11 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The Computer Hipster - Part 1 - SGI IRIX&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, November 26, 2017&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Everyone has a little bit of hipster in them......after all, it makes you feel special to be part of a subculture that is both &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;cool&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;uncommon&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  For example, I remember being an Apple computer user back in the PowerPC G4/G5 days before Apple made it big and everyone knew who they were.  Back then, if you were an Apple user, if felt as if you were a member of the small rebel alliance in Star Wars, fighting the big evil Imperial army.  It was cool, and not that many people were doing it.  Of course, vanity Apple computers are everywhere today, and while they are still considered cool, they are considered &#x201C;BMW rap-star cool&#x201D; not &#x201C;rebel alliance cool&#x201D; like they were 15 years ago.&#xD;&#xD;But computer hipsterism is still alive and well in computing today.....it just focuses on older computer platforms that were extremely cool back in their day, alongside a community of computer geeks that want to keep the platform alive as a hobby.  After all, it&#x2019;s cool, and not everyone is doing it ;-)&#xD;&#xD;The two computer hipster communities that still exist today are:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	a)	The SGI/IRIX community&#xD;	b)	The Commodore Amiga community&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;In this blog post, I&#x2019;ll give you an insight into the SGI/IRIX community, and the Commodore Amiga community will be the topic of my next blog post.  &#xD;&#xD;OK - so what is SGI and IRIX?&#xD;&#xD;Simply put, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;SGI (Silicon Graphics Inc.)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; was the coolest computer company of the 1990s.  They made high-end computers that had very powerful &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;MIPS RISC processors&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (instead of the more common and less powerful Intel/AMD processors), and were primarily used for graphics and complex tasks that could benefit from visualization.  As a result, they were often used to gen&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;erate 3D graphics and animations (the famous MAYA software was first made for the SGI platform), as well as heavily used in science and engineering (chem&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;ical modeling, 3D building design, etc.).  The operating system they ran was a flavor of UNIX called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;IRIX&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; that had a great graphical desktop:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Better yet, SGI made sure that their computers had &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;cool looking designs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; for the time - instead of being housed in a plain beige box, each SGI computer was in a colourful case that a distinct shape and layout to it:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;The models of these computers from left-to-right are:  &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;SGI Octane&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - the most powerful SGI workstation of the 1990s&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;SGI Fuel&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - the successor to the SGI Octane in the 2000s (very very powerful)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;SGI Visual Workstation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - a rare Intel-based SGI that never took off (it ran Windows)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;SGI O2 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;- the most common SGI workstation of the 1990s - it&#x2019;s cute little case was actually used as a character called Erwin in the first webcomic, userfriendly.org (which every computer geek followed religiously):&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;In addition to being &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;revered amongst computer geeks&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, SGI computers were &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;very very expensive&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;!  Every computer geek in the 1990s fantasized about having a powerful SGI workstation on their desk, but few could afford one.&#xD;&#xD;My grandmother grew up during the depression and started a family during the second World War.  In short, money was tight, and she never had enough money to buy the beautiful clothes that she wanted when she was young.  After the war, when times were good, she amassed a huge wardrobe that would make most fashion buffs jealous.  And if you asked her why, she&#x2019;d always say that it was because she couldn&#x2019;t have nice clothes when she was younger!&#xD;&#xD;The same is true for SGI among computer geeks today.  SGI was the most revered computer workstation of the 1990s, but difficult to obtain.  So when used ones became easy/cheap to find in the early 2000s as SGI faded into the sunset, a whole community of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;SGI/IRIX hipsters&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (um...I mean hobbyists) started to form.  I was one of them.&#xD;&#xD;The last version of the IRIX operating system (6.5.30) was released in 2006, just a few years before SGI went defunct.  But an online community of computer hipsters keep using it, tinkering with it, and compiling open source software software (such as Firefox) for it on SGI hardware.  You can find this community online at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;NekoChan&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, whose banner has a girl holding an SGI O2:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;NekoChan has a very active forum, as well as links to software that you can run on your SGI hardware, which is still quite powerful by today&#x2019;s standards (my SGI Fuel is actually quite fast!).  &#xD;&#xD;A bunch of factors have to come together to create an online computer hipster community. &#xD;In short, some of the things that have led to the creation and success of the SGI/IRIX hipster community include:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	a)	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The coolness factor &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;- SGI was the coolest power workstation of the 1990s&#xD;	b)	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The unobtainable factor&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - SGI was too expensive to obtain back in the 1990s, so people want to own one today....just because....&#xD;	c)	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The UNIX factor&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - since IRIX is a UNIX flavor, it&#x2019;s easy to continue using it in a productive way (UNIX is easily customizable with scripts and command-line utilities, such as ssh, that will continue to make it useful in the future)&#xD;	d)	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The software factor&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - it&#x2019;s easy to obtain and compile open source software made for modern UNIX/Linux systems for IRIX&#xD;	e)	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The hipster factor&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - not many people are doing it, so you feel like you&#x2019;re part of a rebel alliance if you are part of the community&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="26_The_Computer_Hipster_-_Part_1_-_SGI_IRIX_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="288px" height="282px"/>
</content>
