<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:42:01 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;RAIDEN V review&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Wednesday, August 24, 2016&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Few video game franchises survive the test of time.&#xA0;Nintendo&#x2019;s &#x201C;Mario&#x201D; is probably the one that comes to the top of everyone&#x2019;s head, but if you look at the gameplay, you&#x2019;ll notice that it has changed radically over the years - for example, Super Mario Bros has very little in common with Super Mario World, or Super Smash Bros.&#xA0; Most video game franchises are like that - they are brands only.&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;However, the same isn&#x2019;t true with the RAIDEN franchise.&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;What is RAIDEN?&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;RAIDEN (Japanese for &#x201C;thunder and lightning&#x201D;) was a 1990 two-player scrolling shoot-em-up (shmup) arcade video game where your &#x201C;Raiden Supersonic Attack Fighter Jet&#x201D; navigated through 8 different stages (the last three in outer space), shooting enemies and final stage bosses to save the world against an alien invasion.&#xA0; What made RAIDEN different than other arcade games of the time was its &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;smooth gameplay&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;amazing background music soundtrack&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;perfectly-balanced difficulty&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.&#xA0; It was crazy popular and made it&#x2019;s game developer (Seibu Kaihatsu) famous.&#xD;&#xD;Seibu spawned several sequels to RAIDEN since 1990 - but unlike the Mario franchise, each RAIDEN game maintained the same core ingredients (gameplay/music/balance) that made the original game so successful:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	RAIDEN Trad (1991)&#xD;	&#x2022;	RAIDEN II (1993)&#xD;	&#x2022;	RAIDEN DX (1994)&#xD;	&#x2022;	The RAIDEN Project (1995)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Viper Phase 1 (1995)&#xD;	&#x2022;	RAIDEN Fighters (1996)&#xD;	&#x2022;	RAIDEN Fighters 2: Operation Hell Dive (1997)&#xD;	&#x2022;	RAIDEN Fighters Jet (1998)&#xD;	&#x2022;	RAIDEN Fighters 2: 2000 Operation Hell Dive (2000)&#xD;	&#x2022;	RAIDEN III (2005)&#xD;	&#x2022;	RAIDEN IV (2007/2009)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Enter RAIDEN V&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;To commemorate the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;25th anniversary of RAIDEN&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, Moss (in collaboration with Seibu Kaihatsu) released RAIDEN V in 2015 as an Xbox One exclusive game.  Most RAIDEN fans were pretty skeptical as to whether this new RAIDEN game would be worthy of the franchise (myself included), but Moss did an amazing job! In fact, it&#x2019;s tied as my favorite RAIDEN game alongside the original RAIDEN and RAIDEN Fighters 2: 2000 Operation Hell dive!&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;First impressions&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;After downloading RAIDEN V, I immediately played all levels on normal difficulty and was shocked at how easy it was to get used to the controls on the Xbox One controller - they weren&#x2019;t as good as a traditional joystick and buttons, but they were far from bad by any means.  That being said, I later switched to a &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hori Arcade Pro V Kai&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; fightstick (real arcade controls), which are a perfect match for RAIDEN V, and the only way you should really play the game if you want to go for the really high scores ;-)&#xD;&#xD;Playing RAIDEN V on the Xbox One &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;felt just like any other RAIDEN game&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - the vertical screen layout, mechanics, weapon usage and stage progression were identical to previous RAIDEN games, and the same gameplay elements were all there (bombs, miclus, fairies, final bosses at the end of each stage, and so on.).  In fine RAIDEN tradition, the background music soundtrack is phenomenal, and just like the original RAIDEN game, there are &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;eight stages&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, and the final stages are in outer space.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The gameplay&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;What was different (and much appreciated by me) were the other elements that augmented the RAIDEN experience.  Since everyone with an Xbox One will be playing the game on a widescreen, the left and right panes of the screen outside the play area are used for a variety of different things.  &#xD;&#xD;On the left pane, you can see the fundamental stuff: what power level your three different weapons are at, as well as your health.  However, you can also see your progress charted throughout the level as well as compare it to others online - and when other online players reach a certain milestone, you can press the Y button to send them a cheer (which increases their cheer meter at the bottom of the screen), and vice versa.  When your cheer meter reaches a certain level, you can press the X button to launch a special cheer attack!  Before I played the game, I thought this &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;online cheer feature&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; looked dumb when I read it online - however, when you&#x2019;re playing the game, it adds a &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;whole new, exciting online dimension to the game&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; that I absolutely love!  I send and receive cheers all the time and time them for key parts of the stage that are difficult, eliminating the need to waste my bombs before I get to the final boss in each stage.&#xD;&#xD;The right pane is used for the story itself.  Yes, RAIDEN has always had a story - an epic battle where your fighter jet (powered by captured alien technology) must fight off an alien invasion and eventually destroy the aliens in outer space.  But in previous RAIDEN games, much of this was left to the imagination......not so in RAIDEN V!  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dialog&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; from your team on the command ship are constantly chiming in during the gameplay with their pictures and dialog on the right pane (it almost feels like Cortana from Halo). But this dialog isn&#x2019;t distracting in a bad way - it adds a sense of urgency to different parts of each stage, as well as, well...a &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;concrete storyline&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; for the first time in a RAIDEN game (and the story is good!).&#xD; &#xD;Another new dimension to RAIDEN V is that there are &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;multiple endings &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;depending on what level you play on.  There are &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;four levels&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; after the second stage: Levels S (special), A, B, and C.  You advance to better levels the better you play in the current level (S is the best, C is the worst). If you complete the final stage on level S or A with all of your weapons on maximum power, you will see a &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;second final boss&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; after defeating the first final boss.  If you defeat this second final boss, you will get a different (and much better) ending than what you get if you complete the final stage on level B or C.  Plus, you can choose to &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;start directly from a particular stage/level combination&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (you must first complete that stage/level combination in order to unlock it on the stage chooser screen).&#xD;&#xD;The only downside to RAIDEN V is the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;lack of two player support&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, which was a standard feature in previous RAIDEN games. After playing the game, I can understand why it was removed - after all, having a second player on the screen would make the game too distracting to play alongside the storyline dialog and online cheer support.  But having an option for a two-player game without storyline dialog and online cheer support is something that Moss should have put in there.... &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;RAIDEN V is a phenomenal game, and one that is worth as a 25th anniversary release in the franchise.  The gameplay elements that make RAIDEN a great game are all there, and there are some new features that make it feel more like a modern Xbox One title (online cheer support, stage levels, dialog and storyline).  More importantly, these new features augment the original gameplay elements rather than change them - and this makes RAIDEN fundamentally different than other franchises such as Mario.  RAIDEN fans can rest assured that RAIDEN V is a worth addition to the RAIDEN franchise with some cool extras.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="24_RAIDEN_V_review_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
