<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200627" date="2020-06-28 02:22:00 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The weird world of arcade collecting, Vol.2&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, June 28, 2015&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;For those who don&#x2019;t already know from reading my bio or arcadia pages, I&#x2019;m an avid arcade game collector.  Back in November 2013, I did a post entitled &#x201C;The weird world of arcade collecting&#x201D; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/9E73E5AF-B3D8-46E6-B2E8-03053094A77F"&gt;click here to read it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;).  After reading it two years later, I thought I should give some additional insight into the hobby that I&#x2019;ve learned over the last few years.&#xD;&#xD;Firstly, I should note that I&#x2019;m even more involved in the hobby today than I was two years ago - I absolutely love this hobby!  My collection is now 24 arcades (the max I can fit in my basement), and I play each one almost daily.  As I get to know more and more arcade collectors, I&#x2019;m finding that I share more in common with them than I originally thought possible.&#xD;&#xD;Without further ado, here are some features of the hobby that I&#x2019;ve learned over the last few years:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	The arcade collecting community contains people from all walks of life. &#xD;	&#x2022;	A large proportion of arcade collectors are nostalgia junkies - they collect other things from the 70s, 80s and 90s (e.g. jukeboxes, 80s movie posters, VHS tapes, etc.), like to watch retro movies and listen to retro music. &#xD;	&#x2022;	Most arcade collectors aren&#x2019;t very good at playing the games - they collect them because they are beautiful works of art in their own right and they enjoy playing the games themselves (even if they aren&#x2019;t that good).&#xD;	&#x2022;	The relatively few arcade collectors who are very good at playing the games (such as myself) usually weren&#x2019;t very good when they were younger because they didn&#x2019;t have an unlimited supply of quarters.  However, with a personal arcade machine, they take the opportunity to get really good at the game at no cost.  This is often what drew them to the hobby years later.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Some arcade collectors like to fully restore a machine to the point where it looks new (e.g. new side art, control panel overlay, power-coated coin door, etc.), whereas others like to see a bit of wear (a stamp of authenticity...something that represents where it came from).  There are also arcade collectors that do no restoration whatsoever (usually these collectors have several machines in poor condition too!).&#xD;	&#x2022;	Arcade collectors have a mutual shared respect for the machines - they like to see a classic arcade machine restored to it&#x2019;s former glory, or at the very least, taken care of by the owner (and not converted to a multicade).  It&#x2019;s a way of preserving a piece of history from a time that they loved, surrounding a gaming culture that doesn&#x2019;t exist today.  Respect the game.  Respect the era.&#xD;	&#x2022;	There are many people (called &#x201C;operators&#x201D;) who buy lots of classic arcade games and either resell them or put them on location in a bar, laundromat or pizza parkour to make money.  Nearly all of these people have little respect for the machines - they often convert them or try to sell them with ridiculously high asking prices.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Most arcade collectors don&#x2019;t like to spend a lot of money on an arcade machine (especially at the beginning of the hobby), but will spend a bit more for a classic arcade that they want that is in very good condition (since it costs less to restore).  &#xD;	&#x2022;	Nearly all arcade collectors enjoy the restoration process of an arcade - it gives them great pride to restore an object that has so much intrinsic meaning, and many collectors say that they enjoy the restoration process more than playing the game itself.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Arcade collectors often get the games that they remember.  However, they sometimes get a few games that they never played when they were younger, because they are fun to play by today&#x2019;s standards.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Arcade collectors often have at least one room in their house that looks like it could be on the next episode of Hoarders ;-)  Many collectors have game room that are tacky in some way that appeals only to other arcade collectors (cheesy signs, coin/token machines, pop machines, etc.).  &#xD;	&#x2022;	Every arcade collector will tell you that they love the hobby.  However, more often than not, their spouse or significant other hates it.  I&#x2019;ve seen many divorces in this community during the last few years, and I&#x2019;m certain that this hobby has something to do with it in most cases.&#xD;	&#x2022;	There are some arcade collectors that get out of the hobby entirely (for a variety of different reasons), but often return to the hobby later.  There are a few I know who have done this several times.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Arcade collectors are much more interesting than, say, stamp collectors....&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="28_The_weird_world_of_arcade_collecting,_Vol.2_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
