<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft turns 45</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/microsoft-turns-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/microsoft-turns-45/</guid>
      <description>On April 4th 1975, a small company called Microsoft was founded in Albuquerque, New Mexico. They would later become the most pivotal company in the technology world, and their co-founder Bill Gates would become the world’s most prolific philanthropist.
Like many tech companies, Microsoft has had a colourful past. Started by two whiz kids (Paul Allen and Bill Gates), they started by selling operating system and supporting software.
Xenix UNIX (later sold to SCO) was their first operating system product in 1980, followed closely by MS-DOS in 1981 (which they originally purchased from Tim Paterson).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Windows Subsystem for Linux</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/using-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/using-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>1. So what is WSL? Simply put, it’s a kernel interface (lxcore &amp;amp; lxss) that allows 64-bit Linux binaries to run on a Window 10 or Windows Server 2019 kernel.
All you need to do is add the userland (file system structure and programs) from an existing Linux distribution, such as Ubuntu, Kali, Debian or SUSE, and that Linux distribution will run natively on the Windows kernel!
You must access the Linux distribution via a Windows program that associates the userland of the Linux distribution to the WSL (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Essentials for SysAdmins</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/powershell-essentials-for-sysadmins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/powershell-essentials-for-sysadmins/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell is essentially a scripting language and shell (command prompt) that you can use on Windows systems. It’s basically Microsoft’s way of getting a powerful UNIX/Linux/Mac-like shell on the Windows platform (long overdue!). The first versions of PowerShell were pretty horrific, but it’s come a long way since then. PowerShell v4 and later is pretty decent (Win10 comes with PowerShell v5). Luckily, PowerShell v4 comes with Windows Server 2012, and since this post is geared towards sysadmins, I’ll focus everything on Windows Server 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft ReFS vs Oracle ZFS - FIGHT!</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/refs-vs-zfs-fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/refs-vs-zfs-fight/</guid>
      <description>In the past, most IT admins have put their faith in systems and SANs (Storage Area Networks) that use RAID (Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks) technology. RAID can be used to combine hard disks together into simple volumes (called RAID-0, or JBOD) that aren’t fault tolerant, but can also be used to create mirrored volumes where both drives are identical in case one fails (called RAID-1), or striped volumes with parity where data is written across several disks with parity information that can be used to calculate the missing data if a drive fails (called RAID-5).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rise and fall of DEC</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/the-rise-and-fall-of-dec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/the-rise-and-fall-of-dec/</guid>
      <description>Firstly, the information that I’m presenting here is taken from various sources, including people I knew who worked for DEC, my own experiences, and the book DEC Is Dead, Long Live DEC by Edgar H. Schein.
Quick background info: DEC was the first knowledge-based company - a company who valued the knowledge of its employees over anything else, and used it to drive change and sell products.
The founder and father icon of DEC, Ken Olsen, spent time working at IBM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All about DEC</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/all-about-dec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/all-about-dec/</guid>
      <description>Digital Equipment Corporation (DEC) was born in the late 1950s when it was lucrative to make computers that cost a ton of money. And DEC was good - they would make computers that would perform much better and cost significantly less than the IBM equivalent (IBM mainframes back then were expensive behemoths).
The DEC PDP (Programmed Data Processor) line of minicomputers were so good and inexpensive, you’d be hard pressed to NOT find one in your local university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you a Mac or a PC?</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/are-you-a-mac-or-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/are-you-a-mac-or-pc/</guid>
      <description>If you are ultra-Mac, you prefer to use an aesthetic computer that “just works” - as a result, you are usually sexy, artistic and cool.
If you are ultra-PC, you prefer to use a clunky un-aesthetic computer that is difficult to use, crashes often, is a virus hell, yet is guaranteed to work with any piece of hardware with a software driver written by a 10-year-old boy in a barn in China - as a result, you are nerdy, cheap and non-cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Operating Systems</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/info/operatingsystems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/info/operatingsystems/</guid>
      <description>UNIX UNIX is the grandfather of all modern operating systems, and today it still remains the most powerful and least known. But if you use an Apple computer running macOS, or an iPhone or iPad running iOS, you are using a UNIX operating system. And if you do online banking, somewhere tucked away in the bank is likely a series of UNIX systems running Oracle Solaris UNIX, HP-UX UNIX, or AIX UNIX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. My published books</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/bio/my-published-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/bio/my-published-books/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps one of my more famous achievements is the authoring of several textbooks for Course Technology, Cengage, Nelson, Thompson/Delmar and Wiley. I&amp;rsquo;ve listed their details in chronological order here (oldest to newest) with cover pictures below:
 Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification (ISBN: 0-619-13004-0) Guide to UNIX System Administration (ISBN: 0-619-13041-5) Linux+ In Depth (ISBN: 1-59200-062-2) MCSE Guide to Managing a Microsoft Windows Server 2003 Network (ISBN: 0-619-12029-0) Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification - 2nd Edition (ISBN: 0-619-21621-2) Linux+ 2005 In Depth (ISBN: 1-59200-728-7) Novell&amp;rsquo;s Guide to CompTIA&amp;rsquo;s Linux+ (Course 3060) (ISBN: 1-4188-3730-X) SUSE Linux Enterprise Server Administration (Course 3037) (ISBN: 1-4188-3731-8) Advanced SUSE Linux Enterprise Server Administration (Course 3038) (ISBN: 1-4188-3732-6) Microsoft Windows Vista Guide (ISBN: 1-4188-3757-1) SUSE Linux Enterprise Desktop Administration (ISBN: 1-4283-2227-2) SUSE Linux Enterprise Server Security (ISBN: 1-4283-2223-X) Microsoft Official Academic Course (MOAC): Exchange Server 2007 Exam 70-236 (ISBN: 978-0-470-31227-8) Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification - 3rd Edition (ISBN: 978-1-418-83721-1) SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 11 Administration (ISBN: 978-1-111-54003-6) Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification - International Edition (ISBN: 978-1-111-54153-8) Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification - 4th Edition (ISBN: 978-1-305-10716-8) Linux+ and LPIC-1 Guide to Linux Certification - 5th Edition (ISBN: 978-13375-6979-8) Hands-On Windows Server 2019 - 3rd Edition (ISBN: 978-0-357-43615-8)  Moreover, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked as a technical editor for numerous Linux and software development titles for both Wiley and Pearson, as well as wrote 6 books for Research in Motion (RIM) on BlackBerry Enterprise Server 4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>