<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sysadmin on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/sysadmin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sysadmin on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/sysadmin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeBSD UNIX for Linux sysadmins</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/freebsd-unix-for-linux-sysadmins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/freebsd-unix-for-linux-sysadmins/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve ever installed and explored another Linux distro (what Linux sysadmin hasn’t?!?), then exploring FreeBSD is going be somewhat similar with a few key differences. While there is no graphical installation, the installation process is straightforward and similar to installing a server-based Linux distro. Just make sure you choose the local_unbound package when prompted if you want to cache DNS lookups locally, as FreeBSD doesn’t have a built-in local DNS resolver that does this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Essentials for SysAdmins</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/powershell-essentials-for-sysadmins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/powershell-essentials-for-sysadmins/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell is essentially a scripting language and shell (command prompt) that you can use on Windows systems. It’s basically Microsoft’s way of getting a powerful UNIX/Linux/Mac-like shell on the Windows platform (long overdue!). The first versions of PowerShell were pretty horrific, but it’s come a long way since then. PowerShell v4 and later is pretty decent (Win10 comes with PowerShell v5). Luckily, PowerShell v4 comes with Windows Server 2012, and since this post is geared towards sysadmins, I’ll focus everything on Windows Server 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft ReFS vs Oracle ZFS - FIGHT!</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/refs-vs-zfs-fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/refs-vs-zfs-fight/</guid>
      <description>In the past, most IT admins have put their faith in systems and SANs (Storage Area Networks) that use RAID (Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks) technology. RAID can be used to combine hard disks together into simple volumes (called RAID-0, or JBOD) that aren’t fault tolerant, but can also be used to create mirrored volumes where both drives are identical in case one fails (called RAID-1), or striped volumes with parity where data is written across several disks with parity information that can be used to calculate the missing data if a drive fails (called RAID-5).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of Information Technology</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/evolution-of-info-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/evolution-of-info-tech/</guid>
      <description>As a Dean for the technology faculties of a private college in Canada, I’m always looking to make our programs more aligned to the industry - my motto is: always look forward and never look back!
However, when it comes to Information Technology (IT), I regularly find that the general perception of IT jobs is stuck in the past by at least a decade. I can’t tell you how many times I’ve met people who think that IT guys are stuck in the back closet of some company doing some menial job, such as re-soldering chips on a computer motherboard much like working on the engine of an old car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 years of UserFriendly.org</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/10-years-of-userfriendly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/10-years-of-userfriendly/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t blogged for a while.
This is partly because my daughter and I have been enjoying some major events in Toronto (Ontario Science Centre, ROM, shopping, more shopping, etc.), and not much has happened in the Geek world aside from the new Apple hardware updates and Firefox achieving 100% market share in Antarctica.
However, the main reason I haven’t blogged is that I have been engrossed with reading the 10th Anniversary book from UserFriendly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I created the Internet</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/i-created-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/i-created-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>Complete with blinking light! It&amp;rsquo;s amazing what you can make with a soldering iron and the spare electrical parts you have in your basement.
If you are wondering what the hell I am talking about, just watch the BBC sitcom “The IT Crowd” Series 3 Episode 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War Games shell scripting fun</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/war-games-shell-scripting-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/war-games-shell-scripting-fun/</guid>
      <description>While my daughter and I sat across from each other in Starbucks drinking coffee and PIN messaging each other in Leetspeak using our BlackBerries (yes, I realize how drastically nerdy this is), the thought occurred to us that a simple shell script could easily be used to simulate the War Operation Plan Response (WOPR) supercomputer from the movie War Games (1983).
Anyways, we analyzed the frame-by-frame output from the movie and recreated the output on the Sun Enterprise 450 in my classroom running Red Hat Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to please your IT department</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/how-to-please-your-it-dept/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/how-to-please-your-it-dept/</guid>
      <description>When you call us to have your computer moved, be sure to leave it buried under half a ton of postcards, baby pictures, stuffed animals, dried flowers, bowling trophies and children’s art. We don’t have a life, and we find it deeply moving to catch a fleeting glimpse of yours.
  Don’t write anything down. Ever. We can play back the error messages from here.
  When an IT person says he’s coming right over, go for coffee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Tech Slogans</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/info/techslogans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/info/techslogans/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t Anthropomorphize computers. They hate that.
I void warranties
I read your email
Code poet
Byte Me
I see dead pixels
cd /pub; more beer  No, I will not fix your computer
There is no place like 127.0.0.1
There is no place like ::1
Bow before me for I am root
Dilbert is NOT fiction
It must be user error.
/* No Comment */  My other shirt is clever</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>