<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200627" date="2020-06-28 02:22:09 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;50 Shades of Cray&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Monday, April 3, 2017&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;If you wanted a fast computer back in 1976, you bought the 5.5 ton, $9 million &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cray-1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; made by Cray Research.  The Cray-1 was dubbed the first &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;supercomputer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; as it was designed to be much faster than other (more massive) computers of the time.  &#xD;&#xD;It was incredibly successful in the large computing space and Cray subsequently released a much faster model called the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cray X-MP&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; in 1983 (shown in the picture at the top of this post).  By today&#x2019;s standards, the Cray X-MP was nothing special (it was only half as powerful as an original Xbox from 2001). but for the 1980s, it was incredibly powerful!  The graphics in the movie &#x201C;The Last Starfighter&#x201D; were created on a Cray X-MP.&#xD;&#xD;As technology advanced, the nature of what made up supercomputers changed as well.  &#xD;By the early 1990s, CPUs were becoming more and more powerful, especially in the high-end computing space.  To stay competitive, Cray switched from their custom computer design to one that used powerful RISC CPUs made by other manufacturers.  The &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cray T3D&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cray T3E&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; computers in the early/mid 1990s contained up to 2048 DEC Alpha CPUs (the most powerful CPU of the 1990s) connected together using incredibly fast, bleeding-edge switching technologies.  And to control it all, Cray used a UNIX operating system called UniCOS.&#xD;&#xD;The 1990s was also the dawn of the Internet as we know it today, and client-server networks were proliferating like wildfire.  To compete in this new server-focused market, Cray released several file servers (that they called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;superservers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;) during the early/mid 1990s. These superservers used SUN Microsystems SuperSPARC and UltraSPARC CPUs and ran SUN Solaris UNIX.&#xD;&#xD;Unfortunately, the competition in the high-end computing space of the 1990s put a great deal of pressure on Cray Research, and ultimately led to it being acquired by &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Silicon Graphics (SGI)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; in 1996.   SGI was mainly interested in Cray&#x2019;s fast switching technologies, which they incorporated into their own products (via a special &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;SGI Bedrock chip&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;).  They sold off the Cray superserver product line to SUN Microsystems (which developed it into the SUN Enterprise 10000 computer), and eventually sold the rest of Cray to &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tera Computer Company&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; in 2000, which rebranded themselves as &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;CRAY&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; and sold supercomputers built around the server-class Opteron CPUs from AMD.  CRAY still sells supercomputers today - however, they are still based on server-class Intel Xeon CPUs, as well as GPUs from Nvidia.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="3_50_Shades_of_Cray_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="399px"/>
</content>
