<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:57:41 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Donkey Kong turns 35 today&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Saturday, July 9, 2016&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Donkey Kong, Nintendo&#x2019;s girl-kidnapping gorilla, was released to the arcades on this day back in 1981.  In this post, I&#x2019;ll reflect on what Donkey Kong was, its impact on the game industry, and its relevance today.&#xD;&#xD;If you grew up in the 1970s or 1980s, then your parents probably didn&#x2019;t know much about video games.  They probably inadvertently referred to a video game as a &#x201C;PONG&#x201D; machine at some point in their lives.  But if you mention Donkey Kong, they&#x2019;ll probably say something along the lines of &#x201C;Ah the gorilla in the video game.&#x201D;  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Donkey Kong is a video game icon.....and the first that pop culture could relate to&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  It&#x2019;s a bit hard to look at a space invader character and say &#x201C;Gee, that&#x2019;s definitely an alien.&#x201D;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;However, Donkey Kong was far more than just an icon - for those of us who grew up in the 70s and 80s, Donkey Kong was a great game, and&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; the first arcade game that really had some sort of depth to it&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  Instead of using your controls to blast stuff off the screen (like in Space Invaders or Asteroids), or eat pellets (like in Pac-man), Donkey Kong had a story to it.  You were this short character in overalls with a baseball cap (called Jumpman) that had to rescue your girlfriend from an angry gorilla (Donkey Kong) who was holding her hostage at the top of a building site made of girders and ladders while throwing barrels at you.  &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;If you climbed to the top while dodging or smashing the obstacles in your path, Donkey Kong retreated with your girlfriend in tow to another part of the building site made of girders.  If you loosened the girder rivets in this structure (by running over them), then Donkey Kong falls down and you are reunited with your girlfriend for a happy ending!&#xD;&#xD; &#xD;&#xD;Of course, the game doesn&#x2019;t stop there - those two screens were just level 1.  You keep on going to a new level.  Each new level starts with the barrel stage, and ends with the rivet stage (where you save your girlfriend again), but introduces new stages in the middle with new challenges like conveyor belts and bouncing springs.  In other words, the game gets really really hard if you play it to later levels, but allows you to experience some satisfaction sooner than later if you complete the first level (to get you hooked on the game).&#xD;&#xD;Due to its success in the arcade, Donkey Kong &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;was ported to many other game systems&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, including the Atari 2600, Colecovision, Amiga 500, Apple II, Atari 7800, Intellivision, Commodore 64, Commodore VIC-20, Famicom Disk System,IBM PC booter, ZX Spectrum, Amstrad CPC, MSX, Atari 8-bit family and Coleco mini-arcade.  It also spawned numerous clones in both the arcade and home console game market.&#xD;&#xD;Donkey Kong was also the game that &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;allowed Nintendo to build the largest franchise in the video game world: Mario&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;. Your character in Donkey Kong (Jumpman) was quickly renamed Mario, and became the central character in the Super Mario Bros series.  Would the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) spark Nintendo;s rise to power in the home console game industry without Super Mario Bros?  Not likely.&#xD;&#xD;With the success of the Super Mario Bros franchise, Donkey Kong returned as a character in 1994 with the crazy popular Donkey Kong Country, and remained as a character in the Nintendo's universe since (e.g. check out Donkey Kong in Super Smash Bros).&#xD;&#xD;The original Donkey Kong game also received a great deal of fame following the release of the documentary &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;"The King of Kong: A Fistful of Quarters"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; in 2007 (a wildly-popular documentary about Steve Wiebe and Billy Mitchell competing for the world record high score on the game itself).  Since the documentary, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;far more people started playing Donkey &#xD;Kong competitively, and the world record has been broken dozens of times&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; by newcomers to the competitive retro game scene.  And just this year, Wes Copeland achieved the highest theoretical score on Donkey Kong of 1,218,000 points.  &#xD;&#xD;I should also note that, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Donkey Kong has become a cult classic among retro gamers and arcade collectors over the past decade&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  Perhaps the funniest reflection of this is a quote from Silver Matrix (Serge) on the Canadian arcade forum (CGCC) with reference to the US arcade forum (KLOV):  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#x201C;KLOV has become a fucking joke. Nothing but fat Americans sitting around their computer judging others (especially Canadians) over a double Big Mac while jerking off to Donkey Kong.&#x201D;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &#xD;&#xD;But beyond the retro game community, Donkey Kong continues to influence pop culture today.  Phrases like &#x201C;It&#x2019;s on like Donkey Kong!&#x201D; are commonplace, and you&#x2019;ll even find Donkey Kong in movies (e.g.and references to Donkey Kong in television and movies aren&#x2019;t uncommon whatsoever.  And for a 35-year-old game, that&#x2019;s quite impressive!&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="9_Entry_1_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
