<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:56:09 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The IBM PC turns 30 today...&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, August 12, 2011&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Today, hundreds of gadget blogs, web sites, radio hosts, and newscasters announced the 30th birthday of the PC......which drove me completely batty since TODAY IS NOT THE 30th BIRTHDAY OF THE PC! Personal Computers (PCs), as their definition suggests, are computers that are used for personal use at home - computers by Apple, Commodore, Tandy, Atari, Sinclair, and others were really the first personal computers, and they arose (roughly) in the late 1970s.&#xD;&#xD;Instead, today is the 30th birthday of the IBM PC.......the IBM PC 5150!&#xD;&#xD;On this day in 1981, IBM unveiled their own PC to respond to the large number of PCs that were already on the market (and shaping computing in a way that IBM never thought possible).&#xA0; IBM never thought that PCs would ever catch on, so they waited until 1981 before entering the PC market - and in doing so, they popularized the MS-DOS operating system and led to the mass proliferation of computer makers who made IBM PC clones (which basically were the same fundamental hardware as the IBM PC and could run MS-DOS and the same applications).&#xA0; In time, the large number of IBM PCs and even larger number of IBM PC clones eclipsed all other PC manufacturers except for Apple - Tandy, Commodore, Sinclair, and Atari all eventually disappeared as a result of the IBM PC.&#xA0; Consequently, IBM PC (or IBM PC clone) became synonymous &#x201C;PC&#x201D;, and Apple Macintosh became synonymous with &#x201C;Mac&#x201D;........you either had a PC or a Mac (the only two types of personal computers that were available by the early 1990s!).&#xA0; This is why people are calling today the anniversary of the PC (they really mean &#x201C;the anniversary of the IBM PC&#x201D;).&#xD;&#xD;Do I have an IBM PC 5150?&#xA0; Yes - it was a fellow colleague&#x2019;s who sold it to me when he retired.&#xA0; He kept it in mint collectable condition and even had a spare brand new motherboard in static bubble wrap for it that he gave me too.&#xD;&#xD;By 1981, IBM had a reputation for making solid business computers, and it shows in the IBM PC 5150 - it is extremely heavy, and made almost entirely of metal (my PC 5150 is shown below).&#xA0; Any plastic components (such as the front of the drive bays) are made of extremely durable/thick plastic. &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;The inside of the computer is equally beautiful - the power supply, twin floppy drives, motherboard and expansion cards are nicely arranged and firmly attached to the metal frame of the case. The CPU is easily visible on the motherboard between the power supply and the first expansion card.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Plus, the power switch is an ACTUAL power switch as shown to the right - it is built into the side of the power supply and can be easily accessed from the side of the PC.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Notice from the earlier pic how the inside looks brand new even today (this PC was reserved as a &#x201C;collectable&#x201D; from early on).&#xA0; Chances are these original IBM PCs will still be functional in 50 years (after the robot wars and zombie apocalypse). &#xD;&#xD;Since today is the 30th anniversary of the IBM PC, I connected my PC 5150 to a CGA monitor and booted it up......PC Load Letter....WTF?&#xA0; Just kidding.&#xA0; Loading DOS didn&#x2019;t take as long as I anticipated, but loading Lotus 1-2-3 was almost painful by today&#x2019;s standards (by early-1980s standards, it was normal).&#xA0;&#xA0; However, when Lotus 1-2-3 was loaded, it was very quick even by today&#x2019;s standards (spreadsheets haven&#x2019;t changed much since then ;-).&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="12_The_IBM_PC_turns_30_today..._files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
