<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind the Mac vs PC Rivalry — And Where Linux Quietly Took Over</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/mac-vs-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/mac-vs-pc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;mac-vs-pc.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;Mac vs PC&#34; title=&#34;Mac vs PC&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to computers, most people today use either a Mac or a PC. In this post, I’ll explore how this digital rivalry began, how it shaped modern computing — and how Linux quietly carved out a space of its own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-early-days-roots-of-the-rivalry&#34;&gt;The Early Days: Roots of the Rivalry&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the 1980s, personal computers (PCs) began appearing in homes, schools, and businesses across the world. A wide range of companies entered the market, including Apple, IBM, Tandy, Commodore, Atari, Texas Instruments, and Sinclair. Most of these early machines featured basic text-based interfaces — often just a simple version of the BASIC programming language. But a few notable outliers, like the Apple Macintosh and the IBM PC, ran more sophisticated operating systems that hinted at what modern computing would eventually become.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Tips for a Healthy Digital Lifestyle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/digital-lifestyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/digital-lifestyle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;phonewedding.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;Phone at Wedding&#34; title=&#34;Phone at Wedding&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As our world becomes more and more digital, so does the need for us to periodically evaluate our technology habits. A 2023 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reviews.org/mobile/cell-phone-addiction/&#34;&gt;reviews.org&lt;/a&gt; study found that people check their phone around 144 times a day. And according to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.statista.com/statistics/1258232/daily-time-spent-online-worldwide/&#34;&gt;Statista&lt;/a&gt;, people spend over 3 hours a day online at a PC for activities not related to work or school.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spending too much unstructured time on any device &amp;ndash; whether it be a phone, tablet, or PC &amp;ndash; has been linked to both physical and mental health issues, including increased feelings of stress, anxiety, and depression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RISCy business: The long and convoluted rise of today&#39;s dominant computing platform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/riscy-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/riscy-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;RISC.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;RISC timeline&#34; title=&#34;RISC timeline&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;risc-vs-cisc&#34;&gt;RISC vs CISC&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, most computing platforms were built with the burden of software in mind. To ensure that a software program could be written easily and with fewer instructions, additional circuitry was added to the central processing unit (CPU) to compensate. This was referred to as complex instruction set computing (CISC). CISC architecture is still common today thanks to the x86 architecture used by Intel and AMD CPUs in most workstations and servers. Unfortunately, the added circuitry within CISC CPUs equated to added cost and complexity - both of which made it more expensive to evolve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An overview of cloud buzz words</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/cloud-buzz-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/cloud-buzz-words/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;dilbert.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;Dilbert comic&#34; title=&#34;Dilbert comic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As this Dilbert comic eloquently illustrates, there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of cloud buzz words thrown around today. But as strange and complex as they may sound (even to seasoned developers and system administrators), they are not difficult to understand. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through the different components and features of the cloud, explaining the associated buzz words along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-the-cloud&#34;&gt;What is the cloud?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in the early 1990s, when the US government sold off parts of their ARPAnet and NSFnet to private companies (later called Internet Service Providers, or ISPs) to create the public Internet, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything exciting about the Internet at all. After all, the Internet was just a physical computer network that allowed your computer to talk to other computers, usually through a telephone network via a modem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work-from-home is the new BlackBerry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/work-from-home-is-the-new-blackberry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/work-from-home-is-the-new-blackberry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;blackberry.jpeg#right&#34; alt=&#34;BlackBerry&#34; title=&#34;BlackBerry&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I vividly remember the first time I was issued a BlackBerry smartphone back in the 2000s for work. I&amp;rsquo;d read emails while in line at the Pita shop during lunch hour, formulating a plan and response before I returned to my desk to reply. For emails that required a quick response, I&amp;rsquo;d hammer out a response on the BlackBerry keyboard while in line. And having access to my Outlook calendar on the BlackBerry meant that I could view, schedule and prioritize my tasks anywhere. There was never any doubt in my mind that it made me far more productive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The future looks a lot like mainframe computing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/mainframe-computing-is-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/mainframe-computing-is-the-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ibm.jpeg#center&#34; alt=&#34;IBM mainframe&#34; title=&#34;IBM mainframe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mainframe computers, like the IBM one shown above, were the first digital computers that started appearing in big companies during the 1950s. They were room-sized behemoths of circuitry and steel primarily used to generate balance sheets and income statements. And while IBM still sells a small number of mainframe computers today, they only enjoyed mainstream popularity until the late 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While early mainframes were only accessed by the people who managed it, most mainframes of the 1970s and 1980s ran programs that were accessed by remote users via a dumb terminal. Dumb terminals were not standalone computers; they had a display and keyboard, but merely allowed you to interact with a central mainframe computer across a network connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why you should use technology less</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/why-you-should-use-technology-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/why-you-should-use-technology-less/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;techbad.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Tech bad&#34; title=&#34;Tech bad&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I’ve taken to using technology less and less in my daily life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I leave my phone in the car when going to a party or social event. I’ll only fetch it if I want to take a picture, and only after appreciating the moment I’d like to capture to the fullest.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When I listen to music on my phone (via headphones) during the long walks I take to get exercise and relax, I don’t check my phone at all. If the environment around me is interesting enough, I’ll stop the music to take in the sounds around me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I limit the time I spend perusing social media to 15 minutes at a time, and only when I’m in a relaxed mood, often in the evening. If I’m sent an interesting article during the day, I’ll quickly post it to LinkedIn/Twitter to share with others who could benefit from it, but not use that opportunity to browse other’s posts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When it comes to work commitments, I will call or meet with people when possible, rather than message or email them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A decade ago, my habits were entirely different:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Nokia tells us about the Internet in 2008</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/what-nokia-tells-us-about-the-internet-in-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/what-nokia-tells-us-about-the-internet-in-2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;n810.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Nokia N810&#34; title=&#34;Nokia N810&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While cleaning out a drawer last night, I came across my old, beloved Nokia N810 Internet appliance that I bought in early 2008. This thing was sexy and entirely made of aluminum. It had a touchscreen (and stylus), backlit slide-out keyboard, expandable SD storage, GPS and front-facing webcam running Maemo Linux on an ARM CPU.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The N810 came out shortly after the iPhone in 2007, and just before Android phones started hitting the market en mass in 2008. But the N810 was not a phone at all.  Instead, it was a portable WiFi-only, Internet-in-your-pocket device, and something that appealed tremendously to me when I first saw it reviewed on the GeekBrief podcast with Cali Lewis.  Better yet, using the promo code on the podcast gave you 20% off and free shipping if you were in the US. When I phoned Nokia, they gladly honoured the deal for me in Canada, and I scored one for under $400 CDN.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The future of smartphones</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/the-future-of-smartphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/the-future-of-smartphones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sp1.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;SP1&#34; title=&#34;SP1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the picture at the top of this post, last week BlackBerry’s smartphone market share fell to 0% in the global marketplace. In all fairness, this number reflects the number of devices running BlackBerry OS (not the number of BlackBerry-branded Android devices, which together with all other Android devices, comprise 82% of the market).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you think back to 2007, BlackBerry pretty much owned the smartphone world that they created - they were too big to fail, and too proud to accept that Apple and Google could eat their cake.  But 10 years later, they’re a niche company trying to peddle their security and smartphone management software to any Fortune 500 company that still has fond memories of their brand.  It’s a stark reminder of how quickly the tech industry can change, and how unforgiving it can be to those left behind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of BYOD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/the-evolution-of-byod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/the-evolution-of-byod/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;byod.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;BYOD&#34; title=&#34;BYOD&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the 1980s, email remained a luxury for a small number of larger organizations and universities. Mobile email did not exist.  Instead, pagers and cellular telephones were the primary tools for mobile communication. However, in the early 1990s, email rose to prominence with the commercialization of the Internet. Although early smartphones did exist at this time (e.g. IBM’s Simon), email was not considered a mobile technology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But by the mid 1990s, the computing landscape had exploded.  PCs spread across companies like a virus, and productivity software like Microsoft Office became standard practice.  Email quickly rose to prominence, and was the primary method for communication within companies by the late 1990s.  Microsoft Outlook (part of Microsoft Office) allowed you to send and receive emails internally or across the internet via your company’s Microsoft Exchange Server (which is still the dominant email server today).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why BlackBerry failed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/why-blackberry-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/why-blackberry-failed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;failure.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;failure&#34; title=&#34;failure&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I really didn’t want to do another BlackBerry-related post.  It just doesn’t feel like something that interests me anymore.  But today I decided to do one anyways for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a long-time BlackBerry user and author of their academic textbooks  - as a result, I know their technology inside-out, and have worked closely with the organization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have lived and taught computer science in the K-W region for the past 15 years, so many of my friends and past students have worked for (or still work for) RIM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspective on RIM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/perspective-on-rim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/perspective-on-rim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always considered myself someone who has a super-natural ability to put things in perspective and explain them to others.  After all, I’ve taught adults for 13 years, and EVERYTHING must be put into perspective when you teach adults ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, it is difficult to put a large situation in perspective when you are too close to the action (for lack of a better phrase).  And I’ve been close to RIM for many years both physically (I live 15 minutes from the RIM headquarters in Canada) and mentally (I’ve dealt with them for years on the academic program front and used their products).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIM is dead. Long live RIM.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/rim-is-dead-long-live-rim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/rim-is-dead-long-live-rim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;rimdead.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;RIM&#34; title=&#34;RIM&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The worst possible news for RIM right now is a delay in bringing some sort of modern product to market.  In other words, delaying their QNX “killer” smartphone.  But that is exactly what they announced last night - QNX phones won’t be ready until the end of 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem is that they are already behind their competitors with little chance at turning the company around and maintaining a big presence in the smartphone market.  This delay will pretty much cripple their chances of catching up with iPhone and Android.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I threw my back out playing Angry Birds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/how-i-threw-my-back-out-playing-angry-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/how-i-threw-my-back-out-playing-angry-birds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;angrybirds.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;Angry Birds&#34; title=&#34;Angry Birds&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I know this sounds extremely lame, but on Wednesday August 3rd, I threw my back out playing Angry Birds.  And each time I’ve told people that, they’ve either burst out laughing, gave me the quizzical look (as if I’m joking), or simply state something along the lines of “if it were to happen, it would have happened to you.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I definitely plan on telling people that I threw my back out playing Angry Birds at future events (it is a great ice breaker for sure!).  And if they ask about details, I’ll refer them to this post&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlackBerry 950 teardown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/blackberry-950-teardown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/blackberry-950-teardown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bb950.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;BlackBerry 950&#34; title=&#34;BlackBerry 950&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I was moving the stuff in my desk from the old campus to the new campus yesterday, I found an old BlackBerry 950&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;..so I took it apart and found an Intel FW88386VXSD CPU, which is an embedded version of the famous Intel 80386 CPU (big black chip on the right side of the picture above).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I remember having an 80386 PC that weighed a ton back in 1990, so this is like carrying that PC around in your pocket.  I wonder if it could run Windows 3.1 or Linux (remember that Linus Torvalds first developed Linux on an 80386).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlackBerry then and now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/blackberry-then-and-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/blackberry-then-and-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bb.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;BlackBerry 950 and 8830&#34; title=&#34;BlackBerry 950 and 8830&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You know - most technologies change drastically over time.  As a result, I got my hands on an old BlackBerry 950 model from 1998 (the 850/950 series were the original BlackBerry smartphones on the 800/900 MHz Mobitex networks, respectively).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem is this:  It really hasn’t changed that much.  Aside from the color and graphics, the BlackBerry 950 running BlackBerry Device Software 2.5 had pretty much the same applications and functionality as the BlackBerry 8830 running BlackBerry Device Software 4.5!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrackBerry Book</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/crackberry-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/crackberry-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;crackberrybook.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;CrackBerry book&#34; title=&#34;CrackBerry book&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I am definitely a CrackBerry user.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a result, when I saw a new book on Amazon called &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CrackBerry: True Tales of BlackBerry Use and Abuse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I simply had to order it and pay the inflated shipping and US exchange rate to have it delivered to Canada. And I am glad I did - it was a hilarious read, and I must admit that I can relate well to the crazy stories within.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linuxtopia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/linuxtopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/linuxtopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past several months (and year), it seems that Linux is really making its way into the desktop market (up until now, it has ruled the server market).  Every time I pick up a magazine at Chapters or read Google news, there is some new Linux device or technology.  Here are a few that have caught my eye in the past short while:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The rapid development of Compiz (formerly Beryl), which puts shame to all other desktop effects and is extremely easy to use and requires very few hardware resources to run.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The rapid adoption of Ubuntu Linux on the desktop market as a Windows replacement (I use it every day on my laptop, and it is a great OS).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hardware manufacturers pre-installing Linux instead of Windows as an option on laptops and desktops (especially Dell and HP).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The addition of Linux PCs and mobile devices - e.g.:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;n810.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;N810&#34; title=&#34;N810&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone first impressions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/iphone-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/iphone-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;iphone.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;iPhone&#34; title=&#34;iPhone&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The iPhone went on sale in the US yesterday.  And yes, for the past several months since its introduction, I wanted one badly&amp;hellip;..but after hearing from those who have one, I am not so upset now that the iPhone is not available in Canada until later this year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basically, those who have one say that it “feels like a 1.0 device”, which it is.   It uses the old EDGE service rather than new and fast 3G Mobile service in order to save battery power (Apple rationalizes that most will use the iPhone’s WiFi to browse the Internet instead).  Plus, Flash and Java are not supported on the iPhone (too much processing/bandwidth?). And my biggest problem with the iPhone is that it only has 4 or 8 GB of storage (bad).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
