<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:41:43 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;SUN Ultra 20 - cheap but powerful Linux box&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Monday, August 10, 2015&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;If you&#x2019;ve read my post from February this year (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/5DA82812-579D-4657-A65C-98E53B3A4F11"&gt;The evolution of the power workstation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;), you&#x2019;ll already know that the ultra-expensive 64-bit RISC power workstations that ruled the 1990s died out approximately a decade ago and were replaced by cheaper 64-bit PCs based on Intel or AMD processors.&#xD;&#xD;Only one power workstation manufacturer transitioned to the PC market: SUN Microsystems.  In 2005, SUN Microsystems started selling high-end PCs that were designed for the professional or prosumer market - they had AMD Opteron CPUs, SATA hard drives,  high-end Nvidia Quadro video cards, and pretty much anything else you&#x2019;d find in a PC (sound, USB, etc.).  They usually ran about $2000-$4000 depending on the hardware configuration, which was very competitive at the time for a power workstation. The most popular PC models that SUN made were the Ultra 20 and 40, and they were quite successful in the prosumer market until they were discontinued in 2010.&#xD;&#xD;Now, 2010 was five years ago......so you can usually get a SUN Ultra 20 or 40 pretty cheap nowadays and install any distribution of Linux on it.  I picked up the SUN Ultra 20 in the pic above for $30 - it has a 64-bit AMD Opteron (2.6GHz), 2 GB of RAM , Nvidia Quadro FX graphics card, and a 250GB hard drive.  Fedora 22 Linux runs incredibly fast on it, even by today&#x2019;s standards.&#xD;&#xD;So, why buy a 5-year-old (or older) high-end computer when you can just buy a new one?  &#xD;Well, there are several reasons for it:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	a)	It&#x2019;s much much cheaper - can you buy a new computer for $30?&#xD;	b)	You&#x2019;re keeping good hardware utilized for a longer period of time rather than having it recycled or dumped in a landfill - and higher-end PC hardware often lasts a very long time! &#xD;	c)	High-end hardware that is 5+ years old often still has more than enough power to run modern software, whether it be Windows 10 or a distribution of Linux.  The only exception to this is if you want a gaming PC.  However, most people typically use their computer to browse the Internet, manage photos/videos and work on documents - for these tasks, you wont notice any difference between a SUN Ultra 20 and a new PC for $500 at Best Buy.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;If you are planning on buying an older computer, keep in mind that you want to look for a high-end or prosumer PC (such as a SUN Ultra, HP X-series, or Dell Precision) - if it cost several thousand dollars 5+ years ago, it&#x2019;s likely made with quality components, including a high-grade power supply that will last a long time.  Most prosumer PCs also have plenty of RAM and a high-end video card, that will allow it to run modern operating systems such as Win10 and the latest Linux distributions with ease.  You can usually find these machines on your local classified ad site (e.g. Kijiji) or at your local non-profit PC recycling depot.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="10_SUN_Ultra_20_-_cheap_but_powerful_Linux_box_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
