<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:41:14 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The coolest arcade game ever&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Tuesday, October 1, 2013&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;....is definitely Namco&#x2019;s &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ms. Pac-man/Galaga 20th Reunion (Class of &#x2019;81) &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;released in 2001. The picture at the top of this post is the actual game in the movie &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Sharknado&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (2013).&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;So what makes this the best arcade game ever made?&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Firstly, it has the three killer arcade games from the early 1980s: Ms. Pac-man, Galaga, and the original Pac-man (which you can play if you enter a secret joystick code described below).  These three games have &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;stood the test of time&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - they were crazy addictive back in the early 1980s and people still go crazy over playing them today.&#xA0; This was due, in part, to the fact that all three games were prime examples of Nolan Bushnell&#x2019;s Law:&#xA0; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;A good game should be easy to learn and difficult to master - it should reward the first quarter and the hundredth.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;But this alone isn&#x2019;t enough to make this the coolest arcade game ever.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Remember that video game arcades died long ago.&#xA0; You may only find one or two at the odd bar, laundromat, restaurant or pizza parlor.&#xA0; But there is a very good chance that those machines are ones that people would be more likely to spend a quarter on, and Ms. Pac-man and Galaga were the two most successful Namco video games within North America!&#xA0; Think of your local area - can you identify some place that still has an original Ms. Pac-man or Galaga game?&#xA0; In my area (Kitchener-Waterloo), I can think of 2 off the top of my head: Sonny&#x2019;s burger joint in Waterloo, and the Frederick Twin Cinemas in Kitchener.&#xA0; Both places still have those arcades because people still put quarters into them!&#xD;&#xD;So, let&#x2019;s think like Namco - it&#x2019;s the late 1990s and we want to release a brand new dual Ms. Pac-man/Galaga game because they are sure-fire winners (with a hidden Pac-man game in there for the Pac-man die hards).&#xA0; How will we convince people to buy them?&#xA0; In other words, how would Namco convince a restaurant owner that if they were to buy this arcade machine, they would be guaranteed to make their money back on it plus a lot more?&#xA0; Simple.&#xA0; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;They added a continue feature!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; This is pure genius on Namco&#x2019;s part since old arcade games didn&#x2019;t allow you to continue - instead, you only had 3 lives, and that was it, which meant you had to practice to get your name on the high score list.&#xA0; With Ms. Pac-man/Galaga 20th Reunion (Class of &#x2019;81), if people want to get their name on a high score list, they just need to have enough $$ because they could insert another credit and continue from where they left off!&#xA0; Even if the owner charged a quarter per play, people would continue several times, dropping a few dollars into the game and having loads of fun.&#xA0; It was a complete success - people went nuts over these machines, and still do.&#xA0; I&#x2019;ve seen them all over the place, and they have become an easy-to-recognize icon.&#xD;&#xD;Another important feature about this arcade is that it &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;runs the exact same game code as the original games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; from the early 1980s.&#xA0; But how is this even possible given that the hardware from back then went obsolete long ago?!?!?!?&#xA0; Well, Namco simply ensured that their new board ran the same &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Zilog Z80 CPU platform&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;!&#xA0;&#xA0; Pac-man and Ms. Pac-man had a single Zilog Z80 CPU that ran at about 3MHz, and Galaga had three Zilog Z80 CPUs that ran at 3MHz each.&#xA0; The new printed circuit board (PCB) that Namco made for this arcade has a Zilog Z180 CPU running at 20MHz to handle all of the game code (the Z180 is just a beefed up Z80).&#xA0; The firmware and game programs themselves are are stored on two modern ROM (Read Only Memory) chips that have a much higher capacity, and the dozens of chips on the original PCBs that provided memory storage, input, sound and graphic generation are now performed by two custom logic chips that can easily perform all of the functions!&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;And the whole board is tiny - the picture below shows the PCB next to the manual (standard 8.5x11&#x201D; printed paper).&#xA0; Modern arcade machines (after about 1987) started using a standard connector called JAMMA (Japanese Amusement Machinery Manufacturer&#x2019;s Association) that allowed you to easily put different game PCBs in arcade cabinets without having to modify the wiring.&#xA0; The PCB below has a JAMMA connection that essentially allows you to stick this in any *relatively* modern arcade machine (which is what I&#x2019;ve done ;-)&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Finally, Namco decided to release the cabinet in three sizes (shown in the picture below) to fit the needs of different people and places:&#xA0; &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Full-sized&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - An upright cabinet that looked very similar to an old Ms. Pac-man or Galaga full-sized cabinet.....but with a huge 25&#x201D; monitor (the original Ms. Pac-man and Galaga arcade games only had a 19&#x201D; monitor).&#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cabaret&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - A slimmer, shorter version of the full-sized upright that was marketed for home use only.&#xA0; It had a 19&#x201D; monitor, but instead of having a coin door, it had a sticker that looked like a coin door.&#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cocktail&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - A two-player, table-based version with a 19&#x201D; monitor that was very common in bars, pizza parlors, and pretty much everywhere else.&#xA0; Namco probably sold as many of these as they did the Full-sized cabinets! &#x2028;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;OK - so what are the secret codes I can enter if I find one of these arcades?&#xD;&#xD;Recall from earlier that one of the coolest features of this game is that it also contains the original Pac-man game!&#xA0; But the game is hidden from the start screen - instead, you need to enter a secret joystick code in order to play it.&#xA0; When you insert your coin and get to the start screen shown to the right, simply enter the following joystick code:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Up,Up,Up&#xD;	&#x2022;	Down,Down,Down&#xD;	&#x2022;	Left, Right, Left, Right, Left&#x2028;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;You&#x2019;ll hear a chime at this point and the Pac-man ghost on the screen will change to a different color - if you hit the Ms. Pac-man start button now, you&#x2019;ll now be playing good old Pac-man game instead of Ms. Pac-man!&#xA0;&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Similarly, if you want to enable fast speed in Ms. Pac-man or fast shooting in Galaga, simply perform the following pattern after inserting your coin:&#xA0; &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Left, Right, Left, Right&#xD;	&#x2022;	Up, Up, Up&#xD;	&#x2022;	Fire button&#x2028;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Again, you&#x2019;ll hear a chime at this point, and if you start Ms. Pac-man, it will be the rapid version - if you instead start Galaga, you&#x2019;ll have rapid fire!&#xA0; One thing to note is that these codes only affect the current game - you&#x2019;ll need to enter these code each time you want to start Pac-man, or enable fast speed/shooting.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Play Galaga for free (for a short time)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Without entering any money, just watch the demo screen until it cycles to the Galaga demo.&#xA0; During the Galaga demo, when the boss Galaga starts its tractor beam to suck up the ship, you can move the joystick and actually take control of the game!&#xA0; You can play the game for a single round, and if you shoot all of the boss Galaga on the screen before they try to suck up your ship, the game will reset and display ROM version information before returning to the normal start screen.&#xA0; This is a great way to get the version of the ROMs used on the game board without opening the cabinet.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Are there sequels to this arcade?&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Yes. Because it was so incredibly popular, Namco released another version in 2005 called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pac-man 25th Anniversary&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, which contained the same games, but you could select Pac-man from the menu screen instead of entering a secret code.&#xA0; The PCB for this game was almost identical too - however, it had newer and fewer components.&#xA0; The cabinet was also released in the same three sizes:&#xA0; full-sized (shown left), cabaret and cocktail.&#xD;&#xD;In 2010, Namco released yet another arcade called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pac-man&#x2019;s Arcade Party &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;that contained&#xA0; 13 games in total: Pac-man, Ms. Pac-man, Galaga, Dig Dug, Galaxian, Pac-mania, Galaga '88, Mappy, Xevious, Rolling Thunder, Dragon Spirit, Rally-X, and Bosconian. However, the hardware for this system was not Zilog Z80-based - instead, it was basically the same hardware you&#x2019;d find in a Sony Playstation 2.&#xA0; As a result, Namco would have had to rewrite much of the code to work on this new platform, or run the original code in a software emulator on the new platform (much more likely).&#xA0; The gameplay for each game is identical to the original game, but the system loses a bit of it&#x2019;s retro charm by ditching the Zilog Z80 platform.....it&#x2019;s not longer an &#x201C;authentic&#x201D; original game from a technology standpoint.&#xA0; Namco also released this version in the same three sizes (full-sized, cabaret &amp; cocktail), with LCD monitors in place of the old CRT picture tube monitors (which are no longer manufactured in North America).&#xA0; The picture to the right is a full-sized Pac-man&#x2019;s Arcade Party cabinet.&#xD;&#xD;I think it&#x2019;s reasonable to assume that Namco will release another version in 2015, 2020, 2025, and so on.&#xA0; After all, people still play these games, and places still buy them!&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Hopefully the price stays the same (or lower) given that the hardware components will only get cheaper over time.&#xA0; This will allow the places that buy them to keep the games at 25&#xA2; - these games are a lot of fun, but I can&#x2019;t see people paying $1 to play or continue their games.&#xA0; At 25&#xA2; though, I&#x2019;m pretty sure that it will be crazy popular for many years to come ;-)&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_The_coolest_arcade_game_ever_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
