<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:32:27 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Atomiswave Candy Cabaret Build&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, October 16, 2015&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Last week, I managed to get a brand new arcade cabinet for free from someone on Facebook who didn&#x2019;t have the time to complete it.  It&#x2019;s a Japanese-style sit down arcade (commonly called a &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;candy cab&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;), but with a narrow width that only allows for a single set of controls (smaller, narrow arcades are commonly called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;cabarets&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;).  Here are some pics of the machine before I picked it up:&#xD;&#xD;    &#xD;&#xD;The person who made it was a professional cabinet maker, and he did an absolutely amazing job in building this cabinet out of MDF.  &#xD;&#xD;And the person who was giving it away (a friend of the person who built it) also made sure to prime the routed corners of the MDF with Shellac to ensure that it would be easy to prime.&#xD;&#xD;Every fine detail was very clearly thought-out, machined and cut to perfection.  There were heavy-duty castors on the bottom that were hidden under a nice base, the rear door was mounted using professional cabinet hinges,  the rear of the bezel was cut to fit a 19&#x201D; LCD panel, and even the underside of the control panel was recessed under the joystick area in order to allow the joystick ball to clear the Acrylite overlay at a comfortable height.  &#xD;&#xD;Oh, and by the way, the pre-cut and routed Acrylite pieces were also included as shown to the left.  He even included an LCD panel for the machine....all FREE ;-)&#xD;&#xD;What I did as soon as I got it home was prime the entire cabinet with Killz primer/sealer (I used 3 thin coats and allowed for drying time between each coat).  I then applied two different colours of high-gloss Valspar latex enamel (3 coats of each with drying time between each) to get the shiny hard plastic look.  After a week of drying, Valspar latex enamel becomes perhaps the most durable enamel that you&#x2019;ll find. To keep with the Japanese candy cab theme, I did the majority of the cabinet in white gloss, and the bezel and control panel in red gloss.  I also did the inside of the cabinet in red gloss because I planned on putting in my Atomiswave JAMMA arcade system (which is also red ;-).  &#xD;&#xD;I also had to cut out 1&#x201D; of the bezel on each side to ensure that the LCD panel could fit in horizontally, and then created a bezel insert and control panel underlay out of black decal.  I then mounted the LCD panel, applied the Acrylite bezel and control panel overlay, and finally added the controls and speaker grille:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Next, I wired up the controls, speaker, switching power supply and Atomiswave system to the JAMMA hardness and ran power to both the LCD and switching power supply:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;And Voila!  It&#x2019;s done!&#xD;&#xD;I&#x2019;ve got Metal Slug 6 in there right now, but I also have a Dolphin Blue cartridge for the Atomiswave that I&#x2019;ll stick in there and play as well.  &#xD;&#xD;Most Atomiswave games use only 3 buttons....but Metal Slug 6 uses 5.  Luckily, button 4 is useless in Metal Slug 6, so I just wired up the first 3 buttons normally and the fifth button (weapon change) is also wired to the Start button.  It plays like a dream!  Here is a Youtube video of it playing: https://youtu.be/3XUgqsL6zyw&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="16_Atomiswave_Candy_Cabaret_Build_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
