<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:31:58 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Galaga turns 32 years old today....&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Tuesday, July 23, 2013&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;There are some things from the 80s that were so good, that they are worth blogging about today.&#xA0; Michael Jackson&#x2019;s Thriller, the Nintendo NES, Ferris Bueller&#x2019;s Day Off, break dancing, Hulk Hogan, The Goonies, Cyndi Lauper, and skateboarding to name some.&#xA0; But when it comes to video games, there was really one that stood above the crowd: Galaga.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;... Everyone wanted to be like him.&#xA0; You were golden if he knew your name.&#xA0; He was the high-scorer on #Galaga. #simpletimes&#xA0; &#xD;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; -Sammi on Twitter (@girlydaytrader) &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Galaga was released July 23rd, 1981, and was crazy popular - the graphics were amazing for the time, and the gameplay was incredibly addictive.&#xA0; But words don&#x2019;t do it justice - just watch G4TV&#x2019;s review of Galaga here: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.g4tv.com/videos/59186/top-100-video-games-of-all-time-92-galaga/"&gt;http://www.g4tv.com/videos/59186/top-100-video-games-of-all-time-92-galaga/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &#xD;&#xD;There you were at the bottom of the screen with your ship firing up at the swarms of aliens swooping down at you in droves and firing shots towards your ship. The boss aliens could also suck you up in their tractor beam, and if you kill the captor, you get double ships and double fire!&#xA0; Every so many levels was a challenging stage where you could rack up points by shooting aliens in quick succession.&#xA0; In each level, the aliens were unpredictable, but you could learn techniques with practice that helped you defeat them without getting killed.&#xA0; You could sink 1000 quarters into the game and not get bored with it. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;All the best games are easy to learn and difficult to master. They should reward the first quarter and the hundredth.&#xD;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; -Nolan Bushnell (founder of Atari)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Now I must admit that Galaga is definitely my all-time favorite game, which is why I have 2 Galaga arcade machines in my basement (upright and cocktail table versions).&#xA0; But I&#x2019;m not the only one who loves this game today.&#xA0; Alongside Pac-man and Ms. Pac-man, Galaga is pretty much the only retro video game that is still crazy popular across all generations.&#xA0; It was released for a ton of game consoles and computing platforms (the Nintendo NES version is great), and you can buy it today for all of the latest game consoles as part of the Namco Museum collection, as well as on your Android and iOS devices, such as your iPad.&#xA0; In 2000, Namco even released a new arcade machine called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ms.Pac-man/Galaga Namco 20 Year Reunion: Class of 1981 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;which had the games Ms. Pac-man and Galaga (the left side artwork was Ms. Pac-man and the right side artwork was Galaga).&#xA0; I see these machines in pizza parlors, laundromats, bars, and restaurants still today, including the 25th and 30th anniversary versions too!&#xA0; If you search for #Galaga on Twitter, you&#x2019;ll see a lot of people gushing about how cool these machines are (with pics).&#xA0; I even came across a Twitter post a few months back from some home boy in Florida that read &#x201C;You don want dem problems shoot yo ass up like #Galaga.&#x201D;&#xA0; I mean....come on....that&#x2019;s classic....&#xD;&#xD;Here are some other things you may or may not know about Galaga:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	It was featured in the 1983 movie War Games with Matthew Broderick.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Alec Baldwin had a huge Galaga addiction in the 1980s, playing for very long hours each day.&#xD;	&#x2022;	There is a no fire cheat in the game, where aliens stop shooting at you.&#xA0; To activate it, you shoot everything but the left 2 bees on level 1 and let them dive at you for about 10-15 minutes.&#xA0; They eventually stop shooting at you and nothing will shoot at you for the remainder of the game.&#xD;	&#x2022;	It is featured at the Game On 2.0 exhibition right now at the Ontario Science Centre (until September 2nd).&#xD;	&#x2022;	Although most people pronounce it GAL-a-ga, its original pronunciation is Ga-LAY-ga to match the pronunciation of its predecessor Ga-LAX-ian.&#xD;	&#x2022;	It has two sequels, Gaplus and Galaga &#x2019;88, which were relatively unpopular.&#xD;	&#x2022;	It was featured on a 1986 episode of Dr. Who.&#xD;	&#x2022;	It was featured and mentioned (by Tony Stark) in the 2012 film The Avengers.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Next to Pac-man and Ms. Pac-man, it was one of the most bootlegged arcade games of all time - bootleg hardware manufacturers created and sold bootleg PCBs to arcade operators for a lower cost.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;To learn all of the details about Galaga, see some cool Galaga fan art and t-shirts, visit &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://galaga.info/"&gt;http://galaga.info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (check it out!)&#xD;&#xD;Today is the 32nd anniversary of Galaga.&#xA0; And the original Galaga arcade had three 8-bit Zilog Z80 CPUs to run the game code, graphics and sound.... for a total of 32 bits of parallel processing power!&#xA0; So, I guess you could say that today is Galaga&#x2019;s champagne birthday!&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="23_Galaga_turns_32_years_old_today...._files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
