<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:55:46 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The death of SGI&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Wednesday, April 1, 2009&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Today is definitely a sad day - SGI announced their bankruptcy.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;SGI was once a great company - in the 1990s, they made the best computers ever, such as the Indigo2, O2, and Octane.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;The cases and designs looked awesome, and they had amazingly fast 64-bit MIPS RISC CPUs and stellar video cards!&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;To the right is one of their ads:&#xD;&#xD;Plus, they made my favorite UNIX operating system: IRIX.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Although I am a Mac OS X UNIX user now, IRIX will always be my favorite UNIX.&#xA0;&#xA0; The following comic from UserFriendly.org captures it perfectly:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;SGI basically sold their entire company for $25 million in cash to pay preferred creditors (they have over $500 million in debt and just over $300 million in assets).&#xA0; I guess it shouldn&#x2019;t really come as a surprise since they discontinued their MIPS/IRIX line in 2006 due to financial reasons, but I had hoped that they would at least exist as a niche seller of Linux clusters.&#xD;&#xD;Ironically, this past weekend I prepared an SGI Indy box with the File System Navigator (FSN) program on it from the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jurassic Park&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; movie (1993) for my class as a cool demo.&#xA0; SGI was used to create many movies in the 1990s, but was most often used by scientists and engineers for visualization (e.g. chemical modeling, CAD) and other heavy duty purposes.&#xD;&#xD;SGI was once a great company that made amazing computers and the best UNIX.  May it rest in peace.&#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_Entry_1_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
