<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:39:44 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Are you a Mac or a PC......&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Thursday, March 13, 2008&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;This question dates back to the early 1990s.&#xA0; Yes, you can like both Apple Macs and Windows PCs, but there must be one that you like a bit more than the other, and the answer is widely considered a reflection on your personality. &#xD;&#xD;If you are ultra-Mac, you prefer to use an aesthetic computer that &#x201C;just works&#x201D; - as a result, you are usually sexy, artistic and cool.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;If you are ultra-PC, you prefer to use a clunky un-aesthetic computer that is difficult to use, crashes often, is a virus hell, yet is guaranteed to work with any piece of hardware with a software driver written by a 10-year-old boy in a barn in China - as a result, you are nerdy, cheap and non-cool.&#xD;&#xD;Here is a Joy of Tech comic that illustrates this:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Like all stereotypes, it isn&#x2019;t exactly true. However, for me, I am definitely 95% Mac and 5% PC.&#xA0; This is why:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;I like to use a computer that looks good and doesn&#x2019;t take up a whole room.&#xD;&#xD;I don&#x2019;t like viruses and spyware and malware. (0 for Mac, over 140,000 for PC)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;I like the power and flexibility of UNIX-based systems (stable, secure).&#xD;&#xD;I like operating systems that are intuitive and don&#x2019;t try to get in your way (after fighting with Windows, I come home to an intuitive Mac).&#xD;&#xD;I like operating systems that are fast, sexy looking, and feature-rich (OS X rules this space).&#xD;&#xD;I like operating systems that have a large amount of Open Source software available (there is not a single Windows program that I can&#x2019;t get an equivalent one for Mac).&#xD;&#xD;I like to compile my own software from source as well as write shell/PERL/etc scripts.&#xD;&#xD;I like computers that work with hardware and other computers easily (&#x201C;it just works&#x201D; with a Mac).&#xD;&#xD;I am not a big gamer (Windows owns this space - although I like games, I typically play them on a console such as Xbox360).&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;I like to get good value for my money, but I absolutely hate buying cheap crap. Macs are more expensive than PCs, but that is because Apple doesn&#x2019;t sell a low-end low-quality computer.&#xA0; When you compare the specs on a low-end Mac to that of a high-end PC, you will quickly find that the hardware and price is the same, but the Mac is far better made when you hold one in your hands.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;I like to run multiple OSes (Mac hardware runs the latest Intel platforms and can easily multi-boot Windows, Linux and OS X - it is the only computer that can run any OS).&#xD;&#xD;I like to add hardware (Macs are easy to upgrade, but today, most hardware upgrades are connected externally via USB such as extra hard drive storage such as Drobo).&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Basically, stereotypes are crap - the tools that you choose to use should reflect your personal preferences.&#xA0; In the 1990s, I was mostly PC because Macs at the time did not match my preferences.&#xA0; Back then, PCs and Macs were both clunky, yet PCs had more hardware expansion and far less cost.&#xA0; Similarly, Windows looked better than the old Mac OS, had more software, more stability, more security, and was just as easy to use compared to Mac OS.&#xA0; But in computing, things change - it is important to go with whatever is the best out there at any given time. &#xD;&#xD;I am not the only one that is more Mac than PC, it seems to be a big theme today as many people are switching over to Macs from PCs.&#xA0; Perhaps that is why I love watching those Mac vs PC commercials from Apple (they are sooooooo true :-)&#xD;&#xD;Lots of people on YouTube have made their own Mac vs PC commercials - while most of them are very amateurish, there are some funny ones.&#xA0; The best one I have seen is the Mac vs PC Rap Video shown in the picture at the top of this blog - you can watch it at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://macorpc.org/"&gt;http://macorpc.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.&#xA0; Enjoy!&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="13_Are_you_Mac_or_PC......_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="497px" height="373px"/>
</content>
