<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:39:45 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Gentoo MIPS Linux dead badger update&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Saturday, March 15, 2008&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Aaron and Peter have been working very hard reading manuals, obscure documentation, netbooting the classroom Octane, preparing the system (tedious), downloading software to it and compiling kernels (several times), and attempting to configure the kernels to boot via arcload. &#xD;&#xD;To give you a good idea of the steps involved, here is the documentation that they (and I) have created during the process:&#xA0; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="Installing%20Linux%20on%20a%20Dead%20Badger,%20Octane%20MIPS%20R12000-1.pdf"&gt;Installing Linux on a Dead Badger, Octane MIPS R12000.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - it is a good indication of the work involved. &#xD;&#xD;They have the process down, but although we can get the latest kernel loaded by arcload, it doesn&#x2019;t boot (a common problems with past kernels on SGI MIPS due to the rigid structure of MIPS software). &#xD;&#xD;So, now, they are going to get creative - either compiling an older kernel, patching the current one, or messing with the SGI Volume Header and System Partitions (#9 and #11) to get the system up and running using ssh file transfer and image files (a complex kind of MacGyver trick).&#xD;&#xD;We will eventually get Linux running beautifully on the Octane and then pimp it up to be a wicked fast server.&#xA0; After this whole ordeal, installing Linux on a dead badger will be easy by comparison.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="15_Gentoo_MIPS_Linux_dead_badger_update_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
