<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>recommended reads on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/categories/recommended-reads/</link>
    <description>Recent content in recommended reads on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jasoneckert.github.io/categories/recommended-reads/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyberpunk, Sci-Fi &amp; General Fiction</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/reads/fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/reads/fiction/</guid>
      <description>Thomas J. Ryan: The Adolescence of P-1 (1977) This is probably the best book I have ever read regarding our human desire for artificial intelligence (AI). It’s about a University of Waterloo student who creates an AI on IBM mainframes. Don’t let that bore you though - it’s a captivating read and has a great ending. I wouldn’t be surprised if this book influenced later movies such as War Games (1983), and books such as Neuromancer (1984).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Fiction &amp; Biographies</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/reads/non-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/reads/non-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Clifford Stoll: The Cuckoo’s Egg (1989) Don’t let the year of this book fool you - it’s probably the best book on computing security. The epilogue is both timeless, and an amazing reflection on the purpose of computer security. Moreover, this book is a very enjoyable read. Cliff, like most of us computer/scientist types, writes with a quirky sense of humour, and isn’t afraid to relay his personal views within the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Books</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/reads/gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/reads/gaming/</guid>
      <description>Martin Amis: Invasion of the Space Invaders (1982) This is probably the most sought-after video game book of the 1980s by the uber-famous, world-renowned author Martin Amis (most copies sell for over $200 today). Martin Amis has a unique way of bringing you back to the video game world of 1978-1982 using verbal imagery and humour - after all, he was a video game addict at the time! Some of the high-resolution colour photos in the book (including the one above) say more than words ever could.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>