<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:40:39 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The Galaga no fire cheat mystery&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Wednesday, October 31, 2012&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;In the classic arcade game &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Galaga (1981)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, there is a well-known cheat for those who are patient.&#xA0; If you destroy all of the enemies on Stage 1 except for the left two enemies (shown to the right), then dodge their fire for about 10-15 minutes, they stop firing at you.&#xA0; At this point, you can safely kill them and no enemies will fire at you for the remainder of the game (they can still crash into you to kill you though).&#xD;&#xD;What this means is that you can get some pretty sweet high scores on Galaga arcade machines if you are patient.&#xA0; Since Galaga was one of the most popular games of the 1980s, people definitely wanted to get the high scores on it ;-)&#xD;&#xD;The mystery about this cheat is that no-one knows if it was a bug or an actual cheat that someone from Namco added prior to releasing the arcade game.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Christopher Cantrell examined a ROM dump of the game back in 2005 and picked apart the code - you can read his analysis here: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://computerarcheology.com/galaga/galaga.html"&gt;http://computerarcheology.com/galaga/galaga.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xA0; What he found was that the cheat was caused by a subtle design flaw in the logic of the game that allows the two left (or right) bees to fill up and clog a shot buffer used by enemy Galaga.&#xA0; But, was this intentional or not?&#xA0; All cheats must be subtle to pass validation ;-)&#xD;&#xD;It is rumored on the Internet that a Namco programmer added the design flaw (or discovered the design flaw and kept it secret) to ensure that he could always get the high score when he visited an arcade.&#xA0; Others then discovered the cheat when they watched him play the game at an arcade.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Considering that this cheat is very obscure, it is unlikely something that was discovered by chance.&#xA0; Someone would have had to kill everything but the left two enemies, and then dodged fire for 10-15 minutes. You can&#x2019;t just move your ship to the right and leave it there for 10-15 minutes because enemy shots occasionally come from the right to kill you - so if someone discovered this by chance, they would have had to spend 10-15 minutes dodging two enemies that just happened to be the right two.&#xA0;It isn&#x2019;t likely that someone in the 1980s would have poured a ton of quarters in the machine to try weird things over and over again to find a loophole.&#xD;&#xD;Of course, without hard evidence, we just don&#x2019;t know.&#xA0; Chance happens after all, and Galaga was an extremely popular game.&#xA0; However, if the cheat was widely known shortly after the game&#x2019;s release, then it is very very likely that it was a planned cheat by someone at Namco.....&#xD;&#xD;I remember learning the Galaga cheat by reading something on a local computer Bulletin Board System (BBS) in the 1980s (can&#x2019;t remember when).&#xA0; And of course, the BBS has long been retired like all other BBSes.&#xA0; However, there may have been posts on USENET, which is archived by Goggle Groups.&#xA0; A quick search of Google&#x2019;s USENET archive will show some posts talking about the cheat as early as 1985 - here is one:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mikel Manitius&#xA0; &#xD;Oct 31 1985, 7:07 pm&#xD;&gt; OK, how do you get the Galaga aliens to stop shooting at you until wave 256? &#xD;&gt; --Evan Marcus &#xD;&#xD;Gosh, here we go: &#xD;On the first or second screenfull of aliens, kill all of them, except the &#xD;two blue ones in the first collumn, at the bottom of the screen, it is &#xD;like this, if I can remember: &#xD;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; . &#xD;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; . &#xD;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; Y X X X X X... &#xD;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; Y X X X X X... &#xD;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; B X X X X X... &#xD;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; B X X X X X... &#xD;The 'Y' are the yellow ones (or whatever colour they are) and the 'B' are the &#xD;blue ones. The trick is to have just the two blue ones circulate, and watch &#xD;their firing patterns. What you are looking for is a cycle when neither of &#xD;the two aliens fire any missles. On the third such cycle, you must shoot both &#xD;of them before they escape through the bottom of the screen. It may take as &#xD;long as ten minutes of avoiding missles before you get the third cycle. From &#xD;now on, they shouldn't fire at you. And it's a deadly sin to get killed! :-) &#xD;The challenging stages repeat after 7 (i beleive that's right, could be 8), &#xD;and when you make it to the 255th level, you should have in excess of 4*10^5 &#xD;points. Beware that if you do this on a two player game, it is very &#xD;unpredictable, the second player will be fired at, and sometimes the first &#xD;start being fired upon again. &#xD;One more thing, the two times I stuck around long enough to get to level 255 &#xD;(about three hours, that's $0.25 worth all right!), when I cleard it, the &#xD;game and hung itself. It had to be reset to be playable again, and you don't &#xD;get on the score charts. &#xD;-- &#xD;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; Mikel Manitius @ AT&amp;T-IS Altamonte Springs, FL &#xD;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; ...{ihnp4|akguc|attmail|indra!koura}!codas!mikel &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;There are a couple important things to note from the above post:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	1.	It is a response to someone who heard about the cheat and posted to USENET to see if anyone knew how to do it.&#xD;	2.	The answer from Mikel is worded as if he knew it a long time ago (&#x201C;it is like this, if I can remember&#x201D;).&#x2028;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Now, keep in mind that very few people could post to USENET at the time.&#xA0; To post on USENET, you needed a powerful commercial or University computer that could connect to the ARPANET or use UUCP or something else that you couldn&#x2019;t do on an early PC or Commodore 64 ;-)&#xA0; So, to see a post on USENET in 1985 about the Galaga cheat is pretty rare - chances are that the cheat was old news by then.&#xD;&#xD;Now, if you look at recent game forum posts, you&#x2019;ll see plenty of people bragging about knowing about the cheat.....but you never know if they are telling the truth or not half the time on modern game forums ;-)&#xD;&#xD;So.....now for the catalyst that sparked this post......&#xD;&#xD;These past few weeks, I&#x2019;ve been teaching a SQL class at the college to IT students.&#xA0; And trust me, everyone knows how much of a Galaga freak I am ;-)&#xA0;&#xA0; So, as I was talking with a student in another class during the Halloween assembly, I mentioned about how I still play a lot of Galaga on my two Galaga arcade machines in my basement, and the guy said &#x201C;Yeah - I remember that game - dual fighters!&#xA0; I played that game so much back then.&#x201D;&#xA0; He even remembered the famous Galaga no fire cheat.&#xA0; So, naturally, I asked him how he found out about it.&#xA0; He said his sister&#x2019;s boyfriend told him about it when he tagged along with them to see Tron at the theatre........&#xD;&#xD;Hmmmm.........Tron was in the movie theatres in July 1982.&#xA0; And although Galaga was released at the end of 1981, most arcades didn&#x2019;t get Galaga machines until 1982.....especially in Canada (we usually got stuff long after the US did ;-).&#xD;&#xD;I&#x2019;m starting to think that the famous Galaga cheat was known very shortly after its release.....which means that it is very likely something was intensionally added by a Namco developer.&#xA0;&#xA0; Now if only someone from Namco could shed some light on the origin of the cheat......wink wink nod nod ;-)&#xD;&#xD;You can find more about Galaga on my Galaga site: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://galaga.info/"&gt;http://galaga.info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE (May 2014):&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jon (I won&#x2019;t give you his last name) sent me an email after visiting &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://galaga.info/"&gt;http://galaga.info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - in it he sent me a link to an October 1983 special edition issue of Joystik Magazine that covers winning strategies for common arcade games of the time.&#xA0; In the TRICKS OF THE TRADE section near the end of the magazine, they cover the Galaga No Fire Cheat beautifully!&#xA0;&#xA0; So what does this mean?&#xA0; Well, considering that it takes at least a few months to composite the material for a special edition of a magazine, it&#x2019;s safe to assume that by Summer 1983, the Galaga No Fire Cheat was extremely well known in the arcade scene.&#xA0; And to be &#x201C;extremely&#x201D; well known at a time before the Internet, it was likely &#x201C;very&#x201D; well known the summer before.........when the student I was talking to at our Halloween assembly initially found out about it while tagging along to see the Tron movie.&#xA0;&#xA0; Following is a link to the October 1983 special issue of Joystik Magazine for you to peruse: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://arcarc.xmission.com/Magazines%20and%20Books/Joystik%20Magazines%20(10%20Issues)/Joystik_Vol2-SE_83_Oct_(replace_me).pdf"&gt;http://arcarc.xmission.com/Magazines%20and%20Books/Joystik%20Magazines%20(10%20Issues)/Joystik_Vol2-SE_83_Oct_(replace_me).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="31_The_Galaga_no_fire_cheat_mystery_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
