<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:57:28 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Life &amp; Death of RIM: Losing the Signal Review&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, May 29, 2015&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;This past week saw the release of a book that detailed the rise of the smartphone pioneer, Research in Motion (RIM), and it&#x2019;s decline into obscurity: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Losing the Signal: The Spectacular Rise and Fall of BlackBerry (Jacquie McNish &amp; Sean Silcoff)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.&#xD;&#xD;Like any corporate biography, it starts from the beginning by discussing the historical roots of mobile technology, followed by the background of RIM&#x2019;s two leaders (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mike Lazaridis&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jim Basillie&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;) and their uphill struggle in the 1990s to keep RIM alive.  It also details how the BlackBerry came to be and why it rose to prominence, as well as the factors and events that transformed RIM into a small shadow of its former self.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPOILER ALERT:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; The next two bulleted sections below detail some key things that caught my eye for those who just want the &#x201C;Coles Notes&#x201D; version of the book. &#xD;&#xD;The first half of the book details the rise of RIM:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Wireless communication dates back almost a century.  Galvin (later called Motorola) created police radios in the 1930s, followed by pagers in the 1970s and cell phones in the 1980s.  &#xD;	&#x2022;	Ericsson sold their Mobitex two-way data network technology to the Rogers communications company in Canada (who originally wanted to use it internally in their service trucks).  Mobitex was used in the first BlackBerry devices (called the RIM Inter@ctive Pager)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Mike Lazaridis is a University of Waterloo drop-out who founded a struggling RIM in the 1980s, and Jim Basillie is an aggressive &#x201C;corporate warrior&#x201D; Harvard grad who was given the chance to invest in RIM after being rejected by the parent company of Sutherland-Schultz. &#xD;	&#x2022;	RIM barely survived in the 1990s and was dealt many blows by other companies, such as U.S. Robotics (who wanted to crush smaller competitors).&#xD;	&#x2022;	RIM rose to prominence because they focused on mobile email (not paging). Unlike Palm, Nokia and Microsoft, Lazaridis didn&#x2019;t think that combining computing, phone and Internet in the late 1990s was a good long-term approach (it sucked batteries dry, required too much bandwidth and was awkward with the screen technology of the time).  Instead, he pushed a &#x201C;less not more&#x201D; approach, which worked well for getting people hooked to mobile email as well as appease carriers that didn&#x2019;t want to relay tons of data.  It also kept the relatively-unused Mobitex network alive in North America.&#xD;	&#x2022;	RIM downplayed their success to placate upcoming competitors, and released Blackberry Connect as a trojan horse to slow down competitors from making competing software and devices.  &#xD;	&#x2022;	By the mid 2000s, they were a massive success in every way.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;The second half of the book details the fall of RIM:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	RIM totally botched the NTP patent troll lawsuit and had to pay more than $600 million in damages - this took a massive toll on both Lazaridis and Basillie. The stock option scandal that Lazaridis and Basillie had to pay for didn&#x2019;t help either.&#xD;	&#x2022;	When Apple released the iPhone (a Mac in a phone), it rewrote the rules of the market. Suddenly, it was all about portable computing and apps - battery life and data compression didn&#x2019;t matter anymore.  Consumers now drove the market. RIM didn&#x2019;t &#x201C;get&#x201D; this until it was far far too late.  Lazaridis was preaching that consumers cared about security, reliability and multitasking, when Steve Jobs was preaching style, content and ease of use.&#xD;	&#x2022;	After the iPhone, RIM came out with a whole line of shitty products, such as the BlackBerry Storm (which didn&#x2019;t work) and the BlackBerry PlayBook (which had few apps and NO native email).  Apps were difficult to develop for the aging JAVA-based BlackBerry OS.  Although they finally released a decent Web browser (made by Torch), it didn&#x2019;t run well on the BlackBerry OS and slow hardware (which was designed for battery life, not power). They bought QNX in hopes that the QNX OS would save their aging BlackBerry OS. &#xD;	&#x2022;	When Android took the market by story (around the time of the Motorola Droid), it opened up hundreds of new competitors for RIM.  The network fees that RIM charged carriers was under big threat because competing phones didn&#x2019;t have them (and these network fees counted for most of RIMs profit due to their large profit margin).&#xD;	&#x2022;	RIM was very very late in bringing a 4G phone to market (which pissed of carriers).&#xD;	&#x2022;	They had massive internal leadership woes - mismanagement was rampant, and nobody would take accountability for anything. People would say things like &#x201C;this is normal for a company growing as fast as we are.&#x201D;  RIM was at war with itself.&#xD;	&#x2022;	RIM kept coming out with marketing campaigns that were out-of-touch with the market, and led people to think that RIM had no clear corporate direction.&#xD;	&#x2022;	RIM focused on selling phones to developing countries to stay afloat as their competitors were killing them in the North American market.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Competitors to BBM showed up relatively fast. Although making BBM cross-platform was discussed early on, it was shelved until it was too late.&#xD;	&#x2022;	RIM had no diverse portfolio to rely on - unlike Google and Apple, RIM was only a smartphone maker.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Bad interviews, tarnishing events (such as the two drunk RIM execs who ended up grounding a flight), as well as the big service outage in 2011 smeared their public image. &#xD;	&#x2022;	Today, RIM (now called BlackBerry) is a niche company that has returned to pushing their physical keyboard (the new BlackBerry Passport is keyboard-based), but with a focus on software for the future.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;On a personal note, I have closer ties to RIM than most who will read this book. I live 15 min from the RIM headquarters, have many friends who have or still work there, and even authored their first academic textbooks (my college was RIM&#x2019;s first academic partner). &#xD;&#xD;My first &#x201C;real&#x201D; BlackBerry was the iconic 7250 (shown right), and I loved it.  I&#x2019;ve also had a BlackBerry Curve, World Edition, and Bold 2.  By the time I had a Bold 2, BlackBerry was becoming seriously antiquated in the tech market, and I longed for an iPhone or Android phone.  Today, I&#x2019;m and Android user.&#xD;&#xD;While I loved their technology, I hated the company.  I got first hand exposure to RIM bureaucracy during our academic relationship - there were some people we dealt with at RIM that we not-so-affectionately called &#x201C;RIMtards&#x201D; for incredibly good reasons.  I remember telling my boss that their bureaucratic culture would ultimately kill them in the tech market when Apple and Google decide to heat up the competition.  Years later, he mentioned something along the lines of &#x201C;You totally called that one.&#x201D;&#xD;&#xD;In short, times change - the backend server infrastructure that ultimately allowed RIM to create fast compressed/encrypted email and messaging services in the early/mid 2000s became a white elephant on their back by the late 2000s.....and ultimately led to the big service disruption in 2011 that was the nail in the coffin for so many IT managers.  By the late 2000s, Android and iPhone smartphones were app-running computers that connected to the fast mobile Internet of the time to access the Internet like any home PC.  The definition of mobile computing changed - it grew up - and RIM was left in the dust because they were too bureaucratic to innovate, and didn&#x2019;t think they could be toppled in the first place.&#xD;&#xD;It&#x2019;s a problem that has traditionally plagued Canadian tech companies - they don&#x2019;t &#x201C;get&#x201D; that after you reach a certain size, that you have to constantly reinvent yourself to match the tech market and remain viable.  There isn&#x2019;t a lot of Silicon Valley in the founders of RIM or the corporate culture that they created.&#xD;&#xD;On a closing note, there is one interesting thing that I was reminded of while reading this book - during RIMs decline, the entire region where I live (Kitchener-Waterloo, Ontario) was populated with a disproportionately large number of RIM supporters/advocates/apologizers.  &#xD;&#xD;It felt like a fucking cult.  If you said something bad about the company, there would be a dozen people down your throat with pissed off expressions (example shown right) telling you how BlackBerry is better than iOS/Android or how you should be supporting Canadian technology. Thankfully, those idiots are few and far between today ;-)&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="29_Life_%26_Death_of_RIM__Losing_the_Signal_Review_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
