<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:58:23 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;20 Years of Google Running the IT World&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Thursday, September 27, 2018&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;It was 20 years ago today that Google released their search engine to the world.  &#xD;&#xD;I was first introduced to Google - probably shortly after that time - by a colleague of mine (Shawn Simpson) who was excited about how fast it returned results that were more accurate than our beloved AltaVista (the search engine that everyone I worked with used exclusively up until that time). I still remember my first impressions of it too! I initially thought that its simple interface was basic and amateurish, but it was definitely fast, and it returned better results than AltaVista. So it replaced AltaVista almost immediately for me, and the rest is history.&#xD;&#xD;In the 1990s, the World Wide Web was taking off like a rocket, and us IT folk were mining the data available like hungry wolves. What file did I need to modify to make a certain feature work in Red Hat? What was that registry key for the login screen legal message in WinNT? What driver did I need for this crappy Soyo motherboard chipset in Win98SE? Screw books....do an online search.&#xD;&#xD;The funny thing is that this data mining never went away - it became a fundamental part of IT that propelled us into the future and allowed us to learn and implement technologies faster than ever! By 2000, you could tell the old-school IT people (often called system operators, or sysops) from the new-school IT professionals simply by their Googling ability. Sadly, some sysops were stuck in the past and needed to read a book or sit a course to learn a new technology - they got left in past while new IT professionals relied on a dangerous combination of knowledge and research to solve problems.&#xD;&#xD;In many ways, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;IT grew up around Google these past 20 years&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;. And that&#x2019;s a good thing, because IT today is perhaps the most dynamic, rewarding, and enjoyable profession that you could pursue - you are always learning, and learning to learn. &#xD;And Google is where you start.&#xD;Happy 20th Google!&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="27_Entry_1_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
