<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024 in Review</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2024-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2024-in-review/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s important to pause and reflect every so often to stay grounded and focused. So, each December I look back on the year&amp;rsquo;s events and summarize them in a blog post. And after doing this again this year, I realize that 2024 was one of reflection, gratitude, and exploration.
I was fortunate enough to go on some epic winter hiking adventures with my dog Pepper in January before she passed away in February at the age of 13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running an LLM locally using Ollama</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/llms-using-ollama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/llms-using-ollama/</guid>
      <description>If you are developing or integrating software with a Large Language Model (LLM) to add chatbot or other AI functionality, then you may have the need to host and run an LLM on your local workstation for development or testing. There are several open source LLMs available that you can freely run on your system provided that you have enough resources to do so.
LLMs are just inert objects that require special software to allow people and other software to interact with it (called running the model).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing a Fedora Linux ARM VM from a Raw Image</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-arm-raw-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-arm-raw-image/</guid>
      <description>Many professionals who work in Information Technology (IT) or software development use an ARM-based PC, such as an Apple Silicon Mac, Snapdragon Elite X Windows Copilot+ PC, or an ARM Linux workstation such as the System76 Thelio Astra. Similarly, many students learning IT or software development may also use an ARM-based PC. For all of these people, it&amp;rsquo;s commonplace to deploy Linux virtual machines (VMs) on a PC using hypervisor software to test cloud apps, host server software, or run specialized tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copilot&#43; PC Review: Windows on ARM is finally here</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/windows-on-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/windows-on-arm/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2017, I wrote a blog post predicting intense competition between Intel x86-based and ARM-based PCs. And finally, after many years of lukewarm development efforts on the part of Microsoft and Qualcomm, that competition is here with Windows 11 Copilot+ PCs running powerful ARM-based Qualcomm Snapdragon X Elite CPUs with built in graphics and AI acceleration.
As shown in the desktop screenshot at the top of this post I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a Copilot+ PC as a productivity and development workstation this month, and I must say that I&amp;rsquo;m thoroughly impressed overall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending the life of an Intel-based Mac using Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/intel-mac-win11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/intel-mac-win11/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2020, Apple introduced the first Macs that used Apple Silicon processors instead of Intel ones, and this transition from Intel to Apple Silicon was completed earlier this year across Apple&amp;rsquo;s entire product line. While Apple promised they&amp;rsquo;d continue supporting macOS on Intel-based Macs for the near future, those of us who remember Apple&amp;rsquo;s previous transitions from M68k-to-PowerPC and PowerPC-to-Intel know full well that this support is going to end sooner than later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential keyboard shortcuts (Windows/macOS/Linux/UNIX)</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Following are some shortcuts that I believe all desktop users should be familiar with. It is not a complete list by any means, and does not include virtual desktop or app pinning shortcuts as I felt those were beyond the scope of common desktop shortcuts. If you feel I omitted a common shortcut, email me (jason.eckert@trios.com) and I&amp;rsquo;ll add it to the list!
1. Windows shortcuts The Windows (⊞) key on your keyboard has the Windows logo printed on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first textbook is now in its sixth edition</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-sixth-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-sixth-edition/</guid>
      <description>While I&amp;rsquo;ve written many textbooks on different topics over the past two decades, my favourite subject area by far is Linux. After all, Linux has evolved to be one of the most foundational topics in tech education. Information Technology (IT) fields such as server/network administration, cloud administration, cybersecurity, and software development now require a solid grasp of the Linux operating system. The first textbook I wrote (Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification) was in 2001 for Course Technology (now Cengage).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of RISC architecture</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/power-of-risc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/power-of-risc/</guid>
      <description>This part of the 1995 Hackers movie shown above is right on par for the time. After all, by the mid 1990s Reduced Instruction Set Computer (RISC) processors were seen as the future of computing by most in the tech industry.
By using a simplified instruction set, computers with RISC processors at the time could perform tasks in a quarter of the time compared to computers that had a traditional Complex Instruction Set Computer (CISC) processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to WireGuard VPN</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/an-introduction-to-wireguard-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/an-introduction-to-wireguard-vpn/</guid>
      <description>1. Why WireGuard? When it comes to encrypting traffic between systems, there are a wide variety of different Virtual Private Network (VPN) software available, some of which have been used since the 1990s. Each of them focus on different encryption algorithms and flow control strategies, alongside mechanisms for providing for secure authentication and negotiating encryption keys. Unfortunately, this complexity often translates to more problems, slower traffic, as well fewer use cases and supported operating systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 in review</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2020-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2020-in-review/</guid>
      <description>I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking - 2020 sucked! Worst year ever! The COVID-19 pandemic, no social gatherings, no dine-in restaurants, no gyms, the US Trumpster fire, and most importantly to those of us in the tech world: Red Hat terminating CentOS development.
Of course, most people will remember 2020 for the pandemic, and that&amp;rsquo;s completely understandable. None of us have experienced a pandemic in our lifetime, and both our society and economy were not prepared to deal with it gracefully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of technology</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>Technology is a crazy ride, and like that lyric in the Talking Heads song Once in a Lifetime, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;you may ask yourself, well, how did I get here?&amp;rdquo;
If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck, because this post is a no-nonsense, give-me-the-big-picture timeline of what the heck happened in the technology landscape these past 50 years. Of course, not every little detail is in there. Just those that are actually important (in my expert opinion, of course ;-) Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most people don&#39;t want a computer</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</guid>
      <description>In the past few decades, people of all ages across North America have become technology-literate in some way or another. Many of them weren&amp;rsquo;t introduced to technology via desktop or laptop computers, but instead through a smartphone or tablet. Similarly, many desktop and laptop users have switched to using their smartphone or tablet over the past decade to interact with the online world.
After all, smartphones and tablets are incredibly easy to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft turns 45</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-turns-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-turns-45/</guid>
      <description>On April 4th 1975, a small company called Microsoft was founded in Albuquerque, New Mexico. They would later become the most pivotal company in the technology world, and their co-founder Bill Gates would become the world’s most prolific philanthropist.
Like many tech companies, Microsoft has had a colourful past. Started by two whiz kids (Paul Allen and Bill Gates), they started by selling operating system and supporting software.
Xenix UNIX (later sold to SCO) was their first operating system product in 1980, followed closely by MS-DOS in 1981 (which they originally purchased from Tim Paterson).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Windows Subsystem for Linux</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/using-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/using-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>1. So what is WSL? Simply put, it’s a kernel interface (lxcore &amp;amp; lxss) that allows 64-bit Linux binaries to run on a Window 10 or Windows Server 2019 kernel.
All you need to do is add the userland (file system structure and programs) from an existing Linux distribution, such as Ubuntu, Kali, Debian or SUSE, and that Linux distribution will run natively on the Windows kernel!
You must access the Linux distribution via a Windows program that associates the userland of the Linux distribution to the WSL (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The history of IT certification</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/history-of-it-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/history-of-it-certification/</guid>
      <description>Nearly everyone working in an Information Technology (IT) field has at least one IT-related certification. This is because IT certification is commonly used as a skills benchmark for hiring and promotion, and it’s been that way for a long, long time.
So where did all this certification stuff start? If you look online, there isn’t even a Wikipedia page that can give you that answer - like many things in the technology world that predated the Internet, it just wasn’t important enough to keep track of in the Internet Age that started in the 1990s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows and macOS could move to Linux</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/windows-and-macos-could-move-to-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/windows-and-macos-could-move-to-linux/</guid>
      <description>For those in the tech world, the title of this post may seem both radical and pretentious.
However, in the following four parts of this blog post, I hope to shed light on why this is a real possibility in the not-so-distant future and why.
PART 1: OS overview First of all, an operating system (OS) is essentially the core software that allows your computer to run - it provides a core component (called a kernel) that understands how to use the hardware in your computer, a user interface (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Essentials for SysAdmins</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/powershell-essentials-for-sysadmins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/powershell-essentials-for-sysadmins/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell is essentially a scripting language and shell (command prompt) that you can use on Windows systems. It’s basically Microsoft’s way of getting a powerful UNIX/Linux/Mac-like shell on the Windows platform (long overdue!). The first versions of PowerShell were pretty horrific, but it’s come a long way since then. PowerShell v4 and later is pretty decent (Win10 comes with PowerShell v5). Luckily, PowerShell v4 comes with Windows Server 2012, and since this post is geared towards sysadmins, I’ll focus everything on Windows Server 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft ReFS vs Oracle ZFS - FIGHT!</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/refs-vs-zfs-fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/refs-vs-zfs-fight/</guid>
      <description>In the past, most IT admins have put their faith in systems and SANs (Storage Area Networks) that use RAID (Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks) technology. RAID can be used to combine hard disks together into simple volumes (called RAID-0, or JBOD) that aren’t fault tolerant, but can also be used to create mirrored volumes where both drives are identical in case one fails (called RAID-1), or striped volumes with parity where data is written across several disks with parity information that can be used to calculate the missing data if a drive fails (called RAID-5).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rise and fall of DEC</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-rise-and-fall-of-dec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-rise-and-fall-of-dec/</guid>
      <description>Firstly, the information that I’m presenting here is taken from various sources, including people I knew who worked for DEC, my own experiences, and the book DEC Is Dead, Long Live DEC by Edgar H. Schein.
Quick background info: DEC was the first knowledge-based company - a company who valued the knowledge of its employees over anything else, and used it to drive change and sell products.
The founder and father icon of DEC, Ken Olsen, spent time working at IBM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All about DEC</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/all-about-dec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/all-about-dec/</guid>
      <description>Digital Equipment Corporation (DEC) was born in the late 1950s when it was lucrative to make computers that cost a ton of money. And DEC was good - they would make computers that would perform much better and cost significantly less than the IBM equivalent (IBM mainframes back then were expensive behemoths).
The DEC PDP (Programmed Data Processor) line of minicomputers were so good and inexpensive, you’d be hard pressed to NOT find one in your local university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you a Mac or a PC?</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/are-you-a-mac-or-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/are-you-a-mac-or-pc/</guid>
      <description>If you are ultra-Mac, you prefer to use an aesthetic computer that “just works” - as a result, you are usually sexy, artistic and cool.
If you are ultra-PC, you prefer to use a clunky un-aesthetic computer that is difficult to use, crashes often, is a virus hell, yet is guaranteed to work with any piece of hardware with a software driver written by a 10-year-old boy in a barn in China - as a result, you are nerdy, cheap and non-cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Operating Systems</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/operatingsystems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/operatingsystems/</guid>
      <description>UNIX UNIX is the grandfather of all modern operating systems, and today it still remains the most powerful and least known. But if you use an Apple computer running macOS, or an iPhone or iPad running iOS, you are using a UNIX operating system. And if you do online banking, somewhere tucked away in the bank is likely a series of UNIX systems running Oracle Solaris UNIX, HP-UX UNIX, or AIX UNIX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. My published books</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/my-published-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/my-published-books/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps one of my more famous achievements is the authoring of several textbooks for Course Technology, Cengage, Nelson, Thompson/Delmar and Wiley. I&amp;rsquo;ve listed their details in chronological order here (oldest to newest) with cover pictures below:
Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification (ISBN: 0-619-13004-0) front rear Guide to UNIX System Administration (ISBN: 0-619-13041-5) front rear Linux+ In Depth (ISBN: 1-59200-062-2) front rear MCSE Guide to Managing a Microsoft Windows Server 2003 Network (ISBN: 0-619-12029-0) front rear dedication Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification - 2nd Edition (ISBN: 0-619-21621-2) front rear Linux+ 2005 In Depth (ISBN: 1-59200-728-7) front rear Novell&amp;rsquo;s Guide to CompTIA&amp;rsquo;s Linux+ (Course 3060) (ISBN: 1-4188-3730-X) front rear SUSE Linux Enterprise Server Administration (Course 3037) (ISBN: 1-4188-3731-8) front rear Advanced SUSE Linux Enterprise Server Administration (Course 3038) (ISBN: 1-4188-3732-6) front rear Microsoft Windows Vista Guide (ISBN: 1-4188-3757-1) front rear dedication SUSE Linux Enterprise Desktop Administration (Course 3086) (ISBN: 1-4283-2227-2) front rear SUSE Linux Enterprise Server Security (Course 3075) (ISBN: 1-4283-2223-X) front rear Microsoft Official Academic Course (MOAC): Exchange Server 2007 Exam 70-236 (ISBN: 978-0-470-38029-1) front rear Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification - 3rd Edition (ISBN: 978-1-418-83721-1) front rear SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 11 Administration (ISBN: 978-1-111-54003-6) front rear Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification - International Edition (ISBN: 978-1-111-54153-8) Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification - 4th Edition (ISBN: 978-1-305-10716-8) front Linux+ and LPIC-1 Guide to Linux Certification - 5th Edition (ISBN: 978-1-337-56979-8) front Hands-On Windows Server 2019 - 3rd Edition (ISBN: 978-0-357-43615-8) front dedication Linux+ and LPIC-1 Guide to Linux Certification - 6th Edition (ISBN: 979-8-214-00080-0) front dedication Hands-On Windows Server 2022 - 4th Edition (ISBN: 979-8-214-01160-8) Available Dec 2024!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
