<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recommended Trails on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/categories/recommended-trails/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recommended Trails on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jasoneckert.github.io/categories/recommended-trails/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>City Trails</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/trails/city/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/trails/city/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;millrun.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hydro falls along Mill Run trail&#34; title=&#34;Hydro falls along Mill Run trail&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;rare-charitable-research-reserve-cambridge&#34;&gt;rare Charitable Research Reserve (Cambridge)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rare Charitable Research Reserve is a community-based urban land trust. They maintain a series of amazing trails within the Blair/Galt area of Cambridge along the south side of the Grand River. The trails along the river are part of a gorgeous escarpment that contains exposed rock and fossils from the Silurian period. There are also trails across alvars and open fields with two Osprey towers. Further south, you&amp;rsquo;ll find the beautiful Maple Lane and Grand Allee Trails that contain massive hardwoods and plenty of deer. They comprised the first planned road in the region and the surrounding forest was home to the first settler (Dan Dodge).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Destination Trails</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/trails/destination/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/trails/destination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kelso.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Top of Niagara Escarpment at Kelso&#34; title=&#34;Top of Niagara Escarpment at Kelso&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;rockwood-conservation-area&#34;&gt;Rockwood Conservation Area&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rockwood has breathtaking scenery - pine and cedar forests surrounding rock cliffs and islands along the Eramosa River. And the trails allow you to see it all. The Cedar Ridge Outlook allows you to see all of Rockwood below. The plateau at the top of the caves is actually owned by the University of Waterloo, but you can hike up there and along the numerous trails to see the remnants of an old house and quarry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trails in and around Algonquin Provincial Park</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/trails/algonquin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/trails/algonquin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;algonquin.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mac on Mizzy Lake Trail&#34; title=&#34;Mac on Mizzy Lake Trail&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;mizzy-lake-trail&#34;&gt;Mizzy Lake Trail&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the trail where you can see the most wildlife in Algonquin park. You&amp;rsquo;ll wind through 11km of lakes, marshes and forests. My daughter and I saw massive turtles, were followed by otters who mocked us, and even stood 2 feet away from a moose who crossed our path when she realized her foal was on the other side. The pic at the top of this page is of my daughter resting shortly after we found the remains of a grey jay (now officially called a Canada jay) that was likely eaten by a pine marten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
