<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:42:27 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Revisiting Vintage Arcade Tokens &lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, May 4, 2018&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;A while ago I managed to buy a bag of arcade tokens from someone at a collectibles show for $10.  After cleaning them up as much as I could, I added them to plastic coin sleeves and spent the next several weeks doing some detective work to find out where most of them came from!  It was a lot of fun, and gave me a great appreciation for some of the video arcades and other locations that hosted video arcade machines across North America.&#xD;&#xD;When arcade machines became popular in the late 1970s, tokens followed suit.  You would buy tokens from an arcade operator or token-dispensing machine, and then use the tokens to insert credits into the game of your choice.  They were better than using quarters for both the arcade owner and the player.  Tokens cut down on theft (people would often break into unwatched arcade machines to steal quarters), and most places gave you 5 tokens for $1, which meant that you had an extra game for free compared to using quarters!&#xD;&#xD;The coolest thing about tokens is that there were hundreds, if not thousands, of different kinds that identified the arcade venue you went to.  Moreover, arcade tokens had different characteristics for different types of arcade venues.  In this blog post, I&#x2019;ll talk about the different features that arcade tokens had for dedicated video arcades, family fun centers, fun parks, and so on.&#xD;&#xD;While dedicated video arcades are mostly a thing of the past, they have a lot of nostalgia value for those people who remember them.  The largest video arcade chain that I remember was Aladdin&#x2019;s Castle (every mall had one), and they also had the coolest looking tokens at the time because they weren&#x2019;t round - one side had a picture of Aladdin himself, and the other side had a picture of his castle:&#xD;&#xD; &#xD;&#xD;In contrast, most other arcade tokens are perfectly round and list the name of the venue on one side, and &#x201C;No Cash Value&#x201D; on the other side.  Here is a list of the dedicated video arcades that I have tokens for:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Aladdin&#x2019;s Castle (large mall chain)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Tilt Family Amusement Center (large mall chain)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Galaxy Game Center (Palatine, IL)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Diamond Square Fun Land (Rosemead, CA)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Red Balloon Arcade (unknown location)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Daytona USA (arcade in Daytona Beach, FL)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Games People Play (Mabelvale, AR)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Jenkinson's South Family Arcades (Pleasant Beach, NJ)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Stevie D&#x2019;s Park Arcade (NJ)&#xD;	&#x2022;	South Beach Family Arcade (Point Pleasant Beach, NJ)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Arcade Only (generic arcade token)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Coin Castle (Seaside Heights, NJ)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Millennium Entertainment (Austin, TX)&#xD;	&#x2022;	GameZone / SG Technical Amusement (Puerto Rico &#x2013; still operating!)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Family fun centers and fun parks were just as popular back in the 1980s when dedicated video arcades were everywhere - however, they didn&#x2019;t rely on making their money from just the games - they often made most of their money from food and other events.  As a result, many of these locations are still operating today, including the well-known Chuck E. Cheese.  However, the majority of games you&#x2019;ll find in these locations are redemption (ticket) games. Nearly all of these locations had a mascot (for brand recognition), and their arcade tokens often had their mascot on the token itself - for example, the Chuck E. Cheese rat, and Caesar from Caesarland (Little Caesar&#x2019;s short-lived competitor to Chuck E. Cheese):&#xD;&#xD; &#xD;&#xD;Some family fun centers and fun park chains currently operating today that I have tokens for include:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Chuck E. Cheese&#xD;	&#x2022;	Celebration Station&#xD;	&#x2022;	Peter Piper Pizza&#xD;	&#x2022;	Dave &amp; Busters&#xD;	&#x2022;	Mr. Gatti&#x2019;s (now just Gatti&#x2019;s)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Boondocks Fun Center&#xD;	&#x2022;	Main Event Entertainment&#xD;	&#x2022;	Fun Factory (&#x201C;#1 For Fun&#x201D;)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Malibu Grand Prix / Malibu Raceway&#xD;	&#x2022;	Boomers!&#xD;	&#x2022;	Brunswick Recreation Centers / Brunswick Zone (Bowling chain in US &amp; Canada)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Chapparal Ice (Ice rink chain in TX with arcade games)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Amazing Jakes Pizza Factory&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Defunct family fun centers and fun park chains that I have tokens for include:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Bopper&#x2019;s Caf&#xE9; (Windsor &#x2013; similar to Dave &amp; Busters, but didn&#x2019;t last long)&#xD;	&#x2022;	The Jungle Fun &amp; Adventure (San Hose, CA)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Sports &#x2018;N&#x2019; Games Family Entertainment Center (East Hanover, NJ)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Caesarland (Little Caesar&#x2019;s arcade chain) &#xD;	&#x2022;	Grand Prix Race-O-Rama (Fort Lauderdale, FL)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Discovery Zone (chain similar to Chuck E Cheese)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Chesnut Square Family Entertainment (Bastrop, TX)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Happy Days Skate &amp; Putt (Davie, FL)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Sports Pizza and Subs (Cleveland, TN)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Romp Around (Green Brook, NJ)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Bostonville Grille All Star Arcade (MA)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Ellwest-Jolar Amusement Centers (San Diego, CA)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;In the 1980s, arcade machines could be found outside dedicated arcades, family fun centers and fun parks - you could find an arcade or two at your local convenience store, pizza parlour, movie theatre, grocery store or bar.  These were called &#x201C;street locations&#x201D; by arcade operators back in the 1980s, who often leased the machines to each location and/or split the revenue from them.  Street locations are still common today! Anywhere that provides entertainment often has an arcade machine or two, sometimes more - just check out your local movie theatre, like Cineplex, and you&#x2019;ll find arcades and a token machine to buy tokens for them!  If the street location is big enough (e.g. a movie theatre chain like Cineplex), then you&#x2019;ll find custom tokens with branding.  However, for smaller locations, they&#x2019;ll often use tokens with a generic picture on them, such as the Statue of Liberty, a clown, or simply the word &#x201C;Token&#x201D;, as shown below:&#xD;&#xD; &#xD;&#xD;  &#xD;&#xD;Below are some street location tokens in my collection from the past and present that have their own brand/logo:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Starburst Coin Machines (put in any street location run by Starburst)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Twin Creeks Sports Complex (Sunnyvale, CA)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Frankie&#x2019;s Fun Park (FL)&#xD;	&#x2022;	The Plex (Wichita Falls, TX)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Funstation USA (Lynbrook, NY)&#xD;	&#x2022;	BlackBeard&#x2019;s Cave (Bayville, NJ)&#xD;	&#x2022;	FlipSide Entertainment Center (Gilbert, AZ)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Red &amp; Jerry&#x2019;s Entertainment (Sheridan, CO)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Race Factory Gaming (Honalulu, HI)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Rockfish Seafood Grille (TX)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Ellen&#x2019;s Fairway Amusement Center (Cedar Hill, TX)&#xD;	&#x2022;	The Pier (Cocoa Beach, FL)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Phoenix Zoo / Phx Zoo (Phoenix, AZ)&#xD;	&#x2022;	iJump 280 (Birmingham, AL)&#xD;	&#x2022;	OMNI Family Amusement Center (Fayetteville, NC)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Zuma Fun Center (Houton, TX)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Mountasia Fantasy Golf &amp; Games (Fayetteville, NC)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Gee-Gee's Arcade and Pizza (Manasquan, NJ)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Margaritaville Sports Bar &amp; Grill (Biloxi, MS)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Colasanti&#x2019;s Tropical Garden (Kingsville, ON)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Rebounderz Indoor Trampoline Arena (Jenison, MI)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Dave&#x2019;s Need 4 Speed (Lubbock, TX)&#xD;	&#x2022;	All Star Sports Entertainment (Wichita, KS)&#xD;	&#x2022;	PrimeTime Playhouses Inc. (Rockaway, NJ)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Funtime America (Eatontown, NJ)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Kids &#x2018;N&#x2019; Action (Brooklyn, NY)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Tech Town (Famous Players movie theatre arcade token)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Cineplex Odeon / Famous Players / Galaxy movie theatre arcade token&#xD;	&#x2022;	ET Zone (Empire Theatres arcade token)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Nascar Speedpark (Sevierville, TN)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Border Town Food &amp; Fun Center (San Antonio, TX)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Fuddrucker&#x2019;s (burger chain with arcades)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Fun Plex (Littleton, CO)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Fire Lake Family Resort Bowling Center (Shawnee, OK)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Cabela&#x2019;s (Outfitter chain with arcade games)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Caesar&#x2019;s Pocono Resort (several locations with gaming arcade)&#xD;	&#x2022;	The Mint Hotel (Las Vegas, NV)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Empress Casino (Hammond, IN)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Isle of Capri (Casino chain in US)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Lady Luck Casinos (casino chain with an arcade)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Belterra Resort &amp; Casino (Florence, IN)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Crabtree Amusements (carnival chain with gaming arcade)&#xD;	&#x2022;	S&amp;S Amusements (carnival chain with gaming arcade)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Ruffler and Deith (an arcade distributor in England &#x2013; 10p tokens)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Family Entertainment Group / FEG (company that sets up arcades in other locations)&#xD;	&#x2022;	ELAUT Amusement Games (company that makes/sells coin-op arcade games)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Intermark Gaming Inc. (company that sold arcade games since 1983)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Rooofus The Roller Roo (Roller Skating Association token they sell to roller rinks that have arcades that take tokens)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Wednesday Company (generic arcade token)&#xD;	&#x2022;	X-Mark IDX Token (a token you could order unique to your establishment)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Puritan (branded arcade token)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Universal token&#xD;	&#x2022;	Six Flags Great Adventure (Jackson, NJ)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Now there are two special arcade tokens in my collection that I didn&#x2019;t get from the $10 bag I bought at the collectibles show.  Instead, I bought these two online and placed them in their own display boxes because they have special meaning:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	A Twin Galaxies token (Walter Day&#x2019;s arcade that became one of the most recognized arcade names because he started an arcade scoreboard from it)&#xD;	&#x2022;	A Flynn&#x2019;s Arcade token from Disneyland (which hosted the famous Flynn&#x2019;s Arcade from the movie TRON for many years)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="4_Revisiting_Vintage_Arcade_Tokens_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
