<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:32:55 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The Apple brand from the 70s to $1 trillion&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, August 5, 2018&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;So the big news this past week was that Apple became the first company to be valued at more than $1 trillion dollars (US). Is that a good thing or a bad thing? I wouldn&#x2019;t say it is either....it is what it is. And in this blog post, we&#x2019;ll examine how that happened from a technologist point-of-view.&#xD;&#xD;Apple&#x2019;s first product was the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Apple II&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; computer in 1977. The Apple II was one of the first personal computer (PC) products on the market and had massive success during the late 1970s and entire 1980s. It was priced well above other PCs with similar specs at the time because Apple thought that &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;people would be willing to pay more for a better-made computer if it was marketed aggressively&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;. Apple definitely spent a fortune on marketing, and the Apple II was definitely a well-made machine....perhaps the best build quality of any PC of the 70s and 80s, both inside and out. For example, my Apple IIc shown in this video (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rVB8mJv6Qt4"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rVB8mJv6Qt4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;) has such a sturdy build and component quality that it still works flawlessly today (I can&#x2019;t say the same for a Tandy or Commodore computer from that era though).&#xD;&#xD;The &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Macintosh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; computer introduced in 1984 was revolutionary for the time because it had a modern graphical user interface and mouse. In fact, if you used the original Macintosh operating system (OS) from 1984 today, the first thing that would strike you is the similarity to modern OSes. While the Macintosh had significantly more expensive hardware than an Apple II, Apple applied the same pricing strategy to it, which made it very expensive at the time compared to nearly all other computers on the market. Consequently, the sales of early Macintosh computers were not great, and it took almost half a decade before Macintosh sales outpaced Apple II sales.  But by 1990, the Macintosh had &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;carved out a name in the market for being the&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt; desktop publishing computer&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.&#xD;&#xD;Massive sales of the Apple II throughout the 1980s, and the growing sales of the Macintosh made Apple a large company by the end of the 1980s, bringing in over &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;$1 billion in yearly sales&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; during much of the 1980s.  &#xD;&#xD;But the 1990s was not a good decade for Apple. The IBM PC entered the market in 1981 and was cloned by dozens of manufacturers.  By 1990 it was clear that the IBM PC was the standard in the personal computing market by a long shot. Apple was a distant second. Anything that was IBM-compatible was called a &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;PC&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; and anything Apple was just called a &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mac&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;. Apple was a big company advertising overpriced Macs and getting hammered by the PC competition, especially since the Macintosh OS was getting antiquated, fast. Not many people I knew bought anything but PCs in the 1990s, even for desktop publishing.  Macs were still common in the schools, but we called them &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;beige toasters&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; at the time because they were beige and about as powerful as a toaster.  My university had a lab full of Power Macintosh 6100s, which came with a PowerPC processor to run the Macintosh OS as well as an Intel 486 CPU to run Windows 3.11 - it was as if Apple was saying &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Yes, we know our OS sucks, so we&#x2019;ll sell you an overpriced machine that can also run Windows 3.11 to make it useful....just buy it please!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; Not Apple&#x2019;s finest moment.&#xD;&#xD;By 1996, Apple was on the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;verge of bankruptcy&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;. Luckily for them, one of their original founders (Steve Jobs) returned to Apple that year and sold them his innovative (yet unprofitable) computer company called NeXT. The good part about this was that the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;NeXTSTEP UNIX operating system&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; was revolutionary at the time, and very easy to develop software for.&#xD;&#xD;By 1998, Apple was making profit again by selling their new all-in-one &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;iMac&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; computer. The iMac was aggressively marketed, but not priced well above other offerings at the time. It was a bit more expensive to get an iMac, but the all-in-one form factor made it easy to justify for people who were new to computing and wanted to get on the Internet easily (which was a big market in the late 1990s).&#xD;&#xD;In 2001, Apple released their new &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; operating system, which was basically NeXTSTEP UNIX with a fresh coat of paint on top. It was elegant, easy-to-use, and eventually drew interest from software developers who made sure that key applications were available for it.  But more importantly, 2001 was when Apple released the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;iPod&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; digital music player that became hottest technology in the world for many years and made Apple a household name.  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The iPod put Apple back into the game, big time&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;! Mac sales increased as a result, and people started to view Mac OS X as a much easier and secure (virus free) alternative to Windows XP. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mac computers were priced well above PCs, but the quality was definitely there and made it worth it for people who were willing to spend the money&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;. For example, my 2005 PowerBook G4 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/395340D4-2DD9-4AA1-8776-9B97001E4604"&gt;lasted me 12 years&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  And each year, Apple brought new offerings to the table that made technologists excited. By 2006, Apple was making &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;$2.4 billion in profit annually&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; and had some nice brand appeal.&#xD;&#xD;The biggest leap forward for Apple was when they put Mac OS X onto a phone and called it the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;iPhone&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;. It changed the smartphone paradigm and industry overnight, eventually replaced the iPod and became the next cool thing (alongside the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;iPad&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; tablet a few years later). By 2011, Apple was making &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;$16.6 billion in profit annually&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; and this number was growing fast. While the iPod led to more Mac sales in the early 2000s, the iPhone led to tremendously more Mac sales after 2007. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;By 2011, if you wanted to look cool, forget the Nike shoes....you needed a Mac and an iPhone&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;. &#xD;&#xD;Apple was still making some kick-ass computers (and phones) at the time, and they were aggressively making improvements that were considered sexy from a technologist point-of-view. In 2013, if you asked me &#x201C;what computer should I get?&#x201D; the answer would be &#x201C;spend a bit more and get a Mac - you won&#x2019;t regret it.&#x201D;  In fact, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;my favorite computer today is the 2013 Mac Pro tube&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - I still use it as my main workstation, and I upgraded it to 1TB of SSD storage and a whopping 128GB of RAM! It&#x2019;s a beautifully-designed computer that&#x2019;s easy to upgrade and performs exactly as it should.  Unfortunately, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;the 2013 Mac Pro tube is the last good computer Apple has released from a technologist point-of-view.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;Simply put, by 2014, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Apple knew they had the brand everyone wanted, and could charge whatever they wanted&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;. Their &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;phones got more expensive&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, and improvements didn&#x2019;t &#x201C;wow&#x201D; anyone when compared to the same improvements in Android. The &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;quality and upgradability of their computers also went down while prices remained high&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;. Keyboard problems, GPU issues and thermal throttling plagued MacBooks, and the last few versions of the MacBook Pro and iMac Pro have SSDs and RAM that aren&#x2019;t upgradable (you have to order the computer with more at a huge premium). And while I still prefer macOS (formerly called Mac OS X) to Win10, there&#x2019;s no compelling reason for anyone to use one over the other today.&#xD;&#xD;To a technologist, Apple is no longer sexy - but Apple doesn&#x2019;t care about technologists anymore.  They care about their brand&#x2019;s profit margin and those that are willing to contribute to it. As a result, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;buying an Apple product today is more about whether you are willing to pay a lot more for the Apple brand without getting the added benefit of a better-made product&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  Consequently, if you ask me &#x201C;what computer should I get?&#x201D; today, the answer isn&#x2019;t going to be Apple. &#xD;&#xD;Apple&#x2019;s brand is incredibly powerful today, and the continued perception of its value on the stock market slingshot Apple past the $1 trillion dollar valuation mark. Let&#x2019;s recap how Apple got here:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;1970s: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Let&#x2019;s make a well-made computer with a higher price and market it well&#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;1980s:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; Let&#x2019;s make a well-made graphical computer with a higher price and market it well&#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;1990s:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; PCs are killing us like crazy! Let&#x2019;s make an all-in-one computer geared towards those who want a simple way of getting on the Internet and call it the iMac. Thankfully that worked!&#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Early 2000s:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; Let&#x2019;s continue to make well-made computers, but with an awesome OS called Mac OS X.  And we&#x2019;ll make a device that allows you to play thousands of digital music files that fits in your pocket called the iPod.&#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Late 2000s:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; That iPod strategy worked out well!  Let&#x2019;s continue to make well-made computers, including one that fits in your pocket and has a cell phone, called the iPhone.&#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Early 2010s:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; The iPhone paid off big-time!  Let&#x2019;s continue to make well-made computers, the iPhone, as well as a tablet called the iPad. &#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Late 2010s:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; Everyone wants Apple. Let&#x2019;s see how much we can milk our brand. Holy crap!  We&#x2019;re now worth a trillion dollars!&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="5_The_Apple_brand_from_the_70s_to_$1_trillion_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
