<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:58:09 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Whohoo - 20 years of teaching!&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, April 13, 2018&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;I started teaching on April 13th 1998 (20 years ago today).&#xD;&#xD;If you haven&#x2019;t read my blog post reflecting on what I learned during these past 20 years, you can read it here:  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/3E5B7F17-C170-415E-B139-E0CB0A4FFBD4"&gt;CLICK HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;However, in this blog post, I want to reflect on what it was like teaching in my environment over the last two decades.  I have many fond memories and did some pretty cool stuff too!&#xD;It&#x2019;s been great and crazy ride, and it&#x2019;d be a shame not to do a blog post on it!&#xD;&#xD;Back in the late 1990s, I taught primarily for our Kitchener campus (on the corner of King &amp; Victoria) - it was a single-story college building that&#x2019;s been a college long before we were there (at one point it was Ontario Business College).  It felt much like a high school inside with rows of lockers along each hallway, and big roomy classrooms.&#xD;&#xD;Not all classrooms had networked computers or Internet access, but those that did had Pentium computers (75MHz or 120MHz) running Windows 95, NT4 or SCO UNIX.  And the Internet was SLOW (dual ISDN with a proxy server to speed things up that I installed in our server closet, which was also my office at the time).&#xD;&#xD;I also installed a Buddha shrine in our server closet (and matching instructions that allowed other instructors to reset their classroom Internet connection when problems arose) - the Bell guys always got a kick out of it when they came down ;-)&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;It&#x2019;s also important to note that in the early days of the college, the IT instructors were responsible for anything tech-related - if a new classroom needed to be cabled for Internet, it was us doing the work, and if something went wrong, the IT instructor who wasn&#x2019;t currently teaching had to solve it.  &#xD;&#xD;I remember spending many nights at the college prepping for something the next day, or performing a software setup (on one of these nights, my co-worker Scott joked that he spent more time with me at the college than he did with his wife).  &#xD;&#xD;But we also had a lot of fun too!  The campus had a massive common area with pool tables and arcade games, and we often had LAN parties after school on the classroom network (Quake III Arena was our staple).  Our campus pub was the Howl at the Moon Saloon down the street.&#xD;&#xD;We had a lot of creative liberty when it came to doing events in the college, and I did some pretty neat things as a result.  One thing I remember was organizing the first Linux conference in Canada (summer 2000).  It was held in our Kitchener campus, and we had plenty of great speakers and sponsors (including the Linux Professional Institute).  We even ran a &#x201C;Computing 4 Kids&#x201D; series where young kids were exposed to computing early on.  Below is a picture of me talking with the kids before they went off to their computer workstations.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;I also got over $300K worth of DEC Alpha servers donated by Compaq (who bought DEC and roped me into doing some work later for SHARCNET).  The servers arrived via overnight air freight from Chicago in a massive crate that my students helped me unbox.  I formed an extra-curricular group of eager students who wanted to see how I was going to write the MPICH implementation for them (a project I did for Compaq at the time):&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Since our parent company was a corporate training centre, I also got poached from the college classroom every so often to do onsite corporate teaches in companies involving topics that the people in our corporate training centre weren&#x2019;t comfortable with.  I taught hundreds of these for dozens of different companies (mostly larger ones) on topics such as SUN UNIX, HP UNIX, shell programming, PERL programming, Novell, Banyan Vines, and Linux).  I taught so much for Atomic Energy of Canada (AECL) that they eventually offered to just hire me outright (I declined of course).&#xD;&#xD;We also had some pretty wild company events and parties (but there&#x2019;s no way I&#x2019;m going to elaborate on that in a blog post ;-)&#xD;&#xD;After the Dot-com Bubble burst in 2001/2002, the college had far less technology enrollments and had to diversify.  I found myself doing a lot more outside of the college during that time for various companies (which was equally exhilarating). By about 2006, things were picking up and I ended up expanding my role in the organization to Faculty Head, where I helped develop and create curriculum for our IT programs.  &#xD;&#xD;In 2002 I also started writing textbooks for various publishers - my first book was a Linux+ textbook for Course Technology.  This book is now in its 4th edition and is used in colleges and universities around the world!   In the late 2000s, I also worked closely with RIM (which was nothing short of a nightmare) to create their BlackBerry Enterprise Server courseware, as well as introduce mobile courses into our curriculum (we were the first college to do this).&#xD;&#xD;By 2010, we had built a beautiful new campus down the road in Market Square that had a similar look and feel to other campuses in the college.  My IT classroom looked pretty good (note the binary clock on the wall):&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Due to my extensive programming background, I was later asked to take a more active role in the two other technology faculties (application development and video game development) as the Dean of Technology.  &#xD;&#xD;That was an exciting time because I made a lot of great changes to the programs (with the help of instructors of course), drove a lot of external relationships with companies and internship hosts, created extra-curricular groups (including one that did the software development for McMaster University&#x2019;s moon rover), as well as brought in a lot of exhilarating hackathon events to our campuses (a LOT of work).  I coded my own apps and games alongside the students at these hackathons. Below is the intro session to one of our Microsoft-sponsored hackathons in the common area before we broke out into classrooms to do 2 days of coding:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Perhaps the coolest 6 months of my career was helping design and run the Game ON 2.0 exhibition at the Ontario Science Centre (our college was the Presentation Sponsor).  I designed the content and interactive displays for our video game development exhibit, as well as gave countless presentations where I created a video game (Galaga) on my laptop and overhead screen with the audience&#x2019;s help.  Here&#x2019;s me chillin&#x2019; next to PONG at the exhibition, as well as an article that was written about me during that same time:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;That same year I was also the recipient of the first annual OACC Excellence in Teaching award (which means I beat out all other teachers in Ontario!).  While my student&#x2019;s praise was enough teaching validation for me, this award was the ultimate validation because it came from others in my field and was based on achievements during my entire career!&#xD;&#xD; &#xD;&#xD;These past few years have been a lot less glamorous - I&#x2019;ve mainly just been upgrading existing curriculum and teaching.  But I&#x2019;m still having fun in the classroom, and I still do a lot of stuff to promote the college, including blog posts for CompTIA, talks for WWITPRO and ITProTO.  I also try to attend as many after-hours professional events as I can.&#xD;&#xD;Before I spend the rest of the evening with my dog, I just want to end this blog post with a big thank you to each and every student that&#x2019;s ever been in my classroom:  I&#x2019;m honored to have had the privilege to teach you, and want you to know that I&#x2019;ve learned as much from you as you&#x2019;ve learned from me!&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="13_Whohoo_-_20_years_of_teaching%21_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
