<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:58:10 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;A Brief History of Personal Computers (PCs)&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, April 15, 2018&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;What was the first personal computer (PC)?  Finding the answer to that question is nearly impossible &#x2013; it wasn&#x2019;t that a personal computer was &#x201C;invented&#x201D; &#x2013; instead, computing technology evolved to a point in the mid-1970s where microprocessors (a.k.a. CPUs), computer memory and programming software became cheap enough to create computers that could be used in the home or small business.  And quite suddenly in &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;1977&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, the world saw three commercially-successful personal computers reach the market: the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Apple II&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Commodore PET&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, and the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tandy TRS-80&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Atari 400/800&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; joined later on in 1979).   &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;The &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Apple II&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; was a great PC, but it was also very expensive compared to other PCs at the time.  Apple&#x2019;s strategy was to charge more so they could market more.  But the extra cost was worth it &#x2013; Apple computers had excellent build quality and boasted expansion slots for additional hardware, which made it extra popular amongst developers and hobbyists.  It also had the largest software library of any PC at the time.  Unfortunately, few families could afford an Apple II for home, so you often found Apple II computers in some small businesses, libraries, and schools.  &#xD;&#xD;When it came to schools, however, you were far more likely to see &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Commodore PET&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; computers.  They were much cheaper than an Apple II, and everything you needed was housed in a single case that could handle the rigor of a school environment.  If you talk with an elementary or high school computer teacher from that time period, they&#x2019;ll almost always recall teaching BASIC on the Commodore PET!&#xD;&#xD;Tandy got into the PC business alongside Apple and Commodore with their own line of computers that they could sell through their retail store chain, Radio Shack.  The &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tandy TRS-80&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; was a cheaply-made computer that had a plethora of problems.  As a result, it was nicknamed the Trash-80.  But its low price and large software library made it popular amongst hobbyists, businesses, and the few households that could afford a PC.  If your family had a PC in the late 70s, it was probably a Trash-80.    &#xD;&#xD;Atari is an interesting story.  In 1977, they released the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Atari VCS (2600)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, which was a video game console built around a very minimal computer with almost no memory designed to run basic video game cartridges.  It was a hit, and Atari became synonymous with video games for the next decade.  But Atari also produced some very powerful computers at the same time that they eventually released 1979 &#x2013; the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Atari 400/800&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  The Atari 400 was perhaps the coolest looking computer of all time, and the 800 was simply an expanded version of it.  Both the Atari 400 and 800 were relatively inexpensive compared to an Apple II, but had great graphics, hardware and build quality.  It also had a slew of great games too!  Because of its game reputation, it wasn&#x2019;t found in schools, libraries or businesses &#x2013; instead it was primarily used by hobbyists and home users.  &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The 1980s &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;The 1980s felt like the like the dot-com bubble of 1997-2001.  But instead of Web-based companies bent on making millions from the Internet, the 1980s consisted of PC manufacturers that all thought their brand of PC would rise above all others and make billions for decades to come.&#xD;&#xD;Companies like Sinclair, Kaypro, Texas Instruments, Osborne, and Coleco came and went, with the PCs they brought to market long forgotten by the 1990s.  Tandy also exited the PC market during the 1980s due to competition.&#xD;&#xD;So what did happen during the 1980s, exactly?&#xD;&#xD;Well&#x2026;.firstly, Commodore took the market by storm.  A big storm.  In 1980, they essentially released a color version of their PET computer with better graphics (and game capabilities) with 5KB of RAM called the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Commodore VIC-20&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; for only $299.  Jack Tramiel (the guy who ran Commodore with an iron fist) wanted to make &#x201C;Computers for the masses, not the classes.&#x201D; The VIC-20 was the first computer that was bought in massive quantities by the average home user &#x2013; it was essentially the first successful home PC and the first computer to sell more than 1 million units.  It put Commodore on the map and made it a household name at the time.  Even the TV commercial for it starred William Shatner!&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Then, in 1982, Commodore dropped a bigger bombshell on the market &#x2013; the infamous &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Commodore 64 (C64)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; shown to the right. The C64 hardware, sound and graphics were revolutionary at the time and blew anything else on the PC market away.   It had a faster MOS 6510 CPU, 64KB of RAM, and a real sound and video chip.....and it only cost $595. Still today, the C64 holds the record for the best-selling computer of all time (17 million units).  Due to its popularity, programmers flocked to the C64.  The software library for the C64 was staggering due to its popularity &#x2013; if there was a new game or application on the market, it was almost guaranteed to be available on the C64.&#xD;&#xD;What were Apple and Atari doing during all of this time?  Basically, what they were doing before.  Atari kept selling the Atari 400/800 series of computers, and Apple kept selling upgraded versions of the Apple II.  By 1983, both Apple and Commodore were billion dollar companies, but Commodore did it by selling far more computers than Apple did.  &#xD;&#xD;After Jack Tramiel left, Commodore bought a company called Amiga and brought their computer to market in 1985.  The &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Commodore Amiga&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (shown to the left) with a Motorola 68000 CPU, 256KB of RAM and custom video chips was the first multimedia PC, and nothing short of revolutionary when it was introduced. &#xD;&#xD;But lack of development alongside poor marketing ultimately led its stagnation and the demise of Commodore in the early 1990s.  It is worthy to note that some of the best games of the late 1980s were released on the Commodore Amiga. The Commodore Amiga was also commonly used for video and TV production during the late 1980s and early 1990s.&#xD;&#xD;Atari was struggling to make money off of their PCs during the 1980s &#x2013; in 1983, they started selling improved versions of the Atari 400/800 series they called the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Atari XL&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; series, which was improved again into the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Atari XE&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; series in 1985.  They also released the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Atari ST&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; line of computers that had similar hardware to the Commodore Amiga.  Unfortunately, the Atari ST had far less software available than the Commodore Amiga and poor sales forced Atari to exit the PC business entirely by 1990.&#xD;&#xD;Apple released their &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Macintosh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; computer in 1984, with the best graphical user interface of any computer in the 1980s.  While it had a Motorola 68000 CPU and 128KB of RAM, it didn&#x2019;t have color graphics and was very expensive when it came out ($2,495), but new versions gained a lot of support in the late 1980s among professionals and the desktop publishing industry.  Due to its cost, it was far more common to see an Apple II in a household during the 1980s than a Macintosh (Apple continued selling the Apple II line into the early 1990s as a result). &#xD; &#xD;Now for the most important part:  The 1980s awoke a sleeping giant&#x2026;.IBM.  IBM made the biggest computers in the world for decades before the 1980s, and their reputation was like pure gold in the computing industry.  In 1981, IBM decided they wanted a piece of the PC market and released the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;IBM PC 5150&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;:  &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;The PC 5150 was built like a tank, but the hardware was nothing special compared to nearly every other PC on the market at that time (Intel 8088 CPU, 16KB RAM).  But the IBM brand meant that they were guaranteed sales from the business market, and other manufacturers such as Compaq, HP and Dell started selling &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;IBM-compatible computers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (a.k.a. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;IBM clones&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;) with the same hardware as a result.  This was possible because IBM simply used freely-available components on the market when they designed the PC 5150, instead of designing custom components like other PC manufacturers at the time.&#xD;&#xD;By the late 1980s, it was clear that IBM won the PC war.  IBM and IBM clones were everywhere - home, schools, libraries&#x2026;.you name it!   &#xD;&#xD;In fact, by the late 1980s IBM and its clones became synonymous with &#x201C;PC&#x201D;, and Apple became synonymous with &#x201C;Mac&#x201D; (Macintosh).  By 1990, most people had either a PC or a Mac, because those were the two personal computers that held nearly all of the market share by the end of the 1980s.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The 1990s &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;The 1990s saw the massive rise of the PC - and by PC, I&#x2019;m referring to the IBM PC (and clones).  The picture to the right is what a typical PC looked like in the mid 1990s:&#xD;&#xD;More specifically, PCs became far more powerful during the 1990s &#x2013; during the rise of the PC in the 1980s, Intel had evolved their CPU line dramatically to include the 80286 and 80386.  This accelerated in the 1990s with the introduction of the powerful &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;80486&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pentium&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; CPU line.  Other manufacturers such as &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cyrix&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;AMD&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; started making their own Intel-compatible CPUs during this time as well.  &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Microsoft Windows&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; quickly became the operating system used on PCs everywhere, and as PC games with sophisticated graphics (e.g. DOOM) started a whole new gaming culture, PC video card manufacturers such as ATI, Matrox, 3Dfx and Nvidia started releasing more powerful graphical chipsets.  Oh, and the Internet became the next big thing.&#xD;&#xD;Macs became more and more scarce in the 1990s, and Apple was on the brink of bankruptcy by 1997.  It wasn&#x2019;t until Steve Jobs returned to Apple that same year and introduced the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;iMac&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (shown left) that Apple sales started to pick up and the company was saved from bankruptcy.  However, the number of Mac computers on the market was minuscule, and the software market reflected that as well &#x2013; nearly all software in the 1990s was written for Windows PCs.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The 2000s &amp; 2010s&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;The 2000s continued the growth of the 1990s - the PC and the Internet were bigger than ever, and nearly all age groups and income levels got into computing.  &#xD;&#xD;Cheap Pentium PCs (like the one shown to the right) became common, and the lure of the Internet (social media, online banking, etc.) brought nearly everyone into computing at some level.  &#xD;&#xD;While 97% of everyone on the Internet used a Windows PC, Apple started selling more and more Mac computers thanks to their success with the iPod.  &#xD;&#xD;After Apple released the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;iPhone&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; in 2007 and Google released &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Android&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; in 2008, mobile Internet computing became popular.  Now, your cell phone was also a small computer with Internet access.  For those that didn&#x2019;t like the small screen Wi-Fi &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;tablets&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; soon followed in 2010.  For many seniors and pre-schoolers, a tablet was their first and only computing experience.&#xD;&#xD;In the 2010s, the price of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;laptop computers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; came down dramatically, which led to more and more people opting for a portable PC or Mac.  It&#x2019;s now 2018, and Windows PCs comprise 83% of the computing market.  Macs comprise 12% (a huge jump compared to the 1990s), and the rest run Linux or ChromeOS.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The future?&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;It&#x2019;s quite clear that mobile computers are going to continue to be the focus moving forward, whether that be a smartphone, laptop or wearable device.  However, it will take a long time (if ever) before we see desktop PCs replaced entirely with mobile devices.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="15_A_Brief_History_of_Personal_Computers_%28PCs%29_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
