<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>arcade on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/arcade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in arcade on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/arcade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I finally beat Tetris!</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/i-finally-beat-tetris/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/i-finally-beat-tetris/</guid>
      <description>I’ve finally done it. I’ve beaten the game Tetris.
More specifically, Atari 2-player arcade Tetris, which is the best version of Tetris ever released (in my opinion) and the one that was available in arcades before Nintendo secured the rights to the game from the Soviet Union.
A few years ago, my daughter and I picked up a Taito arcade cabinet that I restored to play Tetris using the original Atari arcade game printed circuit board (PCB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 in review</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2018-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2018-in-review/</guid>
      <description>At the end of each year, I take some time to reflect on the previous year - it provides perspective, and is a lot of fun!
For me, 2018 was the year I spent a lot of time improving myself physically, challenging myself mentally, and most importantly, enjoying life!
On the personal side, I cut out the bad foods from my diet:
 breads starches alcohol  On top of this, I upped my indoor and outdoor exercise to lose a whopping 85 pounds since mid 2017 - I feel great, have loads of energy, and no longer have any back pain whatsoever!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 in review</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2017-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2017-in-review/</guid>
      <description>So what happened in 2017?
Last year I thought I completed my basement arcade by getting Donkey Kong (see my blog post entitled &amp;ldquo;2016 in review&amp;rdquo;), but I was wrong! I actually got two new arcade games this year. The first one was an arcade machine I never thought I’d find in good working condition. It’s also the absolute coolest arcade game of the 1980s with its amazing vector graphics (as well as my all-time favourite arcade game)&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014 in review</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2014-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2014-in-review/</guid>
      <description>I think it’s always a good idea each year to reflect on the events that happened during the year - it’s a great way to remember some of the great things that have happened, as well as put some of the not-so-great things that have happened in perspective. If you regularly post to social media (e.g. Facebook or Twitter), looking back on your posts are a great way to revisit the major events that took place during the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Arcade Games</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/info/arcadegames/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/info/arcadegames/</guid>
      <description>Growing up in the 80s was awesome! One of the best things about growing up in the 80s for me was that I developed a love of video games. I loved spending time at the arcade playing the classics like Tempest, Missile Command and Galaga. At home, we had an Atari 2600 and later a Nintendo NES. I loved it all.
In recent years, I purchased my absolute favourite arcade games of all time&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Books</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/reads/gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/reads/gaming/</guid>
      <description>Martin Amis: Invasion of the Space Invaders (1982) This is probably the most sought-after video game book of the 1980s by the uber-famous, world-renowned author Martin Amis (most copies sell for over $200 today). Martin Amis has a unique way of bringing you back to the video game world of 1978-1982 using verbal imagery and humour - after all, he was a video game addict at the time! Some of the high-resolution colour photos in the book (including the one above) say more than words ever could.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>