<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:41:47 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Aftermath from The King of Kong (updated)&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Monday, February 1, 2016&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Competitive arcade gaming has been around since the very beginning of the arcade game era (late 1970s/early 1980s).  And in 1981, Walter Day started collecting arcade high scores from around the world - his arcade, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Twin Galaxies (TG)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; since became the unofficial score keeper of all things arcade.  TG&#x2019;s long time star video game champion was &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Billy Mitchell &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;(who is also a very influential member of TG).  And like many organizations that have free reign over something, it also became heavily corrupted internally.  But few people knew of this until 2007, when the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The King of Kong: A Fistful of Quarters&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; documentary came out.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. The documentary in a nutshell&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;If you haven&#x2019;t watched The King of Kong documentary yet, go watch it!  &#xD;It&#x2019;s not just a good documentary, it&#x2019;s a great documentary.  And a great documentary portrays real events and people in a raw way that allows the audience to see the true nature of the story and people within it from every angle without the filmmakers adding any content.  &#xD;&#xD;The King of Kong does this better than any documentary I&#x2019;ve seen to date - it will leave you with an uneasy-but-satisfying feeling at the end.  Oh, and you&#x2019;ll complete despise Billy Mitchell.&#xD;&#xD;In short, The King of Kong documentary introduces Walter Day, TG, and the nature of competitive arcade gaming, but then exposes the corruption within TG by showcasing live footage of Billy Mitchell and his loyal &#x201C;disciples&#x201D; trying to prevent &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Steve Wiebe&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; from getting his Donkey Kong high scores recognized officially between 2005 and 2006 (because it would overthrow Billy Mitchell&#x2019;s Donkey Kong high score).  The documentary is as gripping, dramatic and entertaining as any blockbuster film, but much deeper in character portrayal.  It was a massive success - not because it was about video game competitions or Donkey Kong - but that it was about people.  More specifically, it was about a good guy trying to achieve something, and a bunch of manipulative/bad people going to long lengths to prevent that (hence the caption &#x201C;Don&#x2019;t Get Chumpatized&#x201D; on the movie poster above).&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. What happened immediately after the documentary?&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Up until the documentary was released, TG was considered &#x201C;the&#x201D; organization for high score seekers and Billy Mitchell was seen as a rock star amongst those in the retro gaming community, especially in the US where his US flag necktie won him extra bonus points for patriotism. So, when a documentary comes out that has clear footage of TG and Billy Mitchell manipulating others, it&#x2019;s a big slap in the face for those involved, as well as others who previously idolized them.  &#xD;&#xD;Many people pointed fingers at the filmmakers and blamed them for portraying TG and Billy Mitchell in a negative light. As a result, I wanted to know exactly how accurate the people were portrayed in the movie.&#xD;&#xD;From an article in &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;GameRoom Magazine (Sept 2007, The King of Controversy)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; that interviewed Seth Gordon (the director), Ed Cunningham (the producer), and Steve Sanders (friend of Billy Mitchell), I learned that the documentary was originally supposed to be sports-like documentary with a video game as the focus, but morphed into its current form after the filmmakers saw that there was a lot of drama under the surface.  Here are a few great parts from that article:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Interviewer: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Do you believe that the sequence of events are accurately portrayed?&#xD;	 	&#xD;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Seth Gordon: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; I know they are.  We joined the story in 2005 and continued filming regularly through early 2007.  The film accurately represents what transpired while we covered the story and provides considerable historical context so an audience might understand the stakes of the rivalry.&#xD;	 	&#xD;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Interviewer: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;When did it become apparent to you that this was no longer a simple story of someone trying to obtain a high score, but more a character study into the world of competitive gaming?&#xD;	 	&#xD;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ed Cunninham: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; For me, it was witnessing the events in and around the 7th Annual Funspot Tournament.  It was apparent that there was more at stake than just high scores, and it became very interesting for me to see what was happening behind the scenes, and that became a more universal story than someone simply trying to set a high score.&#xD;	 	&#xD;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Interviewer: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;What&#x2019;s your perspective on the sequence of events as they appear on the screen?  Do you feel they&#x2019;re accurate?&#xD;	 	&#xD;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Steve Sanders: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; The timeline is accurate in all the relevant details.  Some quotations are taken out of context/sequence, but nothing that makes any substantial or historical difference....&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;I also found the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Filmlot interview with Seth Gordon&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; from the Wikipedia entry on Billy Mitchell (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120322222322/http://thefilmlot.com/interviews/INTsgordon.php"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20120322222 ... gordon.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;).  Although you have to read the whole interview, here is one part that stood out for me:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Interviewer: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;There was this real dichotomy between the two main subjects. They really fell into the good guy (Steve Wiebe) and the bad guy (Billy Mitchell) roles. It was also surprising to see the lengths Billy went through to keep tabs on Wiebe. &#xD;	 	&#xD;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Seth Gordon:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; I completely agree. The archetypes of Darth Vader and Luke Skywalker are very present... There&#x2019;s a lot of stuff we couldn&#x2019;t include that Billy did just because of inter-state telephone rules. We only could use stuff where we had a camera pointing at Billy. All I&#x2019;m saying is, the stuff he did to keep tabs on Steve and control him, was far greater than we could actually show. He is a true puppet master &#x2013; and really rules this whole group of guys. He tells them where to walk, where to be, what to do, what to say&#x2026; it&#x2019;s unbelievable. Billy is such a good gamer that when he&#x2019;s finished beating the games, he moves on to play games with people and we [even] became part of that. Especially Ed who had to deal with him the most&#x2026; &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;So, essentially, the documentary was incredibly accurate in it&#x2019;s portrayal of the characters.&#xD;&#xD;This isn&#x2019;t surprising since the documentary&#x2019;s raw footage largely speaks for itself, and others both within and outside the gaming community knew this as well after watching it.  Websites started selling t-shirts that said stuff like &#x201C;Team Wiebe&#x201D; and &#x201C;Wiebelieve!&#x201D; and even &#x201C;Billy Mitchell never lies!&#x201D; (har har ;-) &#xD; &#xD;&#xD;It isn&#x2019;t to surprising that these events, combined with countless others, angered many of the TG members and Billy Mitchell.  So much so, that the October 2007 edition of GameRoom Magazine included a spin-doctored article entitled &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Truth About Billy Mitchell&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, whose purpose was to attack the validity of the documentary and highlight Billy Mitchell&#x2019;s good side. They even had &#x201C;CONFIDENTIAL&#x201D; and EVIDENCE&#x201D; plastered on the cover like a sleazy tabloid magazine.  &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. What were the long term effects of the documentary?&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;In the years since 2007, the King of Kong has essentially brought:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Donkey Kong back to the public spotlight after 25 years. &#xD;	&#x2022;	Retro arcade gaming to the public spotlight (there have been a flood of retro arcade game documentaries since).&#xD;	&#x2022;	TG to the public spotlight, while simultaneously exposing them as a corrupt organization.  They&#x2019;ve since undergone many struggles, including losing their relationship with Guinness and closing down for several months. Today, they no longer dictate the rules of competitive gaming - instead, they struggle to stay relevant in a world where online streaming (e.g. YouTube, TwitchTV) allows the world to judge a video game competition without bias.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;It also brought an end to the epic battle between Billy Mitchell and Steve Wiebe. Since 2007, the number of people entering competitive arcade gaming skyrocketed, especially with Donkey Kong (a game that is both fun and challenging to master).  Consequently, a flood of newcomers have since knocked Steve Wiebe and Billy Mitchell off the top 10 high scores list (from &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://donkeykongforum.com"&gt;http://donkeykongforum.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;/):&#xD;&#xD;&#xD; &#xD;Steve Wiebe is now #16 and Billy Mitchell is now #17 ... and their ranks will fall further as more people play Donkey Kong competitively.  While The King of Kong documentary was certainly the catalyst in popularizing Donkey Kong and competitive gaming, it really was the key events and true nature of the characters in the film that inspired people to beat their way to Donkey Kong fame and take the title of &#x201C;The King of Kong.&#x201D; &lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_Entry_1_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
