<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:55:30 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Anniversary of the World Wide Web&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Monday, November 12, 2007&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Do you remember the dawn of the Internet in the mid 1990s?&#xA0; Everyone was talking about the &#x201C;Information Superhighway&#x201D; (a cheezy term for the Internet back then) and how it would change everyone&#x2019;s life.&#xA0; Then people starting talking about the World Wide Web (WWW) and email and facebook. &#xD;&#xD;Still today, many people don&#x2019;t know how to properly define the World Wide Web and the Internet.&#xA0; At dinner parties with non-geek friends, I like to bring this up by asking, &#x201C;So, can anyone here tell me what the Internet and World Wide Web are?&#x201D;.&#xA0; People start by blurting out things such as email and text messaging and doing taxes online, and usually someone argues that it is a social phenomenon or something, but eventually people start to realize that they really have no idea what the Internet and World Wide Web actually are.&#xA0; I can be a bastard sometimes, but it is fun. &#xD;&#xD;Then, of course, I enlighten everyone.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Early Home Networking and BBSes&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Computer networks have been around since the 1970s.&#xA0; In the 1980s, you could buy a modem that allowed your computer to connect to other computers (called servers) that would serve you some information if you requested it.&#xA0; If your computer served the information during a particular exchange, your computer was then called a server as well.&#xA0; By 1990, most people who had modems used them to connect their 386 computer to a Bulletin Board System (BBS) by dialing the telephone number of the server that had files that you could download (mostly programs, games and pics).&#xA0; None of this really had anything to do with the Internet or World Wide Web.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Internet&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;In the 1970s and 1980s, the Internet was called the ARPANET (Advanced Research Projects Agency Network) due to its government/university funding and usage.&#xA0; It was basically a way of connecting existing computer networks (mainly at universities) together so you could send files and emails to others.&#xA0;&#xA0; If you were a university student in the 1980s, you probably sent emails using ARPANET on the schools terminals, but few outside academia knew of its existence.&#xA0; If you were a home computer user and wanted to connect your home computer to another computer, you probably dialed up a BBS because the ARPANET was limited mainly to universities.&#xD;&#xD;In the early 1990s when the U.S. government ran out of money to maintain ARPANET, parts of it were essentially sold off to companies such as AT&amp;T, who became commercial Internet Service Providers (ISPs) that you could pay to access the Internet from home or business (if you had a dial-up modem or router).&#xA0; Thus, the Internet (or Internetwork) is simply a large collection of publicly-accessible computer networks.&#xA0; It consists of all the physical components that allow a company/individual to send information around the world.&#xA0; It is similar in scope to the telephone lines and switching stations that have allowed us to make calls around the world for almost a century. &#xD;&#xD;The Internet was gradually developed into its current form by many different organizations over the past 30 years.&#xA0; Today, we don&#x2019;t use modems to dial up ISPs to get Internet access, we typically use high-speed routers (the black box you get from your ISP is typically a DSL/cable router).&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The World Wide Web (WWW)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The World Wide Web is different from the Internet.&#xA0; As people were thinking about what the ARPANET could be used for outside academia, the most obvious use was global information access. &#xD;&#xD;But what format should this information be in?&#xD;&#xD;HyperText Transfer Protocol (HTTP) was eventually selected as the main format of information transmitted on the Internet - you simply connected to a server that gave you a page formatted in HTTP that your computer could understand.&#xA0; This HTTP page would then contain links to other HTTP pages (called hyperlinks) on other servers so that you could &#x201C;browse&#x201D; the world to obtain information quickly. &#xD;&#xD;This approach to information access was called the World Wide Web (WWW).&#xA0; You browsed &#x201C;web pages&#x201D; on a &#x201C;web site&#x201D; by connecting your &#x201C;web browser&#x201D; program (Netscape, Internet Explorer, Firefox) to &#x201C;web servers&#x201D; that gave you the actual HTTP pages.&#xA0; You could then read these web pages and click on hyperlinks to carry you to other public web servers and read more web pages, and so on.&#xA0; Web servers are typically accessed using names that start with www and underlined text can be clicked to obtain other resources on the World Wide Web (e.g. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/"&gt;www.google.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;).&#xD;&#xD;HTML and the WWW were conceptualized in 1989 by Sir Tim Berners-Lee and Robert Cailliau, working at CERN in Geneva, Switzerland.&#xA0;&#xA0; The official paper that described the WWW was published on this day in 1990 (November 12th, 1990).&#xA0; As the Internet became more commercialized in the early-mid 1990s, web sites kept popping up all around the world, making the World Wide Web a reality.&#xD;&#xD;Today, we obtain information from servers on the Internet that participate in the World Wide Web.&#xA0; So what about email, instant messaging, downloading music, etc.?&#xA0; Well, those are other Internet technologies that arose as technology and the Internet advanced over time........and a whole other story.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;NOTE: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Do not confuse the &#x201C;World Wide Web&#x201D; with the &#x201C;World Wide Wedge&#x201D;, which was invented in 1996 by Ronald &#x201C;Wedgie&#x201D; Jackson, a high school student in Springfield, Missouri.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="12_Entry_1_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="513px" height="385px"/>
</content>
