<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:42:51 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Cult of Mac Book (Escaping the Cult of Mac)&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Saturday, February 2, 2019&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;A few weeks ago, I was out at a social event with a bunch of guys and gals from the local Linux/UNIX/developer/IT community (contrary to popular opinion, Linux/UNIX people know how to party hard). &#xD;&#xD;At one point during the night, we were sitting at a round booth and poking fun at a total Apple fanboy in our group. Someone called him a &#x201C;Cult of Mac member&#x201D; and he replied, &#x201C;And proud to be one - I could write the book on the cult!&#x201D; to which I replied, &#x201C;Firstly, you're not an accomplished author. Secondly, as a cult survivor, I'm the one who should be writing the book.&#x201D; &#xD;&#xD;A few drinks later, I somehow got roped into making a bet that I could write a proper book on the Cult of Mac in a weekend. So I did. During the freezing cold weekend we had two weeks ago. It&#x2019;s called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Escaping the Cult of Mac: A Guide from a Cult Survivor&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;You can download the PDF of the book here: &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/jasoneckert/CultOfMac"&gt;https://github.com/jasoneckert/CultOfMac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;It&#x2019;s 76 pages long as has the following chapters:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	1.	Introduction&#xD;	2.	Acquiring context: A brief history of personal computers and Apple&#xD;	3.	Defining the cult: What&#x2019;s it all about?&#xD;	4.	Psychology, fake ideals and influencers: Why people join the cult&#xD;	5.	Cult evangelism: Keeping you in the cult&#xD;	6.	Diagnosing cult members: A survey&#xD;	7.	Leaving the cult: The why and how&#xD;	8.	Final thoughts&#xD;	9.	Additional reading&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;When I was finished, I sent the PDF out to everyone.&#xD;Most reactions were &#x201C;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The was freakin&#x2019; hilarious, and so very very true!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#x201D; However, there were a few people (all of whom were Cult of Mac members) that were quite irked by what I wrote (irony is not dead ;-).&#xD;&#xD;Anywho, it&#x2019;s true, it&#x2019;s funny, and it&#x2019;s worth a read.&#xD;However, like any satire, it is not politically correct, and will never be.&#xD;If you are terminally thin-skinned and feel offended after reading it, do not send me an email complaining about it. You won&#x2019;t get any sympathy from my end. Instead, click on this link and read the associated quote by Stephen Fry several times until you internalize the message: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/stuff/offended.jpg"&gt;http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/stuff/offended.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;  &lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="2_Cult_of_Mac_eBook_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
