<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200627" date="2020-06-28 02:21:59 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The evolution of the power workstation&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Wednesday, February 18, 2015&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Since the early days of personal computers (PCs), geeks have boasted about their computer hardware specs, and the &#x201C;alpha geek&#x201D; in any department or organization is often the person with the most powerful PC at their desk ;-)&#xD;&#xD;PCs with significantly more hardware power than other PCs are often called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;power workstations&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - the first power workstations were introduced in the early 1980s and have changed dramatically over the following three decades!  In this post, I&#x2019;ll examine the history and evolution of power workstations from the early 1980s to today.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Early 1980s: The first power workstations appeared (SUN, SGI &amp; Apollo)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;By this time, people and companies were starting to realize that high-end computing wasn&#x2019;t going to require the use of expensive mainframe computers forever, and that the focus of computing would shift to PCs.  After all, in the early 1980s, there was an explosion of commercial PCs available on the market, including the Commodore 64, Apple II, Apple Macintosh, Tandy TRS-80, Atari 800, IBM PC5150, DEC Rainbow, and KayPro.  You could easily pick up one of these computers from your local shopping mall.&#xD;&#xD;The three main companies that provided more powerful workstations during this time were &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Standford University Network (SUN) Microsystems&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Silicon Graphics Inc (SGI)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Apollo Computer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  All three based their workstations around the Motorola 68000 CPU family, and although they were designed to be more powerful than the average commercial PC, they were also much more expensive - a typical SUN-2 workstation (below left) cost around $30,000, compared to a Mac Plus workstation (below right) that cost $2,500.  &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;The SUN-2 workstation had a larger screen, 4 times the RAM of the Mac Plus, a SCSI hard disk (Mac Plus owners had to purchase an external SCSI hard disk), and a 30% faster Motorola CPU.  Doesn&#x2019;t sound like the spec difference justifies the massive cost difference, right?  I&#x2019;d agree with you there, which is why you&#x2019;d never find a SUN, SGI or Apollo computer in your neighborhood Sears or Radio Shack store at the time.  However, SUN, SGI and Apollo workstations contained a powerful OS based on UNIX that was designed to communicate with other workstations and minicomputers/mainframes across a computer network, which was both a rare and valuable asset at the time.  SUN even adopted the motto &#x201C;the computer is the network&#x201D; later on.&#xD;&#xD;So what were these early power workstations used for?  Mostly science and engineering, since both of those disciplines required both computing power and graphical visualization capabilities.  Most universities at the time had a small armada of SUN workstations networked together, and ironically, an equal-or-larger number of Macintosh computers.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Late 1980s to late 1990s: New platforms, more players, lots of money&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;In the late 1980s, power computing started to gain critical traction as organizations realized that high-end computing would fast become a necessity for research and development (and hence competition) in their respective industries.  And they were willing to pay a hefty sum for powerful workstations!&#xD;&#xD;As a result, SUN created the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPARC&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; CPU in 1987 to replace the limited Motorola platform they used earlier. SGI followed suit and moved to the powerful &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;MIPS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; CPU architecture for their workstations. Apollo was bought by HP, which phased them out in favor of their own line of power workstations built with the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;PA-RISC&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; CPU.&#xD;&#xD;It is important to note that SPARC, MIPS and PA-RISC are all &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;RISC (Reduced Instruction Set Computing)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; platforms - RISC had far more potential for power computing compared to the CISC (Complex Instruction Set Computing) CPUs found in commercial PCs of the time, such as the Intel x86, Motorola 68000 family, and so on. &#xD;&#xD;The two high-end computer manufacturers (IBM and DEC) also got into the game - IBM released power workstations built around the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;POWER&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; RISC CPU architecture (including PowerPC), while DEC released power workstations with the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Alpha&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; RISC CPU, which was the most powerful CPU of the 1990s. &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;But this power didn&#x2019;t come cheap - a DEC Alpha power workstation cost you about $70,000, and a decent SGI MIPS, SUN SPARC, IBM POWER, or HP PA-RISC power workstation cost anywhere from $20,000 to $50,000!&#xD;&#xD;So why did companies buy them? To answer that you must first understand that there was a massive spike in computing research and development from late 1980s through late 1990s due a a wide variety of factors, including a strong economy and the proliferation of the Internet.  The amazing graphical effects that you saw in &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jurassic Park&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; were created on SGI MIPS power workstations, the computer animations that you saw in &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Toy Story&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; were created on SUN SPARC power workstations, and the ultra-realistic cinematics in &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Titanic&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; were created on DEC Alphas. But movies were only one application of power workstations.  Throughout the 1990s, you&#x2019;d find power workstations performing chemical modeling, designing space shuttles, operating bleeding-edge medical equipment, and much much more.  &#xD;&#xD;That being said, you still had to have a good reason to justify their cost, as reflected in the following &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;User Friendly &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;comic from February 1999:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;The 1990s also saw huge growth in the video game industry.  As a result, Sony and Nintendo decided to capitalize on the powerful MIPS platform already rampant in the power workstation industry - the Sony Playstation and Nintendo 64 used MIPS CPUs, and SGI MIPS workstations were employed to do game development for them.  J.C.Herz puts it best in her book, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Joystick Nation&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;	&#x27A1;	&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The artists and animators who render video games on Silicon Graphics workstations can only afford to do so because SGI&#x2019;s largest customers, until recently, were companies like Boeing and Lockheed that needed computational Clydesdales for military projects.  If they hadn&#x2019;t bought thousands of these machines, it wouldn&#x2019;t be economically possible to develop &#x201C;Donkey Kong Country 2&#x201D; or &#x201C;Battle Arena Toshinden&#x201D;... &#xD;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;After 2000: Cheaper power computing and the shift to x86/x64&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;By about 2000, the world had embraced the Internet, PCs were everywhere, the stock Intel and AMD CPUs that you found in your commercial PCs started to get much more powerful, and affordable graphics cards that supported the same type of visualization capabilities as power workstations of the 1990s started to appear.  Suddenly, you didn&#x2019;t need to buy a $50,000 SGI Octane to do graphical modeling anymore.  Consequently, the prices of the RISC-based power workstations that ruled the 1990s plummeted....but not enough - they still couldn&#x2019;t keep up with the more powerful commercial PCs of the time, especially gaming PCs such as &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Alienware&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Note that the only inferior spec in the Alienware shown above was its 32-bit CPU (versus the 64-bit CPUs of the SGI and SUN workstations) - but the higher CPU output and advanced graphics card more than made up for it. &#xD;&#xD;And when AMD and Intel starting shipping 64-bit (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;x64&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;) CPUs in large numbers a few years later, it was a nail in the coffin for the RISC power workstations of the 1990s - by 2009, they had all vanished.  HP discontinued their PA-RISC workstation line, SGI discontinued their MIPS workstation line, IBM discontinued their POWER workstation line and SUN discontinued their SPARC workstation line. DEC was bought by Compaq in 1998, which continued to sell Alpha workstations - but when HP bought Compaq in 2002, they ditched the Alpha line and briefly sold power workstations based on the horribly slow Intel Itanium CPU before discontinuing power workstations altogether. &#xD;&#xD;In fact, the Alpha, MIPS and PA-RISC CPU architectures disappeared entirely during the 2000s (MIPS is only used today in low-power embedded devices).  The SPARC platform is alive and well, but only on large servers made by Fujitsu and Oracle (which purchased SUN Microsystems in 2010) - the 16-core Oracle UltraSPARC T5 CPU is one of the best-performing CPUs on the server market!&#xD;&#xD;The POWER platform is also alive and well today in large IBM servers, such as IBM&#x2019;s WATSON supercomputer.  It is also used in game consoles (Nintendo Gamecube, Nintendo Wii/Wii-U, Sony Playstation 4, and Microsoft Xbox 360), and Macintosh computers of the early/mid 2000s.  In fact, the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Power Mac G5 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;shown right can be considered the last &#x201C;widely-used&#x201D; power workstation that used a RISC CPU architecture - it had a starting price of $2,000, could contain up to two 64-bit PowerPC G5 CPUs, and remained a popular seller up until it was discontinued in 2006.   &#xD;&#xD;So what really WAS the power workstation of the 2000s and beyond? &#xD;&#xD;Well.....essentially it was just a &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;commercial PC with very good specs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (lots of RAM, high-end video card, and fast AMD or Intel CPU).  And you could get one for well under $5,000. In other words - movies, video games, chemical models and complex engineering software of the 2000s ran primarily on PCs that had the same specs as a high-end gaming PC like the one shown below:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Even Macintosh switched entirely from the PowerPC platform to the Intel platform back in 2007.  Their latest high-end power workstation (the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mac Pro&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, shown below in triplicate) is essentially a centrally-cooled turbine in a tube form factor with dual AMD FirePro video cards, a screaming fast SSD, and high-end Intel Xeon CPU.  And the only reason it&#x2019;s able to compete with other power workstations today is that Apple managed to cram all that high-end hardware in their Mac Pro and sell it for much less than what you&#x2019;d pay if you were to purchase the components separately - after all, &#x201C;getting the best bang for your buck&#x201D; is what caused the RISC power workstations to die in favor of x86/x64 power workstations after 2000!  Needless to say, Apple sells a lot of Mac Pros today.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="18_The_evolution_of_the_power_workstation_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
