<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:42:38 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Why I removed all of my Facebook data&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Wednesday, October 3, 2018&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Yes, you heard that correctly!  I actually deleted (not disabled) my Facebook account. And as you can see from the picture at the top of this post, this includes nearly 10,000 posts and over 7000 photos over the past decade.&#xD;&#xD;Being enamored with the rise of social media in the computing landscape, I was an early Facebook adopter compared to most. I liked the ease at which you could share visual information, and how it altered how we ultimately communicate (memes, likes, shares, and everything else).&#xD;&#xD;It also allowed me to connect with people from my childhood, distant family members, ex-girlfriends, former students, and a lot of people from around the world that seem like genuinely good people. I accepted any friend request from a real human being, including a lot of people in Washington state (USA) that thought I was the &#x201C;other&#x201D; Jason Eckert that they knew, because we both posted about Linux and our dogs (which look quite similar). When the &#x201C;other&#x201D; Jason Eckert friended me and let me know that I even confused his own sister, we had a laugh and still remained friends on Facebook.&#xD;&#xD;I opened Facebook in my desktop Web browser and mobile app every day. Most days ended with me catching up on other people&#x2019;s posts on Facebook. It was the modern equivalent of the boob tube (or &#x201C;television&#x201D; for you youngsters) from when I was a kid - a place where you could waste a lot of time at home, but have fun in the process.&#xD;&#xD;So why did I get rid of it all?&#xD;&#xD;Well, firstly - I started to see first hand the social manipulation that people have been accusing Facebook of these past several years. Social media does a good job of validating your own preconceptions and beliefs in general, but Facebook definitely goes far beyond that. If the topic is a hobby or harmless interest like arcade collecting or Linux, then it can be a good thing that allows you to pursue that hobby or interest further. However, it also means that:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	If you are a racist, Facebook will make you more racist by showing you racist stuff.&#xD;	&#x2022;	If you are a Trump supporter, Facebook will make you think that Trump is an angel by showing you more pro-Trump stuff. &#xD;	&#x2022;	If you are a vegan, Facebook will show you more vegan stuff (which is inhumane in my opinion ;-)&#x2028;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;I knew it was happening, but never thought much of it a few years ago because it didn&#x2019;t affect me as much back then - it wasn't until this past year when it really hit home. Because I've friended over 500 people, the likelihood of my having one or two racists, Trump supporters and vegans in there meant I was constantly using the Facebook controls on those posts to tell Facebook not to show me topics like these (and these topics came from ALL areas of Facebook, not just from those one or two people!). It was both tiring and enlightening at the same time. The dark, manipulative side of social media at its finest.&#xD;&#xD;But the final straw was today, when I got a polite message from a Facebook bot noting that my account will be banned from posting, liking, or replying to posts for 3 days because of a picture that I posted a week ago that didn&#x2019;t fit their &#x201C;community standards&#x201D; for posting - here is the picture (and yes, irony is not dead):&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Was it politically correct? Of course not - I wouldn&#x2019;t wish political correctness - or the censorship of critical thought - on my worst enemy. And yes, it was funny, especially to us gamers who&#x2019;ve read LEVEL magazine.&#xD;&#xD;So, here I find myself using this online service (Facebook) that I access for free in return for my personal data for advertising purposes and social manipulation. Now it&#x2019;s telling me that I can&#x2019;t post something on their site that is quite arguably harmless. And to discourage me from repeating that behaviour, they banned me from any sort of interaction (posting/liking/replying) for three days.&#xD;&#xD;My first reaction was of anger (How dare they try to condition me?!?). &#xD;&#xD;But then I thought to myself, &#x201C;Why is this Web site making me angry?&#x201D; &#x201C;Have I developed a dependency to this Web site that makes a 3 day ban feel like punishment?&#x201D; &#xD;&#xD;And, of course, the answer is yes. It was gradual, over a long period of time - a feedback loop of positive reinforcement (likes). But just like you can get up from a couch and stop watching television, you can do the same for social media. After all, it&#x2019;s just a bunch of pictures and phrases that you&#x2019;ve posted, some other ones that you&#x2019;ve liked, and a lot of time. &#xD;&#xD;Do I need to post on Facebook? Do I need to have people like my posts? No.&#xD;Do I like the social manipulation features that Facebook implements? No.&#xD;Do I value my freedom of thought, as well as reject the consensus terrorism and thought censorship that provides the foundation of political correctness? Yes, unequivocally yes.&#xD;&#xD;So I removed 10 years of data, and links to over 500 people without any desire to look back.&#xD;Will I miss it? Maybe. And I&#x2019;ll have to text my friends and family members instead of using the Facebook Messenger app to send them messages. But this 3 day ban was a great wake up call - it allowed me to put my priorities back in order. Plus, it feels absolutely great to delete stuff. It&#x2019;s just data, after all - not something that defines who you are.&#xD;&#xD;Now, I should mention that while my Facebook account is now gone, when you click the Delete Account button shown in the picture at the top of this post, Facebook tells you that your data will be kept for 30 days in case you change your mind. I suspect I&#x2019;ll get some emails from them during this time reminding me of this, but I&#x2019;ll be ignoring them. Facebook was fun, but it&#x2019;s time to explore some other cool stuff! &#xD;&#xD;Ask yourself - could you visualize deleting your own Facebook account? If this thought makes you feel uncomfortable after thinking about it seriously for a few minutes, you may want to reevaluate your dependency on the Facebook platform like I did today!&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="3_Why_I_removed_all_of_my_Facebook_data_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
