<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:55:22 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;New Years security resolutions for 2006&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, January 1, 2006&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;1. Don&#x2019;t give personal information to obtain documents on the web&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Many sites want you to register to get a free document or certain web page.&#xA0; What do you think they use your information for?&#xA0; Spam, spam and more spam.&#xA0; If you want to get these documents without putting in your personal information, simply put the URL for the site in &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://bugmenot.com/"&gt;http://bugmenot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; and get past the registration! &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. Protect against Viruses&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Use Firefox&#xA0; - Many spyware/malware/viruses have code that targets Internet Explorer.&#xA0; Why not use Firefox instead?&#xA0; It&#x2019;s the web browser that crackers (who make the spyware/malware/viruses) use to browse the web and it stops most pop-up windows, viruses and spyware.&#xD;&#xD;Run AVG - Virus scanners are not equal &#x2013; look for the one that offers the largest virus database and most frequent updates &#x2013; today, that virus scanner is AVG, and its free!&#xA0; Just go to &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://free.grisoft.com/"&gt;http://free.grisoft.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;. &#xD;&#xD;Disable Macros - Macro viruses are the easiest viruses to create &#x2013; after taking a course on Microsoft Office you can make your own&#x2026;&#x2026;.and you can bet every other 12-year-old who takes Office in grade school has figured that out too.&#xA0; Macro viruses can also spread easily in attachments and can go undetected by virus scanners because virus scanners look for a &#x201C;footprint&#x201D; identification and most hackers modify the header of the macro virus to get by this detection (if you change the header, you have a different &#x201C;footprint&#x201D;).&#xA0; In the properties/options of your application (e.g. Office, IE, Outlook), you can usually set an option to warn you if a Macro is run or disable macros altogether.&#xA0; Set one of these options!&#xD;&#xD;Use Linux/Mac!&#xA0; According to Sophos (Antivirus software maker), there are 97,467 active Windows viruses.&#xA0; Linux only has 48 active viruses (most of which require you to run a program as the root user to execute).&#xA0; Old Mac OSes (OS 9 or earlier) have 68 known viruses but most of them are more than 10 years old, and the latest Mac OS (OS X) has a whopping 0 known active viruses.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Scan for viruses even if you use Linux/Mac!&#xA0; Although there are essentially no viruses for these OSes, there are still plenty of Antivirus software programs for Linux/Mac, so why? Well, these programs scan for and remove Windows viruses to prevent them from being spread to Windows computers and infecting them.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Viruses also affect VMWare &amp; VirtualPC images.  If you run a Windows OS in an emulator such as VMWare or VirtualPC, that OS is as prone to viruses like any regular Windows OS.&#xA0; If you run the &#x201C;virtual networking&#x201D; component in these emulators to create a real virtual NIC, this IP is also susceptible to network-based viruses too.&#xA0; I always disable this component &#x2013; you can still use the network, but it will force the traffic to go through the entire TCP/IP stack on the host OS first.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. Protect against Spyware/Malware&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Spyware currently only exists for Windows computers, but is more serious than most viruses.&#xA0; While viruses typically slow your computer or spread themselves to other files, spyware/malware typically changes registry settings to disable system components (e.g. Display properties) or install software that sends or responds to network traffic.&#xA0; Linux/Mac computers run a type of UNIX, so spyware/malware can&#x2019;t be run as a privileged user.&#xA0; Windows Vista (the new XP) has a feature like this called User Account Protection (UAP), but it doesn&#x2019;t work with most spyware/malware.&#xA0; For Windows computers, download and install several different spyware scanners and removers; no single spyware scanner/remover will remove all spyware/malware!&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;4. Don&#x2019;t chat without protection&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Do you realize that anyone with a packet sniffer can obtain your instant messaging chat conversations?&#xA0; To prevent this, download and use encryption software for your instant messaging.&#xA0; There is encryption software for nearly all types of chat programs.  For the MSN, Yahoo, Google, ICQ chat programs, you can use the free SimpLite-MSN program to do this.&#xA0; For iChat, you can use Intego ChatBarrier X3.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;5. Protect your home wireless&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Who knows how many 10-year kids are using your wireless router at home? Hacking wireless and using Snort/AirSnort is a well-known science &#x2013; in fact, there are half a dozen books on it at Chapters!&#xA0; And they are good (I admit, I bought a few, and they ARE good).&#xD;&#xD;Ensure that your Wireless Router has WEP or WPA enabled and that the key length is at least 128 bits with a long passphrase.&#xA0; Although WEP is very good, if you are paranoid, WPA is pretty much uncrackable, but every hour you will notice that it pauses your connection for a few seconds while it generates new keys (which is annoying if you use Remote Desktop continuously like I do).&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;6. Use Protection in Internet Caf&#xE9;s or Public Free Internet Locations&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Do you bring your laptop to a public place that offers free Internet? This access is usually unauthenticated and unencrypted, so if you want to use it, you must use it insecurely!&#xA0; To solve this problem, connect to a third-party web service that provides encryption between your laptop and the web service &#x2013; this web service can then let you browse the Internet freely and no one on the public wireless LAN will see what you are doing.&#xA0; Two examples of these types of services are HotSpotVPN (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://hotspotvpn.com/"&gt;http://hotspotvpn.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;) and T-Mobile Hotspot 802.1x Service (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.t-mobile.com/"&gt;http://www.t-mobile.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;).&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_Entry_1_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
