<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:31:53 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Space Invaders turns 35 years old today&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Wednesday, June 5, 2013&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;On June 5th 1978, Taito unleashed Space Invaders to the world.&#xA0;&#xA0; It promptly chewed up 8 billion quarters within 3 years and popularized the video game industry worldwide!&#xA0; Before Space Invaders, video games = Pong.&#xA0;&#xA0; After Space Invaders, people realized that video games could do much more.&#xA0; Martin Amis puts it best:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;If it hadn&#x2019;t been for Space Invaders, none of us would be where we are today.&#xA0; After Space Invaders, we were defending Earth, against monsters, in sublunar skies.&#xA0; Here they come again. . . . &#xD;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; &#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; -Martin Amis, Invasion of the Space Invaders (1982)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;What makes Space Invaders so important (and why its birthday should be celebrated) is that it inspired so many other people to make video games.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;After Space Invaders came out, companies like Nintendo, SEGA, Konami, Romstar, Namco, Midway, Atari, and dozens of others started making and releasing video games.&#xA0; And they weren&#x2019;t just video games......they were great video games like Pac-man and Galaga that took the industry to a whole new level (pun intended).&#xA0;&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Plus, these video games drove technology to all new heights.&#xA0; A typical home computer of the time had very poor graphics and a single CPU.&#xA0; A typical PCB in an arcade game had several dedicated graphics chips (usually a whole board full of them) and multiple CPUs!&#xA0; The U.S. Military even contracted Atari to build a version of their Battlezone arcade game for tank simulation, citing that video arcade games had more technology than a missile defense system!&#xD;&#xD;That all started with Space Invaders.&#xA0; Not only did Space Invaders popularize video games worldwide, it jumpstarted the industry in 1978 and ushered in &#x201C;The Golden Age&#x201D; of video games!&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;So cheers to Space Invaders - the father of modern video games.&#xA0; I&#x2019;m proud to still have a 1978 Space Invaders cocktail table in my rec room (shown at the top of this post) - not only is it still fun to play, it symbolizes the beginning of the video game industry.&#xA0; After all, back then we were all saving the world one quarter at a time.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="5_Space_Invaders_turns_35_years_old_today_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
