<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>blog</title>
    <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog</link>
    <description></description>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft turns 45</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2020/4/4_Entry_1.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1b3efb80-9312-451d-b639-7ce94d92c5a3</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 4 Apr 2020 07:40:52 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>On April 4th 1975, a small company called Microsoft was founded in Albuquerque, New Mexico. They would later become the most pivotal company in the technology world, and their co-founder Bill Gates would become the world&#x2019;s most prolific philanthropist.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Like many tech companies, Microsoft has had a colourful past. Started by two whiz kids (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Allen"&gt;Paul Allen&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Gates"&gt;Bill Gates&lt;/a&gt;), they started by selling operating system and supporting software. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Xenix UNIX (later sold to SCO) was their first operating system product in 1980, followed closely by MS-DOS in 1981 (which they originally purchased from Tim Paterson). &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After Bill Gates made a deal with IBM to license MS-DOS for their PC line of computers, but retain rights to the software, Microsoft turned into the world&#x2019;s largest software company, making tons of $$.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;But Microsoft wasn&#x2019;t just MS-DOS. The Multi-Tool Word software they created for Xenix later became Microsoft Word - one of the keystones for the Microsoft Office suite that would become the staple of productivity worldwide, overshadowing all competitors. Today, Microsoft 365 (formerly Office 365) is moving much of that productivity to the cloud, where it can benefit from integration with other products (email, SharePoint file hosting, Microsoft Teams conferencing/messaging, and so on).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;While Microsoft Windows and the Microsoft Mouse were both released in 1983, they weren&#x2019;t nearly as common or well-known as MS-DOS. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;However, by the early 1990s, Windows 3.1 was everywhere, and when Windows 95 was released, it became the ultimate symbol of tech coolness. Microsoft followed it up closely with Windows NT 4, which provided a server operating system for companies that evolved into Windows Server.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Microsoft was late to the Internet and TCP/IP bandwagon (Bill Gates was skeptical about its significance early on). However, when they got on board, Internet Explorer was released. And while Internet Explorer sucks today, it was by far the best Web browser of the late 1990s and early 2000s. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Microsoft&#x2019;s focus in the 1990s was on software developers.  By the late 1990s, everyone was developing on the Windows platform, and Microsoft was very very good to their developer community - including game developers. Since the DirectX API was often used by game developers when making PC games, Microsoft decided to enter the game console by putting DirectX in a box (calling it the Xbox) and took a massive chunk of the game console industry away from some pretty big players (Sony, Sega, Nintendo).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;By the early 2000s, Microsoft was a massive organization, and had a lot of bad press. They were constantly under scrutiny for aggressively crushing their competitors. They had security issues with their Windows 9x/2000/XP operating systems (viruses/malware galore). And they were widely hated by the open source (i.e. Linux) community. In 2001, Steve Ballmer (then CEO of Microsoft) called Linux &#x201C;a cancer that attaches itself in an intellectual property sense to everything it touches.&#x201D; They were widely seen as a big evil company in the early 2000s.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Then, around 2010, they reinvented themselves and changed all of that. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Their focus changed to providing cloud services (Azure), and their new operating system (Windows 10) cleaned up their security act in an impressive way. Defender in Windows 10 sends suspicious stuff on your PC to Azure for deep inspection. If it&#x2019;s deemed malicious, a new malware signature is created and sent out to the plethora of Windows 10 PCs on the Internet. Now, 95% of all new malware is first detected and remedied by Microsoft instead of other security companies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;At that same time, Microsoft changed their people and culture. The cut-throat business folks and product evangelists were replaced by progressive, open source-loving thinkers and a new CEO who embodied all of it: Satya Nadella. They&#x2019;ve fought hard to earn the trust of the open source community this past decade, and they&#x2019;ve definitely got it and continue to build on it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Their failed (but noble) attempt to get into the smartphone race alongside iOS and Android with Windows Phone was ditched and replaced by one of the most useful mobile productivity lines: the Microsoft Surface. Microsoft is thinking so intently about what people actually need to be productive, that even Apple (who has since lost their touch when it comes to innovation) is trying to copy the Microsoft Surface with their latest iPad Pro line.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I can&#x2019;t wait to see what they do next.   </description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object001.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2020/4/4_Entry_1.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting the most out of your online course</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2020/3/20_Getting_the_most_out_of_your_online_course.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">f94e65b6-f79a-46ee-a686-aaed606104ff</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 20:52:16 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>The COVID-19 virus has forced colleges and universities in Ontario to quickly move their stuff to an online format to allow classes to continue using social isolation. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As a learner, this means that you&#x2019;ll be immersed in a new learning format that is very different from a physical classroom environment. Both physical and online learning have their own unique advantages, and you&#x2019;ll likely be engaging in both over the course of your career. As a result, it&#x2019;s good to familiarize yourself with online learning sooner than later!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So, how does online learning work?&lt;br/&gt;Online courses are almost always taught with video conferencing software. This could be Zoom, ON24, Microsoft Teams, Cisco WebEx, or one or several others. This software is essentially your home during an online course.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Your college will invite you to join a group for your class in this software, and your instructor will start each class with a video/audio conference call.  You&#x2019;ll be able to hear your instructor speak as they narrate slide decks, or demonstrate program configuration and configuration tasks on their system by sharing their screen to the class. In many ways, the screen sharing functionality of video conferencing software is similar to what your instructor normally does using a classroom projector. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;There&#x2019;s also a text chat feature that allows you to communicate with your instructor and fellow classmates, as well an area for you to obtain files that your instructor shares with you. Usually, your instructor will mute everyone else&#x2019;s microphone while they talk, but can un-mute it during verbal discussions or when you have a question.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;If your computer has a webcam, video conferencing software will allow you to chat visually with your instructor or class in order to ask questions or engage in discussion. However, most instructors disable this functionality at the beginning of each class to ensure that you focus on the material presented.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Most online classes are shorter than physical classes (typically a maximum of 2 hours) to ensure that everyone stays alert. The remaining time is used for discussion or getting individual help performing lab exercises and completing homework tasks that your instructor assigns. At the end of the online class, your instructor will likely share a video of the class that you can watch again.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tests and quizzes may be performed in your video conferencing software, or you may be instructed to connect to your college&#x2019;s learning management system (LMS) to take the test or quiz. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;What should I do to prepare for an online course?&lt;br/&gt;At minimum, you&#x2019;ll need access to a modern computer with a microphone (optional but recommended if you want to ask questions verbally instead of using the text chat feature). Most video conferencing software allows you to connect using a tablet or phone, but for the best experience you should plan to use a computer. If you are in a technology-focused course, your computer should also have enough hardware (memory, CPU, storage) to handle any additional software your need to run in the course.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You&#x2019;ll also need a reliable Internet connection. A basic Internet plan is fine as long as it&#x2019;s high speed. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Next, you&#x2019;ll need to familiarize yourself with the video conferencing software that is used. This may be done interactively with your instructor on the first day of online class, or may be done beforehand using videos or online tutorials that your college has prepared. Don&#x2019;t try to learn every feature of this software. Just focus on the core functionality (the rest can come over time, and only if you find it useful).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Finally, watch your email for important online training details from your instructor!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;What should I do before starting each online class:&lt;br/&gt;There are several tasks that you must do prior to attending an online class in order to get the most out of the experience:&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Unplug any virtual assistants (e.g. Google Home, Amazon Alexa) and make sure your family members aren&#x2019;t playing online games or watching online videos (e.g. YouTube/Netflix) to guarantee Internet bandwidth for your session.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Test your audio. You may need to enable these in your conferencing software and operating system, or adjust their levels. If you have a microphone, turn down the volume on your speakers to a lower level to prevent an audio feedback loop that lowers audio quality. &lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Get a notepad ready. Note taking is still valuable during online education as it allows you to summarize key details that you find valuable, as well as write down questions that you&#x2019;d like to ask your instructor later using your microphone or text chat feature.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Take a bathroom break. Just like you do before going on a long car ride.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Connect to your session 5 minutes early. This allows you to resolve any last-minute connection and audio issues, as well as ensures that you don&#x2019;t miss any important information at the beginning of the class. Don&#x2019;t be John:&lt;br/&gt;                  Me: Glad you could join us John.&lt;br/&gt;                  John: Sorry for being late - the traffic was horrendous.&lt;br/&gt;                  Me: John, this is an online class&#x2026;.&lt;br/&gt;                  John: Yes, network traffic.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Other key things to remember when attending an online class:&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Note and adhere to your instructor&#x2019;s rules of engagement. Your instructor will let you know how and when you can interact during an online course to ensure that everyone has a good online experience. For example, in larger classes your instructor may request that you do not enable your microphone or webcam, and wait until specific times in order to ask questions.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Use online course etiquette. The same rules that apply in a physical classroom environment also apply online. Don&#x2019;t make comments in the text chat that would be considered inappropriate during a physical class.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Dress for a physical class. If your computer has a webcam, you may accidentally start sharing your video if you click the wrong button in your video conferencing software, and your whole class could see you on their screens.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Don&#x2019;t be afraid to participate. You&#x2019;ll get more out of an online class the more you participate with your instructor and classmates. And participating online is much easier than participating in a physical classroom environment. &lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	If you are unable to attend for technical reasons, email your instructor. If you don&#x2019;t email your instructor, they won&#x2019;t know that you were attempting to connect and are experiencing issues. They may be able to resolve it quickly or forward it to college tech support to resolve the issue.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	If you are unable to attend for other reasons, email your instructor. Just as you would in a physical class, you should always let your instructor know when you need to miss a class. They can then send you information and a link to the video of the session to allow you to catch up. &lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	After the class, review the session video and any notes. This will allow you to consolidate key concepts as well as prepare questions that you can ask during the next session.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Stay caffeinated.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object002.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2020/3/20_Getting_the_most_out_of_your_online_course.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips to survive teaching an online course</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2020/3/16_Online_teaching_advice_from_a_veteran.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">fe066a8a-74da-4e4b-aa5d-f4ded3bf0233</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 15:10:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>The COVID-19 virus has forced colleges and universities in Canada to quickly move their stuff to an online format to allow classes to continue using social isolation. One teacher even wrote a funny song about it: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CCe5PaeAeew"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CCe5PaeAeew&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I&#x2019;m luckier than most, since I&#x2019;ve been doing online seminars and classes for a wide variety of different organizations for many years now. Most of these sessions have been Train the Trainer (TTT) classes where I teach a course to other technical instructors worldwide. Apparently I&#x2019;ve gotten so good at it that I was voted best TTT instructor in 2019 by members of the Computing Technology Industry Association (CompTIA), and won their annual award at their summit in Vegas!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And while many &#x201C;How to teach online&#x201D; posts and videos have appeared this past week, none of them I&#x2019;ve seen mention what you &#x201C;actually&#x201D; need to pull it off, so I thought I&#x2019;d offer my take on it here.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;While the physical classroom environment can&#x2019;t be replicated online, there are ways to make an online learning experience great - and it&#x2019;s merely a combination of what you already know with some online-only tips and tricks.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;1. First, you need some tools:&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	A modern computer with a webcam and microphone. Most laptops come with these already, but desktops often do not.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	A reliable Internet connection. A basic Internet plan is fine as long as it&#x2019;s high speed. &lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Video conferencing software. This could be Zoom, ON24, Microsoft Teams, Cisco WebEx, or one or several others. The one you use should have these core features:&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	The ability to do in-person video/audio and screen sharing&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	A chat window&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	The ability to share files&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	The ability to record a session for later viewing&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The video conferencing software is your home online. For your class to participate with you online, you must invite each attendee to your group in the video conferencing software (your organization may instead do this). Next, you start a video/audio conference call at the beginning of each class where students can see you and hear you speak. In this conference call, you can display and narrate a slide deck (e.g. PowerPoint) to students, as well as use or demonstrate programs on your PC that you wish to screen share. You can also screen share your entire Desktop to get the same experience as using a classroom projector (just move any personal files from your Desktop to another location first).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2. Preparing for an online class:&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Explore the video conferencing software as much as possible. Don&#x2019;t try to learn every feature of this software. Just focus on the core functionality (the rest can come over time, and only if you find it useful). Your organization may train you how to use this software, or provide videos that walk you through the configuration.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Design your class around a slide deck (e.g. PowerPoint). This provides a central structure for your class that you can return to. The slide deck should also start with an agenda. &lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Plan to provide continuous visual and audio stimulation at all times. Instead of narrating a particular slide for a long period of time, break the slide up into several smaller slides that you can advance periodically as you talk.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Plan to switch your delivery methods frequently (e.g. every 5 slides). You could switch to a screen share to demonstrate software configuration or open a Web page, or you could introduce a discussion topic or question that students can respond to in the chat window. For example, after discussing the cp command in a Linux course, I may ask students to answer this question in the chat window (give them 30 seconds to respond before taking up the answer):&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;               &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Do what is comfortable for you. When creating custom content for a slide deck, you could create a diagram in a program such as Microsoft Paint if you are quick doing so, or you could just write it on paper, take a picture of it with your phone and add it:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Plan to assign homework tasks or lab exercises each class. Online training should always extend beyond the online presentation component. These tasks and exercises can be reviewed and discussed at the beginning of the next class using the chat window.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Plan for an online session that takes no more than 2 hours. We can only stay focused in an online session for up to 2 hours, which is why it is widely considered the maximum time for online training sessions. If your organization teaches a class for more than 2 hours, you could use the remaining time to help students with their homework tasks or lab exercises using the chat or individual video calling features of your conferencing software.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Plan to provide your students with as much direction as possible. Any detailed information that is easily lost during a demonstration or when a slide advances should be provided to students. This can include hyperlinks, supporting files, commands, and so on. If you share your PowerPoint presentation with your students or record each session, you can put this information in the slide deck itself. Alternatively, you could put this information in a file that you upload to your video conferencing software or send to students in a follow-up email.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;3. Before starting an online class:&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Make sure you eliminate possible audio distractions on your end. This means putting kids and pets somewhere you can&#x2019;t hear them, as well as turning the ringer off on all phones (mobile and landline). Since my dog likes to bark at things she sees outside of my big living room window, I put up a doggy gate at the living room entrance before online training to ensure she can&#x2019;t get to that window.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Unplug any virtual assistants (e.g. Google Home, Amazon Alexa) and make sure your family members aren&#x2019;t playing online games or watching online videos (e.g. YouTube/Netflix) to guarantee Internet bandwidth for your session.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Test your audio and video. You may need to enable these in your conferencing software and operating system, or adjust their levels. If there is audio static, turn down the volume on your speakers to prevent the audio feedback loop. If video is not working, check to ensure that the shutter on your webcam isn&#x2019;t closed. &lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Fill a sealable bottle with water and keep it at your feet. Online training involves more talking than classroom training, so you&#x2019;ll need it if your mouth gets dry.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Take a bathroom break. Just like you do before going on a long car ride.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;4. When teaching an online class:&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Mute all students at the beginning of the session. The amount of background audio feedback from students will prevent you from hearing anything. Most conferencing software has a &#x201C;mute all&#x201D; function, but you may have to mute each student connection individually in the software, or ask participants to mute their own microphones.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Keep it simple and informal. Students feel more comfortable (and hence learn more) in  a casual session.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Focus on the material and the students. While most of what you do will be presenting or demonstrating material, try to interact with your students as much as possible. This means providing regular questions or discussion topics. Periodically pause during your session and ask &#x201C;Does anyone have any questions about ______?&#x201D; and give people time to respond.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Talk slower and watch your chat window continuously for student questions. You could respond to them right away, or periodically (e.g. after you finish a topic or sentence) depending on your teaching style.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Do NOT aim for perfection. This isn&#x2019;t Broadway, and you&#x2019;ll gradually get better and better after doing many more online sessions.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Expect things to go wrong. When they do, give your class a 5 minute discussion break so that you can try to resolve them. Also keep your tech support phone/email handy!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hope this helps!&lt;br/&gt;Cheers,&lt;br/&gt;Jason.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object002_1.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2020/3/16_Online_teaching_advice_from_a_veteran.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to write an academic technical textbook</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2020/2/19_How_to_write_an_academic_technical_textbook.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ce87c815-c6e2-4570-b12b-6670fdfb5e77</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 20:05:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;br/&gt;If you head over to my &lt;a href="../about_me.html"&gt;about me&lt;/a&gt; page, you&#x2019;ll see that I&#x2019;ve written a large number of textbooks over the years for different publishers, as well as worked as a technical editor for many other titles. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Just this past week, I mentioned to a coworker that I&#x2019;ve finished submitting the AU1 of the final chapter for my latest textbook (Hands-On Windows Server 2019, ISBN: 978-0-357-43615-8). &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Their response was &#x201C;That&#x2019;s great, but what is an AU1?&#x201D; I&#x2019;ve written so many textbooks that I take terms like AU1 for granted. In this blog post I&#x2019;ll share the process used to write an academic technical textbook, and give some tips along the way!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The people:&lt;br/&gt;There are several people involved in the development of an academic textbook, regardless of the publisher. And while different publishers vary in the number and type of these roles, most academic authoring projects involve:&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	The author (or authors if multiple people are creating content).&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	A technical editor (TE). The TE reviews everything that the author creates, verifying technical details to ensure that the content is accurate. This involves verifying technical details online, testing URLs, and ensuring that the content is technically sound. &lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	One or more reviewers. Reviewers are often college instructors who teach a course that aligns well with the textbook content. Their main job is to read over the material and identify whether there are areas that they think will be difficult for their students to understand, as well as give their general impressions about content and flow. You can think of reviewers as the private beta testers for a textbook project.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	A copyeditor (CE). The CE is a content editor that checks for grammatical errors and modifies content according to a style guide (a large set of rules for wording consistency and flow created by the publisher). They also review every sentence to ensure readability and comprehension. If there is a sentence that they do not understand, they will ask for clarity. They also check structural elements for consistency. If a sentence refers to a particular figure, key term or concept, they will check the reference to ensure that it is accurate. Copyeditors transform the content into a beautiful and consistent state.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	A project manager (PM). The PM sets and modifies the schedule during the project. PMs typically manage several different authoring projects at the same time.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	A developmental editor (DE). The DE is the central point of contact for all other people in the project (PM, CE, reviewers, TE and author). They distribute files as necessary and provide the communication that keeps everyone updated and on track. They also edit content for structure, flow and consistency before distributing it to others. DEs are often experienced or senior editors that have the background needed to oversee an authoring project. You can think of DEs as the movie directors for a textbook project.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The process:&lt;br/&gt;The steps involved in authoring a textbook are listed below. Each step is given a deadline for completion by the PM in the project schedule:&lt;br/&gt;	1.	Chapters are submitted by the author to the DE. This submission is called an Author 1st (AU1) and is often a Microsoft Word document and supporting figure files. &lt;br/&gt;	2.	The DE sends the AU1 to the TE and reviewers. &lt;br/&gt;	3.	After reading through the chapter, the TE and reviewers add their comments to the chapter (using the Comments feature of Microsoft Word) and send it back to the DE.&lt;br/&gt;	4.	The DE combines all TE and reviewer comments into a single chapter document and edits it for flow and consistency before sending it back to the author.&lt;br/&gt;	5.	The author responds to all TE and reviewer comments, making associated changes (if necessary) before sending it back to the DE as an Author 2nd (AU2).&lt;br/&gt;	6.	The DE sends the AU2 to the CE, who performs an in-depth edit of the content (using the Track Changes feature of Microsoft Word). The CE also adds comments for sentences that need clarification (using the Comments feature of Microsoft Word) before sending the chapter back to the DE.&lt;br/&gt;	7.	The DE sends the copyedited chapter to the author, who accepts/rejects the changes (with rationale) and responds to all comments before returning it back to the DE. &lt;br/&gt;	8.	The DE releases the chapter to the production department, who composites the chapter content (including figures) to produce a finished PDF. This PDF (called the first pages) is returned to the DE.&lt;br/&gt;	9.	The DE sends the first pages to the author for validation. If there are problems with command spacing, figure or information layout, the author will add the relevant notes to the PDF (using the Comments feature of Adobe Acrobat) before returning it to the DE. This is called a page proof (PP).  &lt;br/&gt;	10.	The DE sends the PP to the production department, who fix any problems and create another PDF (called the second pages) that is ready for print.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;It is important to note that steps 1 through 10 are performed concurrently for different chapters on a project. As an author, you may be writing the AU1 for Chapter 5 while you are working on the AU2 for Chapter 3 and PP for Chapter 1. So you&#x2019;ll need to check your schedule often and be comfortable juggling multiple different tasks simultaneously.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The prerequisites:&lt;br/&gt;Every author will tell you that authoring isn&#x2019;t for everyone. Creating content is always more difficult than it looks, and takes time and practice to master. In addition, &lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	You must master the English language and be able to generate structured prose quickly, without having to rewrite it multiple times. If you are an avid reader, you&#x2019;ll likely be a great author. If you need to rely on the Grammarly plugin, then authoring probably isn&#x2019;t for you.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	You must master the associated technical subject matter, as well as be a skilled teacher. Technical concepts must be structured and worded in a way that can be easily understood by readers. As Albert Einstein said, &#x201C;If you can't&#xA0;explain it simply,&#xA0;you&#xA0;don't understand it well enough.&#x201D;&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	You must avoid using idioms that other cultures will have difficulty understanding.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	You must use direct language. For example, use in instead of within, and you will instead of a person will. The third person is for research papers only.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Other tips:&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Planning is the most important part of an authoring project. I often spend 2-3 weeks at the beginning of each authoring project to plan the structure of each major and minor topic for all chapters (including the major tasks performed in each lab exercise).&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Your software setup is vital during a project. Rely on virtual machines, and take snapshots regularly so that you can return to a previous state to test something later on.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Don&#x2019;t use MacBooks to write anything (their keyboards are garbage and you won&#x2019;t get much done). If you have to use a MacBook for vanity reasons, go out and purchase a good USB keyboard to use with it.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Remember that nothing goes smoothly in an authoring project. There will be times where a format or convention change requires that you revisit previous chapters, or times when a TE or reviewer is late submitting material, pushing back other deadlines. Never let these things stress you out, and keep current with each schedule change.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Stay caffeinated. Purchase enough coffee at the beginning of the project to last for about half the project duration, and keep it varied (mostly dark roast). For example, the following is what you&#x2019;ll need for the first half of a 12 chapter textbook:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;How do I break into textbook writing?&lt;br/&gt;I get this question frequently. My response is always &#x201C;Why? Are you a masochist?&#x201D;&lt;br/&gt;But if you possess the right qualities to be a good author, the best way to break into textbook writing is to reach out to an acquisitions editor at a publisher (you can find them on LinkedIn) and let them know your background and areas of strength. In general, new book projects typically go to veteran authors for obvious reasons. However, when a publisher has a need for a book in a new topic area where an existing author is unavailable, you may be offered the book project!</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object001_1.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2020/2/19_How_to_write_an_academic_technical_textbook.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I finally beat Tetris</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2020/1/23_I_finally_beat_Tetris.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9d8c4474-ecd6-4541-ac2d-fd9fe9d8d057</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 16:35:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>I&#x2019;ve finally done it. &lt;br/&gt;I&#x2019;ve beaten the game Tetris.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;More specifically, Atari 2-player arcade Tetris, which is the best version of Tetris ever released (in my opinion) and the one that was available in arcades before Nintendo secured the rights to the game from the Soviet Union.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A few years ago, my daughter and I picked up a Taito arcade cabinet that I restored to play Tetris using the original Atari arcade game printed circuit board (PCB) as shown in the picture to the right: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I accidentally smashed the neck of the CRT monitor when removing it, so I installed a Wells-Gardner arcade LCD (which takes the CGA video signals generated by the Atari Tetris game PCB inside the cabinet), as well as a matching HAPP bezel to make it look great, as shown below.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And I&#x2019;ve played it quite a bit - Tetris has always been one of my favorite games, and is a great way of relieving stress and regaining focus after a long day.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Today, as I was playing around the 50,000 point mark, the screen paused and started jumbling up the characters. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Rebooting the game didn&#x2019;t help. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I put the game PCB in another working arcade cabinet to verify that it was indeed the PCB that had failed.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Yes, that&#x2019;s right. The game PCB died during gameplay, leaving me the clear winner.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Like any game trophy, I&#x2019;m going to frame the PCB and stick it on the wall in my rec room. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As for the Tetris arcade?  Well, it&#x2019;s a good thing I bought a spare Tetris PCB on eBay last year so that I can get my Tetris fix tonight ;-)</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object001_2.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2020/1/23_I_finally_beat_Tetris.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2019 in review...</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2019/12/22_2019_in_review....html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">60c2c26f-fa7c-4041-81e5-e551e89401b7</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 07:59:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>This year was flat-out awesome! I can&#x2019;t think of many years in the past decade that had the same amount of academic, physical, and personal fulfillment all in one year!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;On the academic side, I presented a 12-week Linux+ webinar series at night to IT instructors worldwide for the Computing Technology Industry Association (CompTIA)&#xA0; Instructor Network. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This, of course, fit well since I just finished writing the 5th edition of my Linux textbook for Cengage (Linux+ &amp;amp; LPIC Guide to Linux Certification). &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The participants loved the series and material I created for them, and I was told it definitely raised the bar for these sessions! And with their votes, I won the Outstanding Train the Trainer award from CompTIA at their summit in Las Vegas!  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Outside of my day job teaching and doing curriculum for our IT programs at the college, I also did a lot of tech editing and reviewing for various Linux books, as well as worked on a lot of development and devops-related projects for several startups and incubators in the Waterloo region. Because I&#x2019;ve done so much of this over the past few years, I get a lot of people wanting me on their team and have the rare privilege of getting to choose what projects I want to work on. So I naturally choose the ones that are the coolest!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Oh, and I&#x2019;m currently writing a book on Windows Server 2019 administration for Cengage. Since it&#x2019;s also published in the National Geographic store, I guess you could say that I&#x2019;m writing a book depicting Windows Server 2019 in its natural habitat ;-) &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;On the computing side, I got an expensive status symbol - the new 16&#x201D; MacBook Pro with the highest available specs (Core i9, 64GB RAM, 8TB SSD) to help make some *stuff* happening at work a lot more palatable.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It&#x2019;s the first laptop from Apple in a very long time that actually has a functional keyboard (with an Esc key!), and proper cooling so that the i9 doesn&#x2019;t thermal throttle. It&#x2019;s probably also the first time ever that Apple listened to customer complains about their products too ;-)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ironically, it&#x2019;s still slower for my devops work (VMs, containers, dev tools) compared to my Thinkpad P52S. Plus the Thinkpad still has a far better keyboard and build quality. My goal now is to fill that storage!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I also received a surprise gift this month from CompTIA with a Raspberry Pi 4 kit. While many of my peers rave about Raspberry Pis, I&#x2019;ve never played with one before. And it was a real eye-opener. They run Linux surprisingly fast. Browsing the Web with Chromium is as fast as on a PC, and 4K content displays perfectly. Plus, the templates for taking advantage of the GPIO port are brilliant, and easy to code around in Python. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;On the vintage computing side, I picked up a couple of really cool ancient UNIX systems. The first one is a &lt;a href="Entries/2019/3/14_SPARCbook_3000ST_-_The_coolest_90s_laptop.html"&gt;SPARCbook 3000ST&lt;/a&gt;, which was a $20K laptop from the 90s that every UNIX geek wanted (it had a SPARC processor running Solaris UNIX). Since it has VGA output, I even did a presentation with it (irony is not dead):&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The second one is an &lt;a href="Entries/2019/11/25_The_secret_to_success_for_working_in_tech.html"&gt;ancient UNIX workstation&lt;/a&gt; with a NS32016 CPU (the first 32-bit general purpose microprocessor) running Genix (BSD UNIX for the NS32016). To my knowledge, this is the only Genix system left in the world! I&#x2019;m currently restoring it to its former glory. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;On the personal side, I still eat well and get plenty of exercise. I walk everywhere and count calories. I ran a marathon in Toronto in May - my feet spent a week recovering, but I loved it! Plus, it definitely helps that I live right next to a running track (you can just see my house in the distance between the trees):&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;But perhaps the coolest part of this year was my taking 4 weeks off this summer to do some amazing day trips with my daughter before she left for Australia for a 1-year work term. We did a lot of hiking, saw a lot of waterfalls, and explored some amazing places all around Ontario, some of them accidental (like the HMCS Ojibwa submarine used to track Soviet vessels during the Cold War).  Plus, I even broke down and bought a Hawaiian shirt like all the hip young people wear ;-)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;While I had a pretty amazing year, I hope that you did too! &lt;br/&gt;Here&#x2019;s to a healthy and prosperous 2020 for everyone!&lt;br/&gt;:wq</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object010.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2019/12/22_2019_in_review....html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reviving an ancient BSD UNIX workstation</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2019/11/25_The_secret_to_success_for_working_in_tech.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">57289765-843d-404c-a8d1-cee292c591ed</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 15:20:21 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>Most people will look at this 3-foot-long behemoth of ancient electronics and wonder why it wasn&#x2019;t scrapped decades ago. But for many of us in the tech industry, these ancient machines are a way to peer into the early days of an industry that has twisted and evolved in leaps and bounds, leaving nearly every player that shaped its landscape forgotten in time.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The machine sitting in my driveway at the top of this post is a workstation from the early 1980s with a NS32016 CPU (the first 32-bit general purpose microprocessor) and a whopping 1MB of RAM. It's running Genix (BSD UNIX for the NS32016) and performs at a speed of 2.5 MIPS. For comparison, a modern AMD Ryzen 7 system performs at over 300,000 MIPS. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The person that gave it to me originally built it for the company he was working for at the time. It was to be a graphics workstation that would compete with the other high-end workstation vendors at the time (Sun Microsystems and Silicon Graphics Inc.).  In many ways, it was a revolutionary design for the 1980s as it used a microprocessor that was heavily influenced by the orthogonal design of the DEC VAX (the leading UNIX platform at the time). It also supported demand paging (which was unusual for that time, but later became the standard in CPUs.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The 40MB hard drive from Computer Memories Inc. is as heavy as a dodge ball, and each circuit board in the computer provides a discrete function. There&#x2019;s a CPU board, a disk controller board, a memory board, and a serial I/O board - all of which plug into a backplane so that they can talk to each other. Together with the myriad of ribbon cables connecting these boards to external components, it&#x2019;s reminiscent of the mainframe systems that wandered the Earth in the 1960s.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To get UNIX started on it, and interface with it from a computer terminal requires that you pour though manuals and schematics, ensure that each board is getting the correct voltage and current, as well as connect serial I/O in a way that it expects. It&#x2019;s sort of like decoding hieroglyphs in ancient Egypt. But the reward is the same - to understand something that was lost to time. But while this computer was lost to history, the UNIX operating system it ran went on to become the most influential operating system of all time, leading to Linux, Android, macOS, iOS and nearly every system you talk to in the cloud.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object003.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2019/11/25_The_secret_to_success_for_working_in_tech.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why you should use technology less</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2019/10/6_Why_you_should_use_technology_less.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4f6aa8b8-10d0-44b2-ab80-092c8d93e0cd</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 6 Oct 2019 18:06:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>Over the past few years, I&#x2019;ve taken to using technology less and less in my daily life. &lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	I leave my phone in the car when going to a party or social event. I&#x2019;ll only fetch it if I want to take a picture, and only after appreciating the moment I&#x2019;d like to capture to the fullest. &lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	When I listen to music on my phone (via headphones) during the long walks I take to get exercise and relax, I don&#x2019;t check my phone at all. If the environment around me is interesting enough, I&#x2019;ll stop the music to take in the sounds around me.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	I limit the time I spend perusing social media to 15 minutes at a time, and only when I&#x2019;m in a relaxed mood, often in the evening. If I&#x2019;m sent an interesting article during the day, I&#x2019;ll quickly post it to LinkedIn/Twitter to share with others who could benefit from it, but not use that opportunity to browse other&#x2019;s posts.&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	When it comes to work commitments, I will call or meet with people when possible, rather than message or email them. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A decade ago, my habits were entirely different:&lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	I was tethered to my BlackBerry smartphone. &lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Social media was a drug addiction, and I had no desire to quit. &lt;br/&gt;	&#x2022;	Personal relationships had to fit my digital lifestyle, and my life was online all the time.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Unfortunately, if you replace the word BlackBerry with an iPhone or Android phone, you&#x2019;ll describe many of the people I know today.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;But why?!?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Jonathan Safran Foer wrote an article in the New York Times 5 years ago that described our increasingly disturbing relationship with technology over the years:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#x201C;Most of our communication technologies began as diminished substitutes for an impossible activity. We couldn&#x2019;t always see one another face to face, so the telephone made it possible to keep in touch at a distance. One is not always home, so the answering machine made a kind of interaction possible without the person being near his phone.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;But then a funny thing happened &#x2014; we began to prefer the diminished substitute.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The problem with accepting &#x2014; with preferring &#x2014; diminished substitutes is that over time, we, too, become diminished substitutes. People who become used to saying little become used to feeling little.&#x201D;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA0;&lt;br/&gt;Technology has tremendous benefits, but when used improperly can become a diminished substitute for the joys of life. I read the article, but it didn&#x2019;t strike a chord with me until a few years later when events surrounding me left me remembering its message. It was then that I started changing my technology views and habits for the better.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I&#x2019;m not alone, however. Until last year, I worked with a brilliant programmer who never had a smartphone. A laptop with Skype provided him the ability to talk with others face-to-face, and an iPad provided portable Internet when needed. At the time, I thought this was absurd, but today I applaud his ability to choose technology that didn&#x2019;t diminish his ability to enjoy life.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I hope this blog post inspires you to refine your relationship with technology to enjoy all that life can give you! </description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object002_2.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog/Entries/2019/10/6_Why_you_should_use_technology_less.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <iweb:dateFormat>EEEE, MMMM d, y</iweb:dateFormat>
    <iweb:baseURL>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/Jason_Eckert_Homepage/blog</iweb:baseURL>
    <iweb:maximumSummaryItems>8</iweb:maximumSummaryItems>
  </channel>
</rss>
