<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200627" date="2020-06-28 02:21:58 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Calling E.T. the worst game ever....&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Thursday, November 20, 2014&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Earlier this year, you probably heard all the hype surrounding the excavation of tons of buried Atari 2600 cartridges from a landfill in Alamogordo, New Mexico. Essentially, the story goes as follows: When the video game industry crashed and burned in 1983, Atari dumped a bunch of worthless stock in a landfill in Alamogordo, New Mexico. Although it was covered in the local newspaper, many people have since labelled the story as urban legend. Moreover, it was assumed that most of these cartridges were Atari 2600 E.T. cartridges, because the flop of the Atari 2600 E.T. game (since coined &#x201C;the worst video game of all time&#x201D;) is largely blamed for the video game crash of 1983. &#xD;&#xD;Then, in May 2014, a waste expert and film crew sponsored by Microsoft digs up the spot where they were supposedly buried and makes a documentary about it. In the end, they did find tons of buried Atari 2600 cartridges and the City of Alamogordo auctioned many of them off on eBay earlier this month (the first round netted them $37,000).&#xD;&#xD;The &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Atari: Game Over&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; documentary surrounding the whole event just came out and I finished watching it today (it&#x2019;s free on Xbox and at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://video.xbox.com"&gt;http://video.xbox.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; on any PC/Mac).&#xD;&#xD;Long story short - it&#x2019;s a great documentary, and one that really examines why the video game industry failed in 1983 and why it had nothing to do with the Atari 2600 E.T. game. &#xD;&#xD;Some key points from the film:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	By the end of 1982, the home video game market was flooded with too many mediocre games.&#xD;	&#x2022;	In a bid to do a cross-licensing deal with Steven Spielberg, Atari had their star programmer (Howard Scott Warshaw) do the Atari 2600 E.T. game in only 5 weeks in order to get it out for Xmas (normally a game takes 6 months).&#xD;	&#x2022;	The Atari 2600 E.T. game was widely regarded as terrible, and many returned their games to Atari, who had printed millions of cartridges too many and paid Steven Spielberg $22 million for the rights (this hit Atari very hard).&#xD;	&#x2022;	Although the Atari 2600 E.T. game wasn&#x2019;t as bad as other games out there, it was easily labelled as the &#x201C;worst game of all time&#x201D; because it didn&#x2019;t match the expectations of those who loved the E.T. movie, was difficult to play, and didn&#x2019;t make a lot of sense.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Howard Scott Warshaw (who made YARS Revenge, one of the best games of all time) since changed careers many times, and is rarely given credit as a game programmer/designer today.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Less than 10% of the cartridges dug up at the Alamogordo landfill were E.T. cartridges. There were many other titles in there like Missile Command, Defender, and Maze Craze.  &#xD;	&#x2022;	The warehouse that dumped these cartridges didn&#x2019;t do it because of a surplus of E.T. cartridges - they did it because they had too many unsellable Atari 2600 cartridge stock at a time when nobody was buying Atari 2600 cartridges!&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Although I agree with many of the points within the documentary, but I must stress that E.T. really was a terrible game. My mom bought me a copy of it at K-Mart for $1.99 in 1983 (which was a steal since most Atari 2600 cartridges in Canada were still going for $15-20 in 1983). I played it and quickly got frustrated with it - more frustrated than ANY other Atari 2600 game. I kept falling into a pit, which took forever to get out, and never figured out what the purpose/objective of the game was. It really was mind-bogglingly terrible at the time. I became immediately bitter whenever I saw the cartridge laying around in my video game collection.&#xD;&#xD;Was it deserving of the title &#x201C;worst video game of all time&#x201D;? Well.....there were plenty of other bad video games out there that were just as bad as E.T., but I don&#x2019;t think it all too unrealistic to attach that label to this game in particular. For me, personally, it really was the worst game ever....and obviously other people shared my view for it to garnish the label of &#x201C;worst video game of all time.&#x201D; There were a lot of really bad Atari 2600 games out at the time, and many of them got me frustrated. But none of them frustrated me as much as E.T., and since I loved the E.T. movie, none of them let me down as much as E.T.&#xD;&#xD;So, yes, I wholeheartedly agree that Atari 2600 E.T. is deserving of the title &#x201C;worst video game of all time.&#x201D;&#xD;&#xD;That being said, I don&#x2019;t think that Howard Scott Warshaw deserves any blame - the fact that he was able to create a game in 5 weeks is worthy of praise! The blame lies in Atari&#x2019;s desire to make a game in 5 weeks based on rights they obtained from the movie. Labeling the Atari 2600 E.T. game as the &#x201C;worst video game of all time&#x201D; allows us a stark reminder of what happens when a game company focuses on making money from cross-licensing content rather than focusing on making great gameplay. And we should never forget that lesson in the video game industry.... &lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="20_Calling_E.T._the_worst_game_ever...._files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
