<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RIM on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/rim/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RIM on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/rim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Work-from-home is the new BlackBerry</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/work-from-home-is-the-new-blackberry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/work-from-home-is-the-new-blackberry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;blackberry.jpeg#right&#34; alt=&#34;BlackBerry&#34; title=&#34;BlackBerry&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I vividly remember the first time I was issued a BlackBerry smartphone back in the 2000s for work. I&amp;rsquo;d read emails while in line at the Pita shop during lunch hour, formulating a plan and response before I returned to my desk to reply. For emails that required a quick response, I&amp;rsquo;d hammer out a response on the BlackBerry keyboard while in line. And having access to my Outlook calendar on the BlackBerry meant that I could view, schedule and prioritize my tasks anywhere. There was never any doubt in my mind that it made me far more productive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The future of smartphones</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-future-of-smartphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-future-of-smartphones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sp1.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;SP1&#34; title=&#34;SP1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the picture at the top of this post, last week BlackBerry’s smartphone market share fell to 0% in the global marketplace. In all fairness, this number reflects the number of devices running BlackBerry OS (not the number of BlackBerry-branded Android devices, which together with all other Android devices, comprise 82% of the market).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you think back to 2007, BlackBerry pretty much owned the smartphone world that they created - they were too big to fail, and too proud to accept that Apple and Google could eat their cake.  But 10 years later, they’re a niche company trying to peddle their security and smartphone management software to any Fortune 500 company that still has fond memories of their brand.  It’s a stark reminder of how quickly the tech industry can change, and how unforgiving it can be to those left behind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why BlackBerry failed</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/why-blackberry-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/why-blackberry-failed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;failure.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;failure&#34; title=&#34;failure&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I really didn’t want to do another BlackBerry-related post.  It just doesn’t feel like something that interests me anymore.  But today I decided to do one anyways for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a long-time BlackBerry user and author of their academic textbooks  - as a result, I know their technology inside-out, and have worked closely with the organization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have lived and taught computer science in the K-W region for the past 15 years, so many of my friends and past students have worked for (or still work for) RIM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QNX on a moon rover</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/qnx-on-a-moon-rover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/qnx-on-a-moon-rover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;moon.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;moon&#34; title=&#34;moon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in September 2011, a group of McMaster business and engineering students started a project aimed to build a moon rover that would be run by the QNX operating system on a BlackBerry PlayBook - a Canadian initiative with Canadian technologies (QNX is 100% Canadian). Here is a link to the original article on CrackBerry.com from the beginning of the project: &lt;a href=&#34;https://crackberry.com/forums-new-group-aims-put-blackberry-playbook-powered-rover-moon&#34;&gt;https://crackberry.com/forums-new-group-aims-put-blackberry-playbook-powered-rover-moon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I reached out to them because of that article since I’ve had experience with QNX and PlayBook development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2011 in review</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2011-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2011-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;2011.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;2011&#34; title=&#34;2011&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;personalwork-related-events&#34;&gt;Personal/Work-Related Events:&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started my new job of Dean of Technology in January.  Basically twice the work but the same money.  Most of the time it’s a thankless job (because you have to deal with complaints and bitching from everyone), but there is the odd job perk such as flex time and attending social events and conferences.  I think the best part is that my official job description has a section that requires that I possess Strong communications skills (fluent in English &amp;amp; Klingon), as well as excellent interpersonal, analytical, strategic, conflict resolution, management, and organizational skills (this is what happens when non-geek HR people ask you for feedback in creating your job description).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspective on RIM</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/perspective-on-rim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/perspective-on-rim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always considered myself someone who has a super-natural ability to put things in perspective and explain them to others.  After all, I’ve taught adults for 13 years, and EVERYTHING must be put into perspective when you teach adults ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, it is difficult to put a large situation in perspective when you are too close to the action (for lack of a better phrase).  And I’ve been close to RIM for many years both physically (I live 15 minutes from the RIM headquarters in Canada) and mentally (I’ve dealt with them for years on the academic program front and used their products).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIM is dead. Long live RIM.</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/rim-is-dead-long-live-rim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/rim-is-dead-long-live-rim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;rimdead.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;RIM&#34; title=&#34;RIM&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The worst possible news for RIM right now is a delay in bringing some sort of modern product to market.  In other words, delaying their QNX “killer” smartphone.  But that is exactly what they announced last night - QNX phones won’t be ready until the end of 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem is that they are already behind their competitors with little chance at turning the company around and maintaining a big presence in the smartphone market.  This delay will pretty much cripple their chances of catching up with iPhone and Android.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I threw my back out playing Angry Birds</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-i-threw-my-back-out-playing-angry-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-i-threw-my-back-out-playing-angry-birds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;angrybirds.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;Angry Birds&#34; title=&#34;Angry Birds&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I know this sounds extremely lame, but on Wednesday August 3rd, I threw my back out playing Angry Birds.  And each time I’ve told people that, they’ve either burst out laughing, gave me the quizzical look (as if I’m joking), or simply state something along the lines of “if it were to happen, it would have happened to you.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I definitely plan on telling people that I threw my back out playing Angry Birds at future events (it is a great ice breaker for sure!).  And if they ask about details, I’ll refer them to this post&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlackBerry 950 teardown</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/blackberry-950-teardown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/blackberry-950-teardown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bb950.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;BlackBerry 950&#34; title=&#34;BlackBerry 950&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I was moving the stuff in my desk from the old campus to the new campus yesterday, I found an old BlackBerry 950&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;..so I took it apart and found an Intel FW88386VXSD CPU, which is an embedded version of the famous Intel 80386 CPU (big black chip on the right side of the picture above).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I remember having an 80386 PC that weighed a ton back in 1990, so this is like carrying that PC around in your pocket.  I wonder if it could run Windows 3.1 or Linux (remember that Linus Torvalds first developed Linux on an 80386).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlackBerry then and now</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/blackberry-then-and-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/blackberry-then-and-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bb.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;BlackBerry 950 and 8830&#34; title=&#34;BlackBerry 950 and 8830&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You know - most technologies change drastically over time.  As a result, I got my hands on an old BlackBerry 950 model from 1998 (the 850/950 series were the original BlackBerry smartphones on the 800/900 MHz Mobitex networks, respectively).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem is this:  It really hasn’t changed that much.  Aside from the color and graphics, the BlackBerry 950 running BlackBerry Device Software 2.5 had pretty much the same applications and functionality as the BlackBerry 8830 running BlackBerry Device Software 4.5!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrackBerry Book</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/crackberry-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/crackberry-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;crackberrybook.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;CrackBerry book&#34; title=&#34;CrackBerry book&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I am definitely a CrackBerry user.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a result, when I saw a new book on Amazon called &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CrackBerry: True Tales of BlackBerry Use and Abuse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I simply had to order it and pay the inflated shipping and US exchange rate to have it delivered to Canada. And I am glad I did - it was a hilarious read, and I must admit that I can relate well to the crazy stories within.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
