<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>history on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in history on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The old Web was fun</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/the-old-web-was-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/the-old-web-was-fun/</guid>
      <description>I was around during the birth of the web in the early 1990s and have enjoyed every twist and turn since then. Even before creating my own personal website and blog (this site) in 1998, I maintained the Department of Science website at UW (originally http://sciborg.uwaterloo.ca).
And while I’ve enjoyed watching the evolution of the web, I still think the old web was more fun. In this blog post, I’ll tell you why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft turns 45</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/microsoft-turns-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/microsoft-turns-45/</guid>
      <description>On April 4th 1975, a small company called Microsoft was founded in Albuquerque, New Mexico. They would later become the most pivotal company in the technology world, and their co-founder Bill Gates would become the world’s most prolific philanthropist.
Like many tech companies, Microsoft has had a colourful past. Started by two whiz kids (Paul Allen and Bill Gates), they started by selling operating system and supporting software.
Xenix UNIX (later sold to SCO) was their first operating system product in 1980, followed closely by MS-DOS in 1981 (which they originally purchased from Tim Paterson).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>