<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:57:20 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;My thoughts on developing gadget apps....&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Monday, September 15, 2014&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;We&#x2019;ve definitely seen our share of cool technology gadgets in the last few years, most notably Oculus VR goggles, Google Glass and Android Wear wristwatches.  And with the recent introduction of the Apple Watch, it looks like gadgeteering isn&#x2019;t going away anytime soon.  &#xD;&#xD;Gadgets garnish a large amount of press and blogs, which isn&#x2019;t surprising &#x2013; after all, they represent optimism surrounding technology, and early adopters of these technologies buy them to bask in that optimism.  But when it comes to usefulness, they often fall short.  For example, an Oculus VR demo looks great, but the games just aren&#x2019;t there today because the limitations of Oculus VR technology right now don&#x2019;t allow game developers to release their next great game idea.  Moreover, many technology reviewers (such as John Pozadzides) have detailed why Google Glass is a terrible product with very limited usefulness.  And, of course, everyone should buy an Android or Apple watch with a tiny screen so that you can easily check the time and run small apps&#x2026;&#x2026;.after all, our smartphones can&#x2019;t do that, or do it better, right? &lt;insert sarcasm here&gt;&#xD;&#xD;In short, gadgets weren&#x2019;t necessarily borne out of necessity &#x2013; they were borne out of optimism.  It isn&#x2019;t hard to find the roots of virtual reality, Google Glass, Android Wear and Apple Watch in the Sci-Fi books and movies of the last 50 years.  &#xD;&#xD;However, as an app developer, you have to be cautious about these platforms.  In order to be a successful app developer, you must develop apps that:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Provide a useful function&#xD;	&#x2022;	Have mass appeal (or a large target market) &#xD;	&#x2022;	Are easy to maintain over time &#xD;	&#x2022;	Have an underlying platform with a solid future roadmap&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Unfortunately, when it comes to gadgets, it&#x2019;s very difficult to create apps for them that provide a useful function (until the technology has matured over many years), and if you did, your apps would appeal to the small early adopter demographic.  As with any new technology, the tools are often more difficult to use and the roadmap of the technology is questionable.&#xD;&#xD;This is why most app developers stick with developing for Android and Apple smartphones and tablets.  Smartphones and tables have a myriad of different uses and have become indispensable devices for most people.  Since most smartphones and tablets run either Android or Apple iOS, focusing on developing apps those two platforms makes the most sense as it hits the largest market of users.  &#xD;&#xD;There are some developers that create apps for the latest and greatest gadgets out there, but I suspect their motivation to do so comes from the same technological optimism that early adopters enjoy, rather than from the desire to generate revenue ;-)&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="15_My_thoughts_on_developing_gadget_apps...._files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
