<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>video games on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/video-games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in video games on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/video-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I finally beat Tetris!</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/i-finally-beat-tetris/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/i-finally-beat-tetris/</guid>
      <description>I’ve finally done it. I’ve beaten the game Tetris.
More specifically, Atari 2-player arcade Tetris, which is the best version of Tetris ever released (in my opinion) and the one that was available in arcades before Nintendo secured the rights to the game from the Soviet Union.
A few years ago, my daughter and I picked up a Taito arcade cabinet that I restored to play Tetris using the original Atari arcade game printed circuit board (PCB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 in review</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2019-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2019-in-review/</guid>
      <description>This year was flat-out awesome! I can’t think of many years in the past decade that had the same amount of academic, physical, and personal fulfillment all in one year!
On the academic side, I presented a 12-week Linux+ webinar series at night to IT instructors worldwide for the Computing Technology Industry Association (CompTIA) Instructor Network.
This, of course, fit well since I just finished writing the 5th edition of my Linux textbook for Cengage (Linux+ &amp;amp; LPIC Guide to Linux Certification).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 in review</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2016-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2016-in-review/</guid>
      <description>For the past years, I’ve done a “year in review” blog post, and of course this one is for 2016! It’s a great way to reflect on the events that have happened during the year, and to honest, is actually a lot of fun!
Just a quick disclaimer: I have no intention of talking about the shallow-but-popular celebrity death fixation that has taken over the Internet (must be a millennial thing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Reflections</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/video-game-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/video-game-reflections/</guid>
      <description>The Atari days When it came to video games growing up, my parents were fairly progressive – although they had no desire to play them, they didn’t see them as anything but fun and somewhat educational. And in the early 80s, when home game consoles were all the rage, my parents bought us an Atari 2600 (the all-black “Darth Vader” model shown to the right) and some games.
We lived in a big old house, and there was a very large, unused room upstairs (we affectionately called “the back room”) that was used as the toy/Atari room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 in review</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2015-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2015-in-review/</guid>
      <description>2015 was an interesting year, and one that I really enjoyed!
I spent a lot of time getting/restoring/playing the last few arcade machines that I’ve wanted in my arcade collection - I just love the retro arcade hobby! As a result, I won’t be getting or restoring any more in 2016 at all (I have a few arcades that I want to work on to upgrade, but that’s about it). I’ll be spending most of my time playing them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video game transcendental meditation</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/video-game-transcendental-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/video-game-transcendental-meditation/</guid>
      <description>What is transcendental meditation? Transcendental meditation is the most commonly practiced form of meditation in the world. People who practice it often listen to, or repeat, a particular sound or mantra in order to reach a relaxed state of consciousness. It’s been praised by many for decades as a means of lowering stress and anxiety.
What is a “flow state” within a video game? Video games that require quick thinking, fast reflexes and precision are often difficult to excel at - but with practice, the game can be mastered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014 in review</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2014-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2014-in-review/</guid>
      <description>I think it’s always a good idea each year to reflect on the events that happened during the year - it’s a great way to remember some of the great things that have happened, as well as put some of the not-so-great things that have happened in perspective. If you regularly post to social media (e.g. Facebook or Twitter), looking back on your posts are a great way to revisit the major events that took place during the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Canadian Appathon 4</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/great-canadian-appathon-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/great-canadian-appathon-4/</guid>
      <description>Today, we finished the fourth Great Canadian Appathon - a Canada-wide competition where students from 18 colleges and universities coast to coast compete to create a mobile video game in 48 hours for a chance to win over $35,000! And we hosted a hub at our Kitchener campus again for the whole weekend.
In short, this year&amp;rsquo;s GCA went incredibly well – everyone was pumped and loved the experience! We had students from three different campuses attend the event (Kitchener, Hamilton and London), and all teams managed to complete some amazing games and submit them before the deadline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAME ON 2.0 wraps up!</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/game-on-wraps-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/game-on-wraps-up/</guid>
      <description>All good things must come to an end&amp;hellip;..and unfortunately this also applies to the Game On 2.0 exhibition at the Ontario Science Centre, which ran for the past 6 months (starting March 9th). This Labour Day weekend is the final time that you can check it out as it closes Sept 2nd.
Our college (triOS College) was the presenting sponsor for the exhibition, which, for me was incredible - not only because I run our video game program, created the information for our game development booth, gave numerous Ontario Science Centre talks on gaming topics, and helped organize various game-themed events - but because I’m an avid retro gamer who has many of the same arcade machines and vintage consoles showcased in Game On 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marshall McLuhan was right</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/marshall-mcluhan-was-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/marshall-mcluhan-was-right/</guid>
      <description>Everyone understands, to some degree, the impact that technology has on our lives. However, if you are an avid reader of “idea” books (for lack of a better word), then you also know that some people understand it poorly at best.
Take, for example, the book The Shallows by Nicholas Carr. Carr argues that the Internet has reduced our ability to carefully reason through problems and use our imagination. And plenty of people have taken the time to carefully point out the flaws in his views.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAME ON 2.0 and triOS College</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/game-on-and-trios-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/game-on-and-trios-college/</guid>
      <description>The best technologies are those that spark our imagination. They create a sense of optimism about what “can” be accomplished in the future.
Atari’s Pong was one of the first technologies to do this because it allowed us to interact with our televisions, instead of just watching them. And we started thinking about the types of wonderful interactions that the future would bring to our televisions, video displays, and Holodecks (for the trekkies out there).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving educational change</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/driving-educational-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/driving-educational-change/</guid>
      <description>In the past, education was assessment based - you sat a class, wrote down notes, memorized those notes, and wrote a test based on those notes. The focus was on following this generic structure, and not necessarily on understanding the material or building knowledge in additional areas.
Of course, some kids would understand many of these topics in good depth and be able to relate them to other topics easily - they were labelled the “smart” kids by their peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The best keynote presentation of all time!</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/the-best-keynote-of-all-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/the-best-keynote-of-all-time/</guid>
      <description>Today I attended the annual DIG conference. DIG stands for Digital, Interactive &amp;amp; Gaming, and is essentially a large conference in London, Ontario that brings together the interactive, game, and digital media companies for both networking and educational/informative sessions.
Although this year’s DIG conference was a bit smaller than last year, there were more industry professionals present, and far more meaningful conversation! Instead of the regular “hello&amp;hellip;.what do you do&amp;hellip;.let’s exchange business cards” stuff that normally goes on at these conferences, I got plenty of time to actually have in-depth discussions with dozens of different app and game developers on what was working for them, what challenges they’ve had, as well as their views on the industry and the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Galaga no fire cheat mystery</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/the-galaga-no-fire-cheat-mystery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/the-galaga-no-fire-cheat-mystery/</guid>
      <description>In the classic arcade game Galaga (1981), there is a well-known cheat for those who are patient. If you destroy all of the enemies on Stage 1 except for the left two enemies (shown to the right), then dodge their fire for about 10-15 minutes, they stop firing at you. At this point, you can safely kill them and no enemies will fire at you for the remainder of the game (they can still crash into you to kill you though).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocap in action</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/mocap-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/mocap-in-action/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always been a big fan of Ubisoft games - I remember when Splinter Cell was released for the Xbox - I spent every waking minute of my spare time playing it. I loved the graphics, shading, storyline, stealth gameplay (quite frustrating at times)&amp;hellip;..everything. In fact, I love the whole Splinter Cell series. Best yet, this series is developed almost entirely at the Ubisoft Toronto studio right now.
Ubisoft is located in a dingy area of Toronto, within an old factory building that doesn’t look impressive on the outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A successful hackathon at our Kitchener campus!</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/a-successful-hackathon-at-our-kitchener-campus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/a-successful-hackathon-at-our-kitchener-campus/</guid>
      <description>In August, I worked with our Microsoft Student Partner (MSP) at the Kitchener campus (Mickey) to organize a 3-day Hackathon for creating Windows 8 Metro apps and games using HTML5/Javascript (technically it’s not called Metro anymore). It just took place this past weekend (Sept 7th - 9th), and was a huge undertaking for Mickey and I, but in the end it turned out amazingly well!
The college was very good at coordinating the event (somewhat last minute because of a staff change), and Microsoft was incredibly generous - they provided a ton of food (Tim Hortons breakfast each day, and a big lunch each day), t-shirts, giveaways, prizes (Microsoft ArcTouch mice for the winners, and a Windows Phone for the GoDevMental draw).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcade game CPUs</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/arcade-game-cpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/arcade-game-cpus/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been getting into arcade games pretty heavily this year, and my posts have reflected this for sure ;-) Today’s post is actually a request from John Spitz, who emailed me after reading some of my other video game posts - he wanted to know if there was a typical progression in the types of hardware used in arcade games over the years.
The short answer is “yes” as you can see in the diagram I made at the top of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to properly pronounce Galaga</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/how-to-properly-pronounce-galaga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/how-to-properly-pronounce-galaga/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been getting some heat over the past short while when I talk about my Galaga arcade, because there are 2 different camps when it comes to pronouncing the word Galaga. You can either emphasize the first syllable:
 GAL-a-ga  Or you can emphasize the second syllable:
 ga-LAG-a  I’ve always emphasized the second syllable (ga-LAG-a). However, the Avengers movie came out this year, and Robert Downey Jr. (who plays Iron Man in the movie) pronounced the game as GAL-a-ga when it showed up in the movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide to buying old arcade games</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/guide-to-buying-old-arcade-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/guide-to-buying-old-arcade-games/</guid>
      <description>One of the coolest things to have in your home is a real video arcade game - not only for the nostalgia, but for the massive amount of fun that you, your friends, and your family will have when playing it. A video arcade game can round out a rec room, basement, or garage more than anything else ;-)
I started seriously getting into arcade games last year - I’ve done tons of research prior to actually buying arcade machines for my own home, and I’ve learned a heck of a lot along the way (thank you Internet!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How our video games evolved over time</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/how-our-video-games-evolved-over-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/how-our-video-games-evolved-over-time/</guid>
      <description>I read an article on Ars Technica yesterday that didn’t sit too well with me: https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2012/04/what-ever-happened-to-the-american-arcade/
Now don’t get me wrong&amp;hellip;..I thought it was a great article, and they did a good job of portraying the difference between Japanese and North American culture when it comes to video arcades (which are still very popular in Japan but have pretty much disappeared in North America outside of the Chuck E. Cheese franchise).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2011 in review</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2011-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/2011-in-review/</guid>
      <description>Personal/Work-Related Events:   I started my new job of Dean of Technology in January. Basically twice the work but the same money. Most of the time it’s a thankless job (because you have to deal with complaints and bitching from everyone), but there is the odd job perk such as flex time and attending social events and conferences. I think the best part is that my official job description has a section that requires that I possess Strong communications skills (fluent in English &amp;amp; Klingon), as well as excellent interpersonal, analytical, strategic, conflict resolution, management, and organizational skills (this is what happens when non-geek HR people ask you for feedback in creating your job description).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I threw my back out playing Angry Birds</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/how-i-threw-my-back-out-playing-angry-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/how-i-threw-my-back-out-playing-angry-birds/</guid>
      <description>I know this sounds extremely lame, but on Wednesday August 3rd, I threw my back out playing Angry Birds. And each time I’ve told people that, they’ve either burst out laughing, gave me the quizzical look (as if I’m joking), or simply state something along the lines of “if it were to happen, it would have happened to you.”
I definitely plan on telling people that I threw my back out playing Angry Birds at future events (it is a great ice breaker for sure!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atari 2600 deep dive</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/atari-2600-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/atari-2600-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>One thing that many people don’t realize is that the foundation of the video game industry, including terminology and techniques were solidified in the 1970s and early 1980s during the home video game movement! And the home gaming console that led to the most development in this area was the least technologically advanced one for its time: The 1977 Atari Video Computer System (VCS), later known as the Atari 2600.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History of game consoles</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/history-of-game-consoles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/history-of-game-consoles/</guid>
      <description>It is now more than 30 years since the first real game console (the Atari 2600) was released in Canada. Below is a timeline of each major console, the CPU/GPU they used and any other neat stuff. Basically, you will notice two important trends:
  The console manufacturers love to copy each other - up to the mid-1980s, they mostly had MOS 6502-based CPUs - in the late 1980s and early 1990s, they had Motorola 68000-based CPUs - in the mid-1990s to early 2000s they mostly had MIPS-based RISC CPUs - and today they all have PowerPC-based RISC CPUs and complex GPUs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Arcade Games</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/info/arcadegames/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/info/arcadegames/</guid>
      <description>Growing up in the 80s was awesome! One of the best things about growing up in the 80s for me was that I developed a love of video games. I loved spending time at the arcade playing the classics like Tempest, Missile Command and Galaga. At home, we had an Atari 2600 and later a Nintendo NES. I loved it all.
In recent years, I purchased my absolute favourite arcade games of all time&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Personal Interests</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/bio/personal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/bio/personal/</guid>
      <description>Parenting I am a happily divorced proud father of one. I’ve pretty much raised my daughter since she was 5 years old on my own, and yes, I’ve made school lunches, threw kids parties, went to great places (Ontario Science Centre, ROM, SportsWorld, Storybook Gardens, Disney World and more!), spent vacations camping/cottaging, and watched far too many Land Before Time movies. The picture on the left is my daughter while we were vacationing at Disney World in Florida over a decade ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Books</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/reads/gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/reads/gaming/</guid>
      <description>Martin Amis: Invasion of the Space Invaders (1982) This is probably the most sought-after video game book of the 1980s by the uber-famous, world-renowned author Martin Amis (most copies sell for over $200 today). Martin Amis has a unique way of bringing you back to the video game world of 1978-1982 using verbal imagery and humour - after all, he was a video game addict at the time! Some of the high-resolution colour photos in the book (including the one above) say more than words ever could.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>