<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Your Hiking Experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/hiking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/hiking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;summit.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;Summit&#34; title=&#34;Summit&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved exploring nature on a good hike, whether it be with other people, my dog, or solo. Hiking builds both physique and mental clarity, and the &amp;ldquo;hiker&amp;rsquo;s high&amp;rdquo; is pure bliss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years that have helped me maximize my own hiking experience. Some I learned from trial-and-error, while others I learned from fellow hikers, my own physician, or from online hiking forums. This post summarizes all of them using six tips. You can also find a list of my recommended trails &lt;a href=&#34;../../trails&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GMOs explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/gmos-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/gmos-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bullshit.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;Bullshit&#34; title=&#34;Bullshit&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like many other people who hold a degree in science, I look at people who are currently upset about GMO products with pity and disdain.  They don’t know what it is, but they’re willing to call it evil for whatever reason.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GMO stands for genetically modified organism, which is essentially any organism (plant, animal, amoeba, etc.) that has had its DNA modified in some way.  DNA are the blueprints of a living cell that in turn produce the RNA that produces the proteins that make up the useful bits of the cell itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3. Personal Interests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bio/personal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bio/personal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;parenting&#34;&gt;Parenting&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am a happily divorced proud father of one. I’ve pretty much raised my daughter since she was 5 years old on my own, and yes, I’ve made school lunches, threw kids parties, went to great places (Ontario Science Centre, ROM, SportsWorld, Storybook Gardens, Disney World and more!), spent vacations camping/cottaging, and watched far too many Land Before Time movies. The picture on the left is my daughter while we were vacationing at Disney World in Florida over a decade ago. Now that my daughter is grown up, I miss those years. But she recently became a parent herself, so in a few years I&amp;rsquo;ll likely be doing some of those things as a grandparent. After my daughter moved out of the house, my adorable dog Pepper and I went on many more amazing adventures until she &lt;a href=&#34;../../myblog/remembering-pepper/&#34;&gt;passed away at the age of 13&lt;/a&gt;. I am incredibly grateful to have been a dad to both my daughter and Pepper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7. Three Unconventional Tips for Career Success</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/info/gradspeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/info/gradspeech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;success.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;career success&#34; title=&#34;career success&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-dont-turn-down-an-opportunity-because-it-isnt-the-job-you-want&#34;&gt;1. Don&amp;rsquo;t turn down an opportunity because it isn&amp;rsquo;t the job you want&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Career progression is never a straight line, and good opportunities don&amp;rsquo;t actually have the words &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;good opportunity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; written in bold letters on them &amp;ndash; you never know where they will lead you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, back around the year 2000 I was asked to teach a corporate Linux course on the weekends. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to give up my weekends for a month, and quite frankly I thought it would be a boring waste of my abilities and time. But I did it anyways, and one of the amazing students in my class worked for Compaq and introduced me to SHARCnet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-Fiction &amp; Biographies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reads/non-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reads/non-fiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;rms.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rms&#34; title=&#34;rms&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;clifford-stoll-the-cuckoos-egg-1989&#34;&gt;Clifford Stoll: The Cuckoo’s Egg (1989)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don’t let the year of this book fool you - it’s probably the best book on computing security. The epilogue is both timeless, and an amazing reflection on the purpose of computer security. Moreover, this book is a very enjoyable read. Cliff, like most of us computer/scientist types, writes with a quirky sense of humour, and isn’t afraid to relay his personal views within the book. For example, the quote below describes Cliff’s colleague Dave when he notices that the hacker used the –f option to the ps command on a Berkeley UNIX system (Berkeley UNIX doesn’t use the –f option, only AT&amp;amp;T UNIX does): &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We’re watching someone who’s never used Berkeley Unix.” He sucked in his breath and whispered, “A heathen.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
