<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>science on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in science on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GMOs explained</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/gmos-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/gmos-explained/</guid>
      <description>Like many other people who hold a degree in science, I look at those poor bastards who are currently upset about GMO products with pity and disdain. They don’t know what it is, but they’re willing to call it evil for whatever reason.
GMO stands for genetically modified organism, which is essentially any organism (plant, animal, amoeba, etc.) that has had its DNA modified in some way. DNA are the blueprints of a living cell that in turn produce the RNA that produces the proteins that make up the useful bits of the cell itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Personal Interests</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/personal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/personal/</guid>
      <description>Parenting I am a happily divorced proud father of one. I’ve pretty much raised my daughter since she was 5 years old on my own, and yes, I’ve made school lunches, threw kids parties, went to great places (Ontario Science Centre, ROM, SportsWorld, Storybook Gardens, Disney World and more!), spent vacations camping/cottaging, and watched far too many Land Before Time movies. The picture on the left is my daughter while we were vacationing at Disney World in Florida over a decade ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Fiction &amp; Biographies</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/reads/non-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/reads/non-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Clifford Stoll: The Cuckoo’s Egg (1989) Don’t let the year of this book fool you - it’s probably the best book on computing security. The epilogue is both timeless, and an amazing reflection on the purpose of computer security. Moreover, this book is a very enjoyable read. Cliff, like most of us computer/scientist types, writes with a quirky sense of humour, and isn’t afraid to relay his personal views within the book.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>