<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BlackBerry on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/blackberry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BlackBerry on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/tags/blackberry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspective on RIM</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/perspective-on-rim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/perspective-on-rim/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always considered myself someone who has a super-natural ability to put things in perspective and explain them to others. After all, I’ve taught adults for 13 years, and EVERYTHING must be put into perspective when you teach adults ;-)
However, it is difficult to put a large situation in perspective when you are too close to the action (for lack of a better phrase). And I’ve been close to RIM for many years both physically (I live 15 minutes from the RIM headquarters in Canada) and mentally (I’ve dealt with them for years on the academic program front and used their products).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIM is dead. Long live RIM.</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/rim-is-dead-long-live-rim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/rim-is-dead-long-live-rim/</guid>
      <description>The worst possible news for RIM right now is a delay in bringing some sort of modern product to market. In other words, delaying their QNX “killer” smartphone. But that is exactly what they announced last night - QNX phones won’t be ready until the end of 2012.
The problem is that they are already behind their competitors with little chance at turning the company around and maintaining a big presence in the smartphone market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I threw my back out playing Angry Birds</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/how-i-threw-my-back-out-playing-angry-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/how-i-threw-my-back-out-playing-angry-birds/</guid>
      <description>I know this sounds extremely lame, but on Wednesday August 3rd, I threw my back out playing Angry Birds. And each time I’ve told people that, they’ve either burst out laughing, gave me the quizzical look (as if I’m joking), or simply state something along the lines of “if it were to happen, it would have happened to you.”
I definitely plan on telling people that I threw my back out playing Angry Birds at future events (it is a great ice breaker for sure!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BlackBerry 950 teardown</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/blackberry-950-teardown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/blackberry-950-teardown/</guid>
      <description>As I was moving the stuff in my desk from the old campus to the new campus yesterday, I found an old BlackBerry 950&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;..so I took it apart and found an Intel FW88386VXSD CPU, which is an embedded version of the famous Intel 80386 CPU (big black chip on the right side of the picture above).
I remember having an 80386 PC that weighed a ton back in 1990, so this is like carrying that PC around in your pocket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BlackBerry then and now</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/blackberry-then-and-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/blackberry-then-and-now/</guid>
      <description>You know - most technologies change drastically over time. As a result, I got my hands on an old BlackBerry 950 model from 1998 (the 850/950 series were the original BlackBerry smartphones on the 800/900 MHz Mobitex networks, respectively).
The problem is this: It really hasn’t changed that much. Aside from the color and graphics, the BlackBerry 950 running BlackBerry Device Software 2.5 had pretty much the same applications and functionality as the BlackBerry 8830 running BlackBerry Device Software 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CrackBerry Book</title>
      <link>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/crackberry-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://triosdevelopers.com/jason.eckert/myblog/crackberry-book/</guid>
      <description>Yes, I am definitely a CrackBerry user.
As a result, when I saw a new book on Amazon called CrackBerry: True Tales of BlackBerry Use and Abuse, I simply had to order it and pay the inflated shipping and US exchange rate to have it delivered to Canada. And I am glad I did - it was a hilarious read, and I must admit that I can relate well to the crazy stories within.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>