<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:58:49 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;2019 in review...&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, December 22, 2019&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;This year was flat-out awesome! I can&#x2019;t think of many years in the past decade that had the same amount of academic, physical, and personal fulfillment all in one year!&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;On the academic side, I presented a 12-week Linux+ webinar series at night to IT instructors worldwide for the Computing Technology Industry Association (CompTIA)&#xA0; Instructor Network. &#xD;&#xD;This, of course, fit well since I just finished writing the 5th edition of my Linux textbook for Cengage (Linux+ &amp; LPIC Guide to Linux Certification). &#xD;&#xD;The participants loved the series and material I created for them, and I was told it definitely raised the bar for these sessions! And with their votes, I won the Outstanding Train the Trainer award from CompTIA at their summit in Las Vegas!  &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Outside of my day job teaching and doing curriculum for our IT programs at the college, I also did a lot of tech editing and reviewing for various Linux books, as well as worked on a lot of development and devops-related projects for several startups and incubators in the Waterloo region. Because I&#x2019;ve done so much of this over the past few years, I get a lot of people wanting me on their team and have the rare privilege of getting to choose what projects I want to work on. So I naturally choose the ones that are the coolest!&#xD;&#xD;Oh, and I&#x2019;m currently writing a book on Windows Server 2019 administration for Cengage. Since it&#x2019;s also published in the National Geographic store, I guess you could say that I&#x2019;m writing a book depicting Windows Server 2019 in its natural habitat ;-) &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;On the computing side, I got an expensive status symbol - the new 16&#x201D; MacBook Pro with the highest available specs (Core i9, 64GB RAM, 8TB SSD) to help make some *stuff* happening at work a lot more palatable.  &#xD;&#xD;It&#x2019;s the first laptop from Apple in a very long time that actually has a functional keyboard (with an Esc key!), and proper cooling so that the i9 doesn&#x2019;t thermal throttle. It&#x2019;s probably also the first time ever that Apple listened to customer complains about their products too ;-)&#xD;&#xD;Ironically, it&#x2019;s still slower for my devops work (VMs, containers, dev tools) compared to my Thinkpad P52S. Plus the Thinkpad still has a far better keyboard and build quality. My goal now is to fill that storage!&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;I also received a surprise gift this month from CompTIA with a Raspberry Pi 4 kit. While many of my peers rave about Raspberry Pis, I&#x2019;ve never played with one before. And it was a real eye-opener. They run Linux surprisingly fast. Browsing the Web with Chromium is as fast as on a PC, and 4K content displays perfectly. Plus, the templates for taking advantage of the GPIO port are brilliant, and easy to code around in Python. &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;On the vintage computing side, I picked up a couple of really cool ancient UNIX systems. The first one is a &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/E4D6618E-31C5-46AE-8452-E71D1C95D8E3"&gt;SPARCbook 3000ST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, which was a $20K laptop from the 90s that every UNIX geek wanted (it had a SPARC processor running Solaris UNIX). Since it has VGA output, I even did a presentation with it (irony is not dead):&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;The second one is an &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/57289765-843D-404C-A8D1-CEE292C591ED"&gt;ancient UNIX workstation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; with a NS32016 CPU (the first 32-bit general purpose microprocessor) running Genix (BSD UNIX for the NS32016). To my knowledge, this is the only Genix system left in the world! I&#x2019;m currently restoring it to its former glory. &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;On the personal side, I still eat well and get plenty of exercise. I walk everywhere and count calories. I ran a marathon in Toronto in May - my feet spent a week recovering, but I loved it! Plus, it definitely helps that I live right next to a running track (you can just see my house in the distance between the trees):&#xD;&#xD;&#xD; &#xD;But perhaps the coolest part of this year was my taking 4 weeks off this summer to do some amazing day trips with my daughter before she left for Australia for a 1-year work term. We did a lot of hiking, saw a lot of waterfalls, and explored some amazing places all around Ontario, some of them accidental (like the HMCS Ojibwa submarine used to track Soviet vessels during the Cold War).  Plus, I even broke down and bought a Hawaiian shirt like all the hip young people wear ;-)&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD; &#xD;While I had a pretty amazing year, I hope that you did too! &#xD;Here&#x2019;s to a healthy and prosperous 2020 for everyone!&#xD;:wq&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="22_2019_in_review..._files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
