<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200627" date="2020-06-28 02:22:03 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Donkey Kong Remix Review&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, March 18, 2016&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Just over a week ago, I saw a screenshot of something called Donkey Kong Remix (or just &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;DK Remix&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;) in my Facebook feed from Ritchie Knucklez that caught my full attention!&#xD;&#xD;After all, if you are a hardcore retro gamer that loves Donkey Kong, and you see a picture of the Donkey Kong barrel level that looks like the one shown to the right, you can&#x2019;t help but get a little excited ;-)&#xD;&#xD;DK Remix is a remastered version of the Donkey Kong arcade game with new levels and game mechanics made by a fellow Canadian, John Kowalski (a.k.a. sock master).  &#xD;&#xD;It was originally made for the Tandy CoCo 3 computer, but Kowalski ported it to run on the real arcade machine by creating a DK Remix add-on board that you can purchase and affix to your original Donkey Kong arcade board.  This board comes with the DK Remix code, as well as another harder version of the original Donkey Kong game called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;DK Deranged&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  You can choose to play either DK Remix, DK Deranged, or just the original Donkey Kong game.  Your high scores will be saved in all of the games....including the original Donkey Kong game, which wasn&#x2019;t possible beforehand!&#xD;&#xD;The following videos show you the DK Remix gameplay: &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FU3oMOuegB4"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FU3oMOuegB4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;  &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KAlpJQINYls"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KAlpJQINYls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;And this video shows you the DK Deranged gameplay: &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nj28Kn8CDXw"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nj28Kn8CDXw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;Very cool eh?  I thought so, and so I ordered one and installed it in my Donkey Kong arcade machine (hence this review).  &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Installation and Usage:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Once you get the DK Remix add-on board, you simply remove the Z80 CPU from your original Donkey Kong arcade board and insert it into the small DK Remix board (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;as shown in the pic at the top of this post&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;).  Then you insert the whole DK Remix board into the CPU socket on your original Donkey Kong arcade board (there are pins on the reverse of the board that fit into your original Z80 CPU socket).&#xD;&#xD;Once you&#x2019;ve installed it, a service menu comes up when you turn on your Donkey Kong arcade for the first time that allows you to choose what game comes up first, as well as any game (DIP switch) setting.  Switching games is also pretty easy - simply hold the Jump button for 4 seconds while in attract mode. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gameplay:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;DK Deranged is essentially the original Donkey Kong game, but much harder.  Things are faster, there are more fireballs, barrels, and chaos......think of it as Donkey Kong for masochists ;-)&#xD;&#xD;DK Remix is also quite challenging (at least I found it challenging). There are some amazing mechanics in the Remix that are very non-traditional for Donkey Kong (but somewhat refreshing). I'm reasonably good at the original Donkey Kong (my high score is over 400K), but I found that I couldn't use many of my original Donkey Kong tricks in DK Remix. Instead, to get good at the game, you have to learn/adapt to the radically different gameplay and challenges in DK Remix, which are much more random at early levels than on Donkey Kong. This isn't necessarily a bad thing - after all, these learning challenges are what drew us to games like Donkey Kong in the first place, as well as the plethora of NES platformers with similar challenges (e.g. Super Mario Bros).  You get to hard parts in the game where you have to try multiple times to learn the trick or pattern that will allow you to get past that part.  I ended up getting pretty far all things considered, but it involved some serious sweat and a consistent and continuous dose of profanity.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;My Review:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Overall, the DK Remix board is incredibly well made, and the games and menus are very polished.  The modifications to the original Donkey Kong in DK Remix are nothing short of brilliant - if you stuck a bunch of veteran game designers in a room and tasked them with making improvements to Donkey Kong&#x2019;s gameplay, they&#x2019;d probably come up with the same stuff you see in DK Remix.&#xD;&#xD;That being said.....I'll be honest - &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;I don't like the game&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (yes, I said it). &#xD;When I was Googling DK Remix earlier, I remember Kowalski saying something like &#x201C;people either love it or hate it.&#x201D;  I guess I'm part of the latter category.  It's a brilliant remix, just not my cup of tea.&#xD; &#xD;I spent a large chunk of my March Break playing DK Remix and Deranged (many many hours), and after all of that, I just have no desire to play anything but the original Donkey Kong.  I guess I'm sort of a Donkey Kong purist - there is definitely something addictive about the original gameplay that a remix can&#x2019;t replace. &#xD;&#xD;I think what impressed me most about DK Remix is that someone put in the effort to change things up again with Donkey Kong.....but in the end, I think it just makes me appreciate the original Donkey Kong more, and I think that&#x2019;s a good thing.  Plus, having the ability to save high scores in the original Donkey Kong game with the DK Remix board is an amazing feature.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="18_Donkey_Kong_Remix_Review_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
