<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SCO on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/sco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SCO on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/sco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve now been teaching tech for 25 years!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/25-years-teaching-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/25-years-teaching-tech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bookshelf.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;Bookshelf&#34; title=&#34;Bookshelf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month marks the 25th anniversary of my teaching Information Technology (IT) courses for &lt;a href=&#34;https://trios.com&#34; title=&#34;triOS College&#34;&gt;triOS College&lt;/a&gt; in Ontario, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in 1998 I was well on my way to becoming an academic bum that kept on taking university courses forever. But I had a wife and child and needed to think more responsibly. So, as my spring university semester was ending, I applied for an instructor job that my grandmother saw in a newspaper ad and thought I&amp;rsquo;d be perfect for. After an interview and demo teach, I got the job and started the following Monday&amp;hellip; April 20, 1998.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2011 in review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/2011-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/2011-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;2011.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;2011&#34; title=&#34;2011&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;personalwork-related-events&#34;&gt;Personal/Work-Related Events:&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started my new job of Dean of Technology in January.  Basically twice the work but the same money.  Most of the time it’s a thankless job (because you have to deal with complaints and bitching from everyone), but there is the odd job perk such as flex time and attending social events and conferences.  I think the best part is that my official job description has a section that requires that I possess Strong communications skills (fluent in English &amp;amp; Klingon), as well as excellent interpersonal, analytical, strategic, conflict resolution, management, and organizational skills (this is what happens when non-geek HR people ask you for feedback in creating your job description).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end of 2007</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/the-end-of-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/the-end-of-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;woot.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;woot&#34; title=&#34;woot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has truly been an exciting year, and I wish to take a few moments to reflect on some of the most important events of 2007 in geekdom:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Halo 3 being released (I love that game)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft pissing off millions with Vista&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The death of SCO (may they rot in hell)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apple releasing the iPhone and iPod touch (the next generation interface for everything)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the Nokia N810 Internet Tablet running Linux (drool&amp;hellip;.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The wicked witch is dead</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/myblog/the-wicked-witch-is-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/myblog/the-wicked-witch-is-dead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;scologo.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;SCO logo&#34; title=&#34;SCO logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I consider myself to be a very patient person (all things considered) - but one thing that causes me to lose my patience is when I hear of proprietary computer companies that spread FUD (Fear, Uncertainty and Doubt) in order to keep their customers from considering other (and usually much better) technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While Microsoft has been the main purveyor of FUD since the early 1990s, SCO used FUD in an attempt to downplay the Linux operating system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
