<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:42:40 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Giving up Facebook - one month later...&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, November 2, 2018&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Exactly one month ago, I removed my Facebook account after 10 years, including 500 friends and thousands of posts, pictures and comments. You can read why &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/12BF0F02-9173-4AC0-939E-D8CB973074F7"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.&#xD;&#xD;It&#x2019;s been an interesting month for sure!  &#xD;Long story short, I have no plans on ever returning to Facebook. But I&#x2019;d like to use this post to detail what it&#x2019;s like to give up Facebook for anyone thinking of doing it!&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The first week is rough:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	You instinctively go for your Facebook bookmark on your computer or look for your Facebook app several times a day until you realize that &#x201C;Oh yeah - I quit Facebook.&#x201D;&#xD;	&#x2022;	When you tell people that you deleted your Facebook account, most are horrified at the mere thought of the idea (which leads me to chuckle ;-)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The second week is where you are missed by others:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	You occasionally crave a Facebook hit, but not nearly as much as during the first week&#xD;	&#x2022;	You end up checking out other social media more to make up for the void left by Facebook (LinkedIn, Twitter, Instagram, etc.)&#xD;	&#x2022;	A lot of people wonder what happened to you. Some of them contact you using some other means and ask you &#x201C;if everything is alright&#x201D; while others are a little less subtle and ask &#x201C;did you unfriend me on Facebook?!?&#x201D; &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The third week is pretty awesome:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	The cravings for Facebook disappear&#xD;	&#x2022;	Your mind is much clearer/focused - you&#x2019;re not bombarded by skewed ads and posts that show other people&#x2019;s biases, racism, negativity, etc.&#xD;	&#x2022;	You suddenly find you have more time (you still spend time on the Internet, but less time, and reading higher quality stuff)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;And the fourth week? Well, that&#x2019;s when you truly realize quitting Facebook was a great decision!&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="2_Giving_up_Facebook_-_one_month_later..._files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="648px" height="365px"/>
</content>
