<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:33:10 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Why you should use technology less&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, October 6, 2019&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Over the past few years&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, I&#x2019;ve taken to using technology less and less in my daily life. &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	I leave my phone in the car when going to a party or social event. I&#x2019;ll only fetch it if I want to take a picture, and only after appreciating the moment I&#x2019;d like to capture to the fullest. &#xD;	&#x2022;	When I listen to music on my phone (via headphones) during the long walks I take to get exercise and relax, I don&#x2019;t check my phone at all. If the environment around me is interesting enough, I&#x2019;ll stop the music to take in the sounds around me.&#xD;	&#x2022;	I limit the time I spend perusing social media to 15 minutes at a time, and only when I&#x2019;m in a relaxed mood, often in the evening. If I&#x2019;m sent an interesting article during the day, I&#x2019;ll quickly post it to LinkedIn/Twitter to share with others who could benefit from it, but not use that opportunity to browse other&#x2019;s posts.&#xD;	&#x2022;	When it comes to work commitments, I will call or meet with people when possible, rather than message or email them. &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;A decade ago&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, my habits were entirely different:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	I was tethered to my BlackBerry smartphone. &#xD;	&#x2022;	Social media was a drug addiction, and I had no desire to quit. &#xD;	&#x2022;	Personal relationships had to fit my digital lifestyle, and my life was online all the time.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;Unfortunately, if you replace the word BlackBerry with an iPhone or Android phone, you&#x2019;ll describe many of the people I know today.&#xD;&#xD;But why?!?&#xD;&#xD;Jonathan Safran Foer wrote an article in the New York Times 5 years ago that described our increasingly disturbing relationship with technology over the years:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#x201C;Most of our communication technologies began as diminished substitutes for an impossible activity. We couldn&#x2019;t always see one another face to face, so the telephone made it possible to keep in touch at a distance. One is not always home, so the answering machine made a kind of interaction possible without the person being near his phone.&#xD;&#xD;But then a funny thing happened &#x2014; we began to prefer the diminished substitute.&#xD;&#xD;The problem with accepting &#x2014; with preferring &#x2014; diminished substitutes is that over time, we, too, become diminished substitutes. People who become used to saying little become used to feeling little.&#x201D;&#xD;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xA0;&#xD;Technology has tremendous benefits, but when used improperly can become a diminished substitute for the joys of life. I read the article, but it didn&#x2019;t strike a chord with me until a few years later when events surrounding me left me remembering its message. It was then that I started changing my technology views and habits for the better.&#xD;&#xD;I&#x2019;m not alone, however. Until last year, I worked with a brilliant programmer who never had a smartphone. A laptop with Skype provided him the ability to talk with others face-to-face, and an iPad provided portable Internet when needed. At the time, I thought this was absurd, but today I applaud his ability to choose technology that didn&#x2019;t diminish his ability to enjoy life.&#xD;&#xD;I hope this blog post inspires you to refine your relationship with technology to enjoy all that life can give you! &lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="6_Why_you_should_use_technology_less_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
