<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open source on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in open source on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNIX/Linux is now a core skill for anyone working in tech</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-is-now-a-core-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-is-now-a-core-skill/</guid>
      <description>If you had asked me in the 1990s whether most people in the tech world would be using a UNIX or Linux shell to manage their servers, I would have chuckled and said &amp;ldquo;No.&amp;rdquo; But two decades later we find ourselves in a world where 96% of the cloud is comprised of Linux servers running Web apps made with open source frameworks, and the majority of software development is done on UNIX (macOS) or Linux workstations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of technology</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>Technology is a crazy ride, and like that lyric in the Talking Heads song Once in a Lifetime, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;you may ask yourself, well, how did I get here?&amp;rdquo;
If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck, because this post is a no-nonsense, give-me-the-big-picture timeline of what the heck happened in the technology landscape these past 50 years. Of course, not every little detail is in there. Just those that are actually important (in my expert opinion, of course ;-) Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most people don&#39;t want a computer</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</guid>
      <description>In the past few decades, people of all ages across North America have become technology-literate in some way or another. Many of them weren&amp;rsquo;t introduced to technology via desktop or laptop computers, but instead through a smartphone or tablet. Similarly, many desktop and laptop users have switched to using their smartphone or tablet over the past decade to interact with the online world.
After all, smartphones and tablets are incredibly easy to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open does not always mean Open Source</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/open-does-not-always-mean-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/open-does-not-always-mean-open-source/</guid>
      <description>In the technology world today, the term Open is most commonly associated with Open Source.
Open Source refers to software released under a license that gives other software developers access to modify the original Source code that was used to create the software. This, in turn allows other software developers worldwide to quickly identify and fix bugs and security loopholes, as well as make feature improvements to the software. Consequently, Open Source software evolves more rapidly than other (Closed Source) software, and is considered the gold standard for software today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The different faces of open source software</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-different-faces-of-open-source-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-different-faces-of-open-source-software/</guid>
      <description>The term open source has become a household term in software circles. Most people who work with technology in some capacity know that the Linux operating system is open source, as is the Firefox Web browser and much of the software that runs on their Android phone.
However, when it comes to defining open source, most people I’ve talked to aren’t that clear on what it is and how it works, but can often list these three aspects:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dark Side of GNU</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-dark-side-of-gnu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-dark-side-of-gnu/</guid>
      <description>In computing, GNU (which stands for “GNU’s Not UNIX”) started as a project led by Richard Stallman aimed to replace all of the components of the UNIX operating system with freely-developed versions.
It also led to the creation of the GNU Public License (GPL) that protected freely-developed software from being exploited by others. Software released under the GPL is commonly called open source software today, and there are dozens of open source licenses available in addition to the GPL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Open Source Software</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-power-of-open-source-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-power-of-open-source-software/</guid>
      <description>Two decades ago, a piece of open source software I wrote for a Canadian HPC project caught the attention of someone working for NASA JPL, and after a few emails and a call regarding our experience applying it, a modified version of it was used in a small way to help the Mars Exploration Rover (MER) mission involving the rovers Spirit and Opportunity.
With last week’s announcement that the MER mission is officially over, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to know that a piece of software I wrote helped, even if it was in a small way - it made me smile over coffee that morning, and it’s made me smile several times since then!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of smartphones</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-future-of-smartphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-future-of-smartphones/</guid>
      <description>As you can see from the picture at the top of this post, last week BlackBerry’s smartphone market share fell to 0% in the global marketplace. In all fairness, this number reflects the number of devices running BlackBerry OS (not the number of BlackBerry-branded Android devices, which together with all other Android devices, comprise 82% of the market).
If you think back to 2007, BlackBerry pretty much owned the smartphone world that they created - they were too big to fail, and too proud to accept that Apple and Google could eat their cake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux operating system turns 25 years old today</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-turns-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-turns-25/</guid>
      <description>Today marks the 25th anniversary of the Linux operating system!
More specifically, it marks the day that Linus Torvalds announced his new operating system (that was later called Linux) in a newsgroup post:
From:torvalds@klaava.Helsinki.FI (Linus Benedict Torvalds) Newsgroup: comp.os.minix Subject: What would you like to see most in minix? Summary: small poll for my new operating system Message-ID: 1991Aug25, 20578.9541@klaava.Helsinki.FI Date: 25 Aug 91 20:57:08 GMT Organization: University of Helsinki. Hello everybody out there using minix- I&#39;m doing a (free) operating system (just a hobby, won&#39;t be big and professional like gnu) for 386(486) AT clones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario Linux Fest</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ontario-linux-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ontario-linux-fest/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I teamed up with and old friend of mine (Scott Elliott) and went to the Ontario Linux Fest at the Toronto Congress Centre. For those who do not know Scott, he is a VMWare guru (you can join his Southwestern Ontario VMWare user’s group @ www.vmware.com), as well as a master in the 8th layer of the OSI Model (the political layer). Although he won’t admit it, he knows UNIX very well and is an advocate of the Open Source movement even though he works mainly with Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More about Open Source Software and Linux</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/more-about-open-source-software-and-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/more-about-open-source-software-and-linux/</guid>
      <description>In light of the upcoming Ontario Linux Fest, I decided to use this blog entry to reflect on Open Source Software and Linux.
Free Software and the Free Software Foundation (FSF) were pioneered by the famous Richard Stallman. Free Software does not mean “at no monetary cost”&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;..it means that the source code is free to anyone who wants to use it (source code freedom). In the words of Stallman, think “free” as in “freedom”, not “free” as in “free beer”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The wicked witch is dead</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-wicked-witch-is-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-wicked-witch-is-dead/</guid>
      <description>I consider myself to be a very patient person (all things considered) - but one thing that causes me to lose my patience is when I hear of proprietary computer companies that spread FUD (Fear, Uncertainty and Doubt) in order to keep their customers from considering other (and usually much better) technologies.
While Microsoft has been the main purveyor of FUD since the early 1990s, SCO used FUD in an attempt to downplay the Linux operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Richard Stallman talk at UW</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/richard-stallman-talk-at-uw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/richard-stallman-talk-at-uw/</guid>
      <description>On July 6th, Richard Stallman gave a talk at the University of Waterloo regarding copyright and its evils. Although slow at the beginning (perhaps because Richard was still finishing his Pepsi and introducing the features of copyright), it turned out to be a powerful and enlightening educational experience.
I decided not to write a blog about it until I was able to view it again on video after my vacation and make specific notes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
