<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:32:38 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;On being a technologist....&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, November 27, 2016&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;So what does it mean to be a technologist?  Well, that&#x2019;s hard to say, since it&#x2019;s certainly not a defined field of study in academic institutions, or something that is clearly defined in any way otherwise (although Wikipedia lists a bunch of different, unrelated subsets).  &#xD;&#xD;Regardless, the term &#x201C;technologist&#x201D; is often used as a catch-all term for people that work with technology - a gadget blogger on the Internet may refer to themselves as a technologist, as could someone who works as a database server administrator within a company, or an engineer working to create a new hardware device.&#xD;&#xD;But to me, what separates a technologist from anyone else in a technology industry is their &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;ability to make accurate predictions of emerging technologies and technology companies&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, based on these four traits:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	1.	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Technologists have an in-depth knowledge of the underpinnings of technology in general.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;  They are often professionals in some computer or technology-related industry (e.g. IT administrators, programmers, or engineers). Moreover, they are often at the upper end of the talent spectrum in their field, as they need to be able to fully understand a wide range of different technical areas, including cryptography, Internet technologies, software platforms, and so on.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	1.	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Technologists understand the relationship between technology and our social and psychological lives.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;  We often internalize technology that we use to create useful things or augment our personal lives.  For example, my favorite computer that I&#x2019;ve owned, and the one I have the strongest personal connection to, is my 12&#x201D; Apple PowerBook G4 from 2006.  Because of its small size, it could be taken anywhere easily, and I&#x2019;ve used it to write 7 textbooks for various publishers, and well as countless articles and presentations.  It&#x2019;s dented, scratched, and even fell off the roof of my car at one point, but still works like new today.  And I still use it at any presentation I do because the old version of Microsoft Office that it has installed still runs all of my PowerPoint presentations flawlessly.  It&#x2019;s been a great tool for me, and that feature has allowed me to internalize it.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;But our relationship with technology on a social and psychological level goes beyond good personal experiences.  We also often internalize technology that we think &#x201C;could&#x201D; allow us to create useful things, and this often manifests itself in brand loyalty within the technology industry.  &#xD;&#xD;Let&#x2019;s take an example from outside the technology industry to start: I have many friends who are professional musicians. None of them are famous, have money or good jobs.  But they all have a large collection of expensive musical instruments that they feel gives them the potential and possibility of them creating great music one day.  They are in love with the idea of creating great music, and their instruments represent the chance of doing so.  Unfortunately, a famous musician is only driven by their vision to create an end product - the instrument is irrelevant - and this is essentially what separates a professional musician from a famous one ;-) &#xD;&#xD;This same principle is common in the technology industry too, and perhaps the best example is Apple.  Having past success with incredibly useful products such as the iPod, iPhone and iPad, society has equated Apple products with success.  This is why you&#x2019;ll see large numbers of people using Apple laptops in certain places such as Starbucks cafes, university libraries and creative startups or incubators - these people are willing to pay a premium for the romantic idea that they&#x2019;ll somehow be able to make something great simply by having an Apple laptop.  And just like professional musicians, many of them won&#x2019;t, but are in love with the idea of being able to.  &#xD;&#xD;When put into a societal perspective on a macro level, both technology and brand internalization take on very different roles in different markets around the world.  If you&#x2019;d like to learn more about the human connection between technology and our social and psychological selves, read the book &#x201C;The Second Self&#x201D; by Sherry Turkle (1984).&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	1.	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Technologists are always actively digesting the latest technology news without prejudice or bias towards a particular type or brand of technology. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;In other words, they keep their eyes and ears open for anything technology related - this often involves subscribing to a large number of RSS feeds that cover the entire industry.  But more importantly, they must weigh and add context to any useful information - there&#x2019;s no brand loyalty, zealots are never trusted, and focus is placed on the usefulness of technologies at every level.  &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	1.	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Technologists actively recall the outcome of previous events within the technology industry.  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;In other words, technologists must have experience and a good memory, because there are a plethora of historical events in the technology world.  And in the technology industry, history repeats itself frequently - often in very similar ways on a multitude of different levels.  &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Essentially, these four traits allow technologists to identify technology trends (past, present and future), as well as accurately predict whether an emerging technology will succeed, fail, or change form into another technology that will succeed.  It&#x2019;s certainly not a simple process - instead, it&#x2019;s the culmination of digesting a lot of information in an organized and intelligent way in order to get a &#x201C;feel&#x201D; for the industry.  And the only validation that you have as a technologist is whether your predictions came true.   For example, back in 1999, I predicted the massive rise of Linux in the server and embedded markets.  I also predicted the stagnation/shrinking of Microsoft back in 2002, as well as their subsequent reinvention (embracing Open Source technologies) back in 2003.  Later on in 2004, I predicted the rise of Apple, and In 2006, I predicted the downfall of Research in Motion (RIM) and their BlackBerry brand (years later, the CEO of my organization sent me an email with the title &#x201C;You called it years ago&#x201D; alongside a link to a news story).  While most were surprised at the outcome of these events, I certainly wasn&#x2019;t. This year, I predict the stagnation/shrinking of Apple over the next 5 years.&#xD;&#xD;Regardless of whether they call themselves technologists or not, it&#x2019;s important to realize that most people who report technology news are not technologists. They&#x2019;re just technology reporters that don&#x2019;t care about &#x201C;the big picture&#x201D; - instead, they produce headlines and articles that get them the most exposure regarding a current technology. I have many good friends who are technology bloggers and reporters.  They all do a very good job at reporting on current technologies, but on a personal level, they all feel that the technology industry is unpredictable and that there&#x2019;s nothing beyond &#x201C;the here and now&#x201D; when it comes to technology (or technology reporting). They don&#x2019;t have the means or context to analyze technology trends, and often attribute my ability to do so to simple luck or voodoo magic.&#xD;&#xD;But they are wrong.&#xD;The technology industry is very predictable if you know how to listen to it ;-)  &lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="27_On_being_a_technologist...._files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
