<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:32:37 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Hiking with technology&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Saturday, October 22, 2016&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;This past summer, a friend of mine got me hooked on geocaching.  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Geocaching&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; is essentially a GPS-based treasure hunt - someone will hide a small treasure somewhere remote and post the GPS coordinates online for others, and then the race is on to locate the treasure (Cannonball Run-style).  It&#x2019;s a great way to get out hiking with the dog and see some great scenery along the way.  We saw some amazing scenery this summer ;-)&#xD;&#xD;In order to do this, you&#x2019;ll definitely need:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;A backpack.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;  Sometimes you&#x2019;ll travel more than 10km, so you&#x2019;ll need something to hold water bottles, food, etc.&#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;A GPS unit.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;  Get a hiking GPS (don&#x2019;t use the GPS on your phone).  A base model hiking GPS will run you about $100 on sale and can take months of continuous measurements on just two AA batteries.  &#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Good hiking boots and hiking socks.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;  If you go on a hike without good boots, you&#x2019;ll be sore, and the hiking socks are designed to prevent athlete&#x2019;s foot from developing, as well as prevent ticks on local brush from attaching to you.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;However, I should note that a hiking GPS isn&#x2019;t just useful for geocaching.  Another great use of it is for mapping local trails that you frequent so that you can see sights that you wouldn&#x2019;t otherwise see, find alternate trail entry points, and locate key landmarks.  In other words, a hiking GPS can also be used to &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;maximize your hiking experience along local trails&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.&#xD;&#xD;Hiking GPSes can save your trail path - this is called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;trail logging&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, and you can configure your hiking GPS to store your current GPS coordinates every so many seconds or meters (I recommend storing them every few seconds to account for steep trail sections).  These coordinates are saved to a &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.gpx file&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; on your hiking GPS that you can later upload to your computer and overlay on Google Maps using a site such as &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gpsvisualizer.com"&gt;http://www.gpsvisualizer.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;/.&#xD;&#xD;For example, below is an example of where my dog Pepper and I travelled today at the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Puslinch Crown forrest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; near Cambridge, Ontario with labels showing key points-of-interest (about a 6 hour hike at a good pace).&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	 	&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; is small lake in a recessed valley that isn&#x2019;t visible from the main trail (you have to take a side trail down a steep hill and into a boreal forest are in order to see it).&#xD;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; is a planned pine forest with horse trails that is tricky to get to from the main trail, but beautiful when you do.&#xD;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#3&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; is a larger lake with a beach along the south end that is perfect for my dog ;-)&#xD;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#4&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; is a beautiful forest marsh that is only barely visible from the main trail, but also can be gotten to from Sideroad 10S to the right of it (there is a small trail inlet there).&#xD;	 	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#5&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; is another beautiful forest marsh that has an amazing range of Southwestern Ontario bird species (various Grebes, Northern Pintails, Green-winged Teals, Ring-necked &amp; Long-tailed Ducks, various Scaups, Common Goldeneyes and even some Hooded Mergansers).&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Before I used a hiking GPS alongside .gpx mapping on Google Maps, I had no idea that #1 and #5 even existed!  And we often plan our trail hiking by first examining the parts we want to tackle beforehand visually on a map.  For example, if we want to just do a portion of the trail, we&#x2019;ll enter the trail at the pinned entry point a few kilometers under #3.  And if we wish to explore the forest in #2 without having to hike for a long time, we&#x2019;ll typically go to the OnRoute centre on the 401 and take the trail entrance south of the picnic area and follow it until we reach the main branch of the trail and travel east.&#xD;&#xD;Regardless of whether you are a casual trail hiker or someone who wants to have fun with geocaching, technology can definitely be used to enhance your hiking experience.  However, you should &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;NEVER let technology take away from your outdoor experiences&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - when you get to the trail, turn on your hiking GPS, put it in your backpack, and enjoy the trail and scenery.  When you get home, you can take it out and map the results of your travels on Google Maps to plan for the next time! &lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="22_Hiking_with_technology_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
