<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IT on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/it/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IT on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fun Facts About Linux</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-fun-facts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-fun-facts/</guid>
      <description>Below are 26 questions that detail fun and obscure facts about the Linux operating system. Regardless of how much you&amp;rsquo;ve used Linux in the past, there&amp;rsquo;s likely a few or more that you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t know. Try answering each one from memory (or give it a good guess!) and then expand the Show me the answer! section to see if you are correct. PERFECT SCORES WIN A PRIZE!!! If you knew the correct answer to all 26 of these questions off the top of your head, send me an email and I&amp;rsquo;ll send you a link to download a free (yes FREE!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Time I Yoga-Balled an Apple Store Employee</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-time-i-yoga-balled-an-apple-store-employee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-time-i-yoga-balled-an-apple-store-employee/</guid>
      <description>Back in the late 2000s, my teenage daughter and I went to a local mall one weekend to do some shopping. As usual, I insisted we drop into the Apple store before leaving.
The store itself was quite busy. There were people playing with nearly every item on display at the tables near the front of the store, and even more people hovering around those people to catch a glimpse of what they were doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 in Review</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2022-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2022-in-review/</guid>
      <description>2022 was definitely an interesting year. COVID was given far less attention and we started living with it much like we live with the flu virus. Mask requirements were dropped, and many social events have resumed. Crazy COVID conspiracy theories and uproar are distant memories (at least for me).
I&amp;rsquo;m still teaching IT classes remotely, which has resulted in better educational outcomes compared to the physical classroom. Working with operating systems and IT software within virtual machines on home PCs promotes tinkering and resourcefulness while allowing students to continue and expand upon class work at any time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reboot your mind once a day</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/tech-workers-should-meditate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/tech-workers-should-meditate/</guid>
      <description>Any IT sysadmin will tell you that if you don&amp;rsquo;t schedule time for computer maintenance, your systems will schedule it for you. The same is true for the human mind. After all, humans are the most powerful computer out there (and the only one that can be mass produced by unskilled labour ;-)
When starting out in a tech field, we are intrinsically motivated to spend long hours trying to make a name for ourselves - after all, there&amp;rsquo;s no better feeling than mastering a new skill to level up in a knowledge industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISCy business: The long and convoluted rise of today&#39;s dominant computing platform</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/riscy-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/riscy-business/</guid>
      <description>RISC vs CISC Traditionally, most computing platforms were built with the burden of software in mind. To ensure that a software program could be written easily and with fewer instructions, additional circuitry was added to the central processing unit (CPU) to compensate. This was referred to as complex instruction set computing (CISC). CISC architecture is still common today thanks to the x86 architecture used by Intel and AMD CPUs in most workstations and servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How modern open source projects work</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/modern-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/modern-open-source/</guid>
      <description>By definition, &amp;ldquo;open source&amp;rdquo; has little to do with how software is actually created.
Instead, open source refers to how the source code for a software development project is distributed and consumed by software developers working on other projects. It is essentially a blanket term that refers to any software that makes its source code available to others. To be open source, the software project must be released under an open source license, of which there are two main categories: Copyleft and Permissive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Linux Certification Has Evolved Over The Years</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-certification/</guid>
      <description>Because organizations continually adopt new technologies, the need for skilled IT professionals to support those technologies is always increasing. Technology certification has been the most common skills benchmark used for hiring and promotion in the IT industry since the early 1990s, with Linux certification being one of the most sought-after. After all, knowing how to use, configure and administer the Linux operating system is prerequisite for a wide variety of different IT job roles, including server administrators, cloud administrators, devops engineers, site reliability engineers, cybersecurity analysts, penetration testers, and software developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual-booting Asahi Linux on your Apple Silicon Mac</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/asahi-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/asahi-linux/</guid>
      <description>What is Asahi Linux? Asahi (https://asahilinux.org/) is a Linux distribution based on Arch Linux ARM that you can install natively on Apple Silicon Macs with an M1- or M2-based CPU. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it daily as a software development workstation for over 3 months now on an M1 Mac Mini (16GB RAM, 500GB SSD), and it&amp;rsquo;s unbelievably fast. It is 100% funded by Patreon and developed full-time by Hector Marcan with many other contributors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Swag in the Tech Industry</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-power-of-swag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-power-of-swag/</guid>
      <description>What is swag? Simply put, swag is any branded freebie that you get from a vendor, and it&amp;rsquo;s been used for marketing at tech industry events and showcases since the 1970s. Some common types of swag include stickers, mugs, water bottles, pins, luggage tags, plushies, squishies, t-shirts, socks, hats, tote bags, throw blankets, lanyards, sunglasses, lip balm, custom Lego sets, branded card/board games, journals/notebooks, sticky notes, phone stands, USB power banks, cables/accessories, USB thumb drives, and Bluetooth thingy&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>macOS for Linux admins (2022 refresh)</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/macos-for-linux-admins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/macos-for-linux-admins/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my CompTIA blog post All About Linux and Linux+ ( https://www.comptia.org/blog/all-about-linux-and-linux ), Linux is essentially an open-source UNIX operating system. And since nearly all of the concepts, commands and files are identical between UNIX and Linux, anyone who works with Linux could easily administer a UNIX system.
The macOS operating system that runs on Apple computers is a flavor of UNIX. Thus, most of the concepts that you use when administering a Linux system are also applicable to macOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario&#39;s Computer Part 2: The LEXICON Server</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/lexicon-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/lexicon-computer/</guid>
      <description>As I described in my previous blog post, the Burroughs ICON was a very cool UNIX-like computer developed by the Ontario governement for use within schools during the 1980s and early 1990s.
But because ICON computers were all diskless workstations, they were completely useless without a network and LEXICON file server. After all, the QNX operating system and programs that ran memory-resident on each ICON had to first be downloaded from the LEXICON across an ARCNET network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario&#39;s Computer: The Burroughs ICON</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/icon-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/icon-computer/</guid>
      <description>Nicknamed the bionic beaver, the ICON was a Canadian computer funded by the Ontario government and used in schools province wide. It was designed by CEMCorp (Canadian Educational Microprocessor Corporation) and manufactured by Burroughs (later renamed to Unisys). Moreover, it ran the QNX UNIX-like operating system, which was also developed in Canada by two University of Waterloo students. If you took a computer programming course in high school during the 1980s or early 1990s, you likely remember learning C, BASIC or Pascal on the ICON, as well as many UNIX commands that would pay off later in college or university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring the i3 Window Manager</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/configuring-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/configuring-i3/</guid>
      <description>Why use the i3 window manager If you&amp;rsquo;re a Linux user, you&amp;rsquo;re probably using a desktop environment that looks like Windows (e.g. KDE Plasma) or macOS (e.g. GNOME). But these desktop environments use a great deal of resources and are cumbersome when it comes to flexibility and navigation between applications and code. To solve these problems, most software developers and Linux/UNIX administrators install and use a tiling window manager.
While there are many different tiling window managers available, i3 is the most common one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of RISC architecture</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/power-of-risc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/power-of-risc/</guid>
      <description>This part of the 1995 Hackers movie shown above is right on par for the time. After all, by the mid 1990s Reduced Instruction Set Computer (RISC) processors were seen as the future of computing by most in the tech industry.
By using a simplified instruction set, computers with RISC processors at the time could perform tasks in a quarter of the time compared to computers that had a traditional Complex Instruction Set Computer (CISC) processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPARCbook teardown</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/sparcbook-teardown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/sparcbook-teardown/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2019, I picked up a rare SPARC-based laptop from the 1990s running Solaris UNIX (marketed as the ultimate UNIX portable on the Tadpole website in 1997). You can read my blog post on it here: SPARCbook 3000ST: The coolest 90s laptop. It occasionally shows up on Hacker News, and I get plenty of comments whenever I post it on Reddit.
However, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been curious as to the internals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 in Review</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2021-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2021-in-review/</guid>
      <description>While 2020 introduced a slew of changes to everyone&amp;rsquo;s personal and professional lives, these changes were considerably less pronounced for those of us working in tech fields. After all, most software engineering and server/cloud configuration was already performed remotely before the pandemic using long-standing processes/tools. Adapting to online tech teaching in the college was a welcome challenge, and also more relevant for the industry.
As 2020 was ending, we all knew that 2021 would bring vaccine rollouts but not a complete return to normalcy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Quickstart</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/kubernetes-quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/kubernetes-quickstart/</guid>
      <description>Over the past two decades, we&amp;rsquo;ve shifted from running servers bare metal to running them almost exclusively within virtual machines (VMs). More recently we&amp;rsquo;ve seen another shift to running servers within containers. Like VMs, containers are servers that contain a unique filesystem, IP stack and software. But unlike VMs, containers do not contain a full operating system or operating system kernel. Instead they rely on an underlying operating system that runs the container using a container runtime, such as Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing a fast Linux server on an M1-based Mac</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/installing-linux-server-on-mac-m1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/installing-linux-server-on-mac-m1/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest worries that IT users have regarding Apple&amp;rsquo;s new ARM-based M1 platform is the ability to run virtual machines (VMs) of other operating systems using hypervisor software. And while it&amp;rsquo;s possible to run virtual machines of both Windows and Linux operating systems made for the Intel platform on the M1, the performance cost of translating Intel instructions to ARM is high (even with the optimizations Apple has within their M1 CPU).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARM on the desktop is here to stay</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/arm-on-the-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/arm-on-the-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Back in the 1990s, Reduced Instruction Set Computing (RISC) architecture was widely seen as the future. UNIX workstations from Silicon Graphics and Sun Microsystems boasted powerful RISC CPUs at the time, but were prohibitively expensive and died out in the early 2000s as a result. Only the Acorn RISC Machine (ARM) architecture used in low-power devices (e.g. PDAs) survived past the early 2000s, and only because of the rise of mobile devices that relied on battery power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a great time to be a developer</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/it-is-a-great-time-to-be-a-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/it-is-a-great-time-to-be-a-developer/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a developer for over 3 decades. I remember prompt statements in dBASE III, M68k Assembly and those awful Borland tools. Documentation was provided in large printed binders and often left a lot to the imagination.
Things got better in the late 1990s and early 2000s, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the late 2000s when things really started to heat up. Sun Microsystem&amp;rsquo;s early 1990s slogan &amp;ldquo;The network is the computer&amp;rdquo; became a reality with the rise of cloud computing, object storage and slick frontend/backend stacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNIX/Linux is now a core skill for anyone working in tech</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-is-now-a-core-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-is-now-a-core-skill/</guid>
      <description>If you had asked me in the 1990s whether most people in the tech world would be using a UNIX or Linux shell to manage their servers, I would have chuckled and said &amp;ldquo;No.&amp;rdquo; But two decades later we find ourselves in a world where 96% of the cloud is comprised of Linux servers running Web apps made with open source frameworks, and the majority of software development is done on UNIX (macOS) or Linux workstations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity in a Nutshell</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/cybersecurity-in-a-nutshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/cybersecurity-in-a-nutshell/</guid>
      <description>Simply put, Cybersecurity is an umbrella term that encompasses all aspects of computer, network and data security. While Cybersecurity-specific job roles are commonplace in larger organizations, smaller organizations often require that existing IT roles perform Cybersecurity-specific tasks. And since Cybersecurity is only going to grow in importance over time, anyone working in IT should have a solid knowledge of it.
So what does Cybersecurity involve? You can divide cybersecurity into four main areas today:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future looks a lot like mainframe computing</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/mainframe-computing-is-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/mainframe-computing-is-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Mainframe computers, like the IBM one shown above, were the first digital computers that started appearing in big companies during the 1950s. They were room-sized behemoths of circuitry and steel primarily used to generate balance sheets and income statements. And while IBM still sells a small number of mainframe computers today, they only enjoyed mainstream popularity until the late 1980s.
While early mainframes were only accessed by the people who managed it, most mainframes of the 1970s and 1980s ran programs that were accessed by remote users via a dumb terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering the Zen of TrackPoint</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/mastering-the-zen-of-trackpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/mastering-the-zen-of-trackpoint/</guid>
      <description>Lenovo (formerly IBM) ThinkPad laptops are widely known for three things:
An amazing keyboard (often touted as the best for professional work) Rugged build quality (it&amp;rsquo;s hard to kill a Thinkpad: https://youtu.be/OMilj81s9SI) The TrackPoint, which has been standard on ThinkPads since the first model in 1992 What is a TrackPoint? Simply put, it is an alternative to using a mouse or trackpad on laptops. To ensure that your index fingers can easily reach it, it&amp;rsquo;s situated in the middle of the keyboard between the G, H and B keys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The computer that saved Apple</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-computer-that-saved-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-computer-that-saved-apple/</guid>
      <description>The very first iMac model (shown above) was released in 1998, came in one colour called Bondi Blue, and had a semi-translucent case that allowed you to see the components inside. It had a 233MHz PowerPC G3 CPU, 32MB of RAM, CD-ROM drive, and shipped with MacOS 8.1 (soon upgraded to MacOS 9 - the last version before Apple moved to Mac OS X).
While passing by a convenience store in my home town of Hespeler, I muttered in distaste when I noticed that someone had dumped a lot of furniture and various other household items next to the already-full dumpster at the back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seldom discussed tips for working in the tech industry</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/seldom-discussed-tech-industry-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/seldom-discussed-tech-industry-tips/</guid>
      <description>There are plenty of blog posts on the Web that give sage advice for anyone working in the tech industry. However, most of them focus on the same topics: time management, resourcefulness, continuous learning, verbal and written communication skills, caffeine consumption, and so on.
In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss 6 tech industry tips that are rarely discussed online, but that are equally (if not more) important from my experience over the past three decades in this industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Z shell features that will encourage you to switch from Bash</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/moving-from-bash-to-zsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/moving-from-bash-to-zsh/</guid>
      <description>The command line interface on your system is provided by a shell. And while there are dozens of different shells available to choose from, nearly every UNIX and Linux system over the past two decades has used the feature-rich Bash shell as the default login shell.
Although the Bash shell still remains the most common login shell used on UNIX and Linux systems, macOS and a few Linux distributions (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I love teaching online</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/why-i-love-teaching-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/why-i-love-teaching-online/</guid>
      <description>When the pandemic hit earlier this year, schools around the globe quickly embraced online teaching to continue their curriculum. While online teaching wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely new in this space, it certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t the norm. This meant that many teachers had to adapt quickly, as these 2 funny videos illustrate:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CCe5PaeAeew https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zy_y9yOrgxk However, I&amp;rsquo;ve loved every part of this transition because I absolutely love teaching tech courses online.
Grant you, I&amp;rsquo;ve had some practice prior to 2020, as well as a general interest in how the Web could be used for education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of technology</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>Technology is a crazy ride, and like that lyric in the Talking Heads song Once in a Lifetime, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;you may ask yourself, well, how did I get here?&amp;rdquo;
If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck, because this post is a no-nonsense, give-me-the-big-picture timeline of what the heck happened in the technology landscape these past 50 years. Of course, not every little detail is in there. Just those that are actually important (in my expert opinion, of course ;-) Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity in the early 1990&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/cybersecurity-in-the-90s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/cybersecurity-in-the-90s/</guid>
      <description>Back in the late 1980&amp;rsquo;s and early 1990&amp;rsquo;s, I remember collecting MS-DOS computer viruses. I’d download them from an online Bulletin Board System (BBS) and store them on floppy disks in compressed format to prevent them from executing. For fun, some friends and I would occasionally release them on one of our systems to see what they did, and then reinstall MS-DOS afterwards. Most viruses didn’t do very much, but some others (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most people don&#39;t want a computer</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</guid>
      <description>In the past few decades, people of all ages across North America have become technology-literate in some way or another. Many of them weren&amp;rsquo;t introduced to technology via desktop or laptop computers, but instead through a smartphone or tablet. Similarly, many desktop and laptop users have switched to using their smartphone or tablet over the past decade to interact with the online world.
After all, smartphones and tablets are incredibly easy to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open does not always mean Open Source</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/open-does-not-always-mean-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/open-does-not-always-mean-open-source/</guid>
      <description>In the technology world today, the term Open is most commonly associated with Open Source.
Open Source refers to software released under a license that gives other software developers access to modify the original Source code that was used to create the software. This, in turn allows other software developers worldwide to quickly identify and fix bugs and security loopholes, as well as make feature improvements to the software. Consequently, Open Source software evolves more rapidly than other (Closed Source) software, and is considered the gold standard for software today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing difficult shell scripts</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/tracing-difficult-shell-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/tracing-difficult-shell-scripts/</guid>
      <description>Whether you&amp;rsquo;re an IT systems administrator, developer or devop working with Linux/UNIX shell scripts, you&amp;rsquo;re likely going to come across some that are not well documented and difficult to trace (read and understand) as a result.
While these scripts discourage others from tracing them, you can easily trace even the most difficult shell scripts if you follow good tracing procedures. Moreover, by tracing a difficult shell script, you build your knowledge of specific Linux/UNIX components, as well as scripting in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UNIX Philosophy in 2019</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-unix-philosophy-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-unix-philosophy-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week, I did a presentation for WWITPRO that detailed the UNIX philosophy and its relevance today. Given the subject matter, I decided to do the presentation in PostScript on my SPARCbook running Sun Solaris 2.5.1. This blog post details the content of the presentation for posterity!
What is UNIX? Simply put, UNIX is an operating system that was created by Ken Thompson in 1969 that was rewritten shortly thereafter in Dennis Ritchie’s C programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Foo</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ssh-foo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ssh-foo/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I gave a presentation at a local LUG (which is a Linux User’s Group, for anyone who hasn’t heard of those before) on the subject of SSH Foo.
In UNIX circles, we refer to tricks of the trade as “Kung Fu” or just “Fu” (which sounds rude), so it is spelled “Foo” ;-)
In this blog post, I’ll summarize my SSH Foo talk! Be aware that this is not an introduction to SSH, but a more advanced look at some interesting SSH features for those who are already comfortable with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three reasons why incubators breed failure</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/three-reasons-why-incubators-breed-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/three-reasons-why-incubators-breed-failure/</guid>
      <description>These past few years, I’ve provided various types of support for some tech incubators in the Kitchener-Waterloo region where I live (it’s a complex arrangement that I won’t go into within this post, but mostly involves helping people with technology implementation issues related to software). It’s not hard to find tech incubators nowadays - they’ve become quite popular this past decade, and larger cities often have several incubators of various sizes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the cloud grew up around Linux</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-the-cloud-grew-up-around-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-the-cloud-grew-up-around-linux/</guid>
      <description>Open source software has had a powerful effect on computing. When the ARPANET/NSFNET was sold to different companies in the 1990s to create the commercial Internet, nobody expected it to grow as fast as it did. It was the open source Apache Web server running on the open source Linux (and BSD UNIX) operating system that ultimately allowed the Internet to grow quickly and attract the attention of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple guide to git</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-simple-guide-to-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-simple-guide-to-git/</guid>
      <description>Simply put, Git is a version control system that can be used to keep track of the changes that you make to files over time - it allows you to revert files to a previous state, or see who made changes to a file at different times if several people are working the those files collaboratively.
Git was original developed back in 2005 by Linus Torvalds (the creator of Linux) to aid in making changes to the Linux kernel, but has since become the most common open source version control system used today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devops Demystified</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/devops-demystified/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/devops-demystified/</guid>
      <description>Last week, my friend Scott Elliott did a great guest presentation at the college where he talked about, amongst other things, devops. Moreover, I’ve been involved myself in the setup and configuration of two software development workflows (which technically makes me a devop); one was in 2017 for a tech startup in Kitchener, and the other one was earlier this year for a much larger project at the University of Waterloo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halt and Catch Fire</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/halt-and-catch-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/halt-and-catch-fire/</guid>
      <description>Halt and Catch Fire is an AMC television series that ran for four seasons from 2014-2017, and covers the culture and pivotal aspects of the computing industry from 1983 (just after the release of the IBM PC) to 1994 (when the Internet and World Wide Web exploded).
You can binge watch it on Netflix if you like today, and trust me - you won’t be disappointed! Halt and Catch Fire is the best drama I’ve ever seen - an emotional rollercoaster like no other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons I&#39;ve learned from teaching 20 years of IT</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/20-years-of-teaching-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/20-years-of-teaching-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>I actually started teaching on April 13th 1998 (20 years ago today).
It was my final year as a student at the University of Waterloo, and as I was finishing up writing my final exams I realized that I needed to actually go out and get a real job to support my family (I was married with a daughter at the time).
Prior to that, I had worked on some very cool technology projects for various companies (including some big names like Microsoft, DEC and SUN), as well as worked for the University as a Web developer and sysadmin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The history of IT certification</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/history-of-it-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/history-of-it-certification/</guid>
      <description>Nearly everyone working in an Information Technology (IT) field has at least one IT-related certification. This is because IT certification is commonly used as a skills benchmark for hiring and promotion, and it’s been that way for a long, long time.
So where did all this certification stuff start? If you look online, there isn’t even a Wikipedia page that can give you that answer - like many things in the technology world that predated the Internet, it just wasn’t important enough to keep track of in the Internet Age that started in the 1990s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Essentials for SysAdmins</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/powershell-essentials-for-sysadmins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/powershell-essentials-for-sysadmins/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell is essentially a scripting language and shell (command prompt) that you can use on Windows systems. It’s basically Microsoft’s way of getting a powerful UNIX/Linux/Mac-like shell on the Windows platform (long overdue!). The first versions of PowerShell were pretty horrific, but it’s come a long way since then. PowerShell v4 and later is pretty decent (Win10 comes with PowerShell v5). Luckily, PowerShell v4 comes with Windows Server 2012, and since this post is geared towards sysadmins, I’ll focus everything on Windows Server 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft ReFS vs Oracle ZFS - FIGHT!</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/refs-vs-zfs-fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/refs-vs-zfs-fight/</guid>
      <description>In the past, most IT admins have put their faith in systems and SANs (Storage Area Networks) that use RAID (Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks) technology. RAID can be used to combine hard disks together into simple volumes (called RAID-0, or JBOD) that aren’t fault tolerant, but can also be used to create mirrored volumes where both drives are identical in case one fails (called RAID-1), or striped volumes with parity where data is written across several disks with parity information that can be used to calculate the missing data if a drive fails (called RAID-5).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of Information Technology</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/evolution-of-info-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/evolution-of-info-tech/</guid>
      <description>As a Dean for the technology faculties of a private college in Canada, I’m always looking to make our programs more aligned to the industry - my motto is: always look forward and never look back!
However, when it comes to Information Technology (IT), I regularly find that the general perception of IT jobs is stuck in the past by at least a decade. I can’t tell you how many times I’ve met people who think that IT guys are stuck in the back closet of some company doing some menial job, such as re-soldering chips on a computer motherboard much like working on the engine of an old car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eBook pilot</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ebook-pilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ebook-pilot/</guid>
      <description>Here is my class with their new Kindle DXs. Notice the absence of heavy textbooks on the desks!
UPDATE: Unfortunately, while it was cool to carry around all of our textbooks in PDF format on our Kindle DXs, the pilot ultimately led to us not adopting eBooks exclusively. Simply put, many of our students just preferred the ease of printed books. eBooks may become the norm in the future, but probably only when everyone carries a laptop with them, and can access a second monitor for it in the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I created the Internet</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/i-created-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/i-created-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>Complete with blinking light! It&amp;rsquo;s amazing what you can make with a soldering iron and the spare electrical parts you have in your basement.
If you are wondering what the heck I am talking about, just watch the BBC sitcom “The IT Crowd” Series 3 Episode 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War Games shell scripting fun</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/war-games-shell-scripting-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/war-games-shell-scripting-fun/</guid>
      <description>While my daughter and I sat across from each other in Starbucks drinking coffee and PIN messaging each other in Leetspeak using our BlackBerries (yes, I realize how drastically nerdy this is), the thought occurred to us that a simple shell script could easily be used to simulate the War Operation Plan Response (WOPR) supercomputer from the movie War Games (1983).
Anyways, we analyzed the frame-by-frame output from the movie and recreated the output on the Sun Enterprise 450 in my classroom running Red Hat Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to please your IT department</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-to-please-your-it-dept/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-to-please-your-it-dept/</guid>
      <description>When you call us to have your computer moved, be sure to leave it buried under half a ton of postcards, baby pictures, stuffed animals, dried flowers, bowling trophies and children’s art. We don’t have a life, and we find it deeply moving to catch a fleeting glimpse of yours.
Don’t write anything down. Ever. We can play back the error messages from here.
When an IT person says he’s coming right over, go for coffee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Energize IT conference</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-energize-it-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-energize-it-conference/</guid>
      <description>Today, I attended the Microsoft Energize IT Conference at the Convention Centre in Toronto. Having been to many Microsoft conferences in the past, I was reluctant to attend since most of them were a biased propaganda show for sales people and managers.
Energize IT was a typical Microsoft conference: lots of money, free food and swank. When the keynote presentations started, it looked promising. The first few speakers emphasized the need for feedback from the audience such that Microsoft can adapt to the changing needs of their customers, as well as the need for a sense of “community” amongst us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. What do I do?</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/what-do-i-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/what-do-i-do/</guid>
      <description>Besides drinking vast quantities of caffeine, I have taught, developed and managed various Information Technology (IT) and computer programming courses at triOS College in Ontario (Canada) since 1998 in both our college and corporate training divisions.
Back in 2011, I took on a different title of Dean of Technology to salvage our video game programs, and it turned into a more strategic role where I was able to help shape the development of our programs and curriculum in the following faculties:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Tech T-Shirt Slogans</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techshirts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techshirts/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t Anthropomorphize computers. They hate that.
I void warranties
I read your email
Linux isn&amp;rsquo;t magic. It&amp;rsquo;s sudo-science.
Kids: Don&amp;rsquo;t try this at ~
Code poet
Byte Me
I see dead pixels
cd /pub; more beer
No, I will not fix your computer
There is no place like 127.0.0.1
There is no place like ::1
Bow before me for I am root
Dilbert is NOT fiction
It must be user error</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6. Tech Humour and Puns</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techhumour/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techhumour/</guid>
      <description>I feel someone needs to start a house-call backup business where someone could pull up to your home (or business) in a car that has a big NAS box in the back, and then perform off-site backups across Ethernet for a fee. They could call it NASCAR.
If I was Voldemort I would have hidden a horcrux in HP&amp;rsquo;s documentation.
NFTs make excellent gifts. After all, they&amp;rsquo;re GIF certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
