<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IT on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/it/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IT on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Microsoft (Probably) Killed My Snapdragon Dev Kit</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-microsoft-killed-my-snapdragon-devkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-microsoft-killed-my-snapdragon-devkit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;snapdragondevkit.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;Snapdragon Dev Kit&#34; title=&#34;Snapdragon Dev Kit&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in October 2024, &lt;a href=&#34;../windows-on-arm/&#34;&gt;I got my hands on a Snapdragon Dev Kit&lt;/a&gt;. With a Qualcomm Snapdragon X Elite ARM64 CPU (the fastest model!), 32GB of RAM, and a 512GB SSD, it ran Windows 11 for ARM lightning fast. So I made it my daily driver, and it stayed that way until very recently. I even wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;../windows-on-arm-1year/&#34;&gt;review of it one year later&lt;/a&gt; back in October.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 in Review</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2025-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2025-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every December I like to step back and reflect on the past year&amp;hellip; my own personal retrospective. Just as software teams use sprints to learn and improve, I’ve found that looking back helps me stay aligned with the person I want to become. And looking back, 2025 wasn’t just memorable. It was epic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My outdoor hiking footprint grew yet again this year. Each month, I explored new sections of the Bruce Trail and surrounding regions, from beautiful frozen lakes, to winding freshwater streams, glacial moraine forests, and even cliff faces dotted with caves. Some routes were moderately difficult while others pushed my limits with steep elevation changes (including one that ended at a mountaintop tea house!). And the fall colours? Absolutely spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grace Blackwell Desktop Supercomputer: First Impressions</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/grace-blackwell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/grace-blackwell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;dellpromax-gb10.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Dell Pro Max with GB10&#34; title=&#34;Dell Pro Max with GB10&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, NVIDIA caused quite a stir in the data-science community when they announced the DGX Spark: a desktop-sized AI supercomputer. It’s aimed at developers and data scientists who need to prototype, tune, and run AI models locally without constantly relying on expensive cloud hardware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the heart of the DGX Spark is the new GB10 chip, which combines NVIDIA’s 20-core Grace ARM CPU with the Blackwell GPU. Together, they deliver roughly 1 petaflop of AI compute and come paired with 128 GB of memory and 4 TB of fast local storage. The system ships with Ubuntu Linux 24.04, which immediately appealed to my inner UNIX/Linux fanatic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sick of cables? Switch to 5G Home Internet!</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/5g-home-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/5g-home-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;5g-ad.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;5G Home Internet ad&#34; title=&#34;5G Home Internet ad&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using 5G Home Internet for well over a year now, and honestly, I love it. For my lifestyle and day-to-day Internet habits, it has hit the sweet spot between performance, convenience, and simplicity. If you’ve ever wondered whether 5G Internet is a realistic alternative to cable or fibre for your home, I’m going to share the details and my experience in this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows on ARM: One Year Later</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/windows-on-arm-1year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/windows-on-arm-1year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;snapdragondevkit.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;Snapdragon Dev Kit&#34; title=&#34;Snapdragon Dev Kit&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A little over a year ago, I got my hands on a Snapdragon Dev Kit for Windows powered by Qualcomm’s new Snapdragon X Elite CPU, and that inspired me to share &lt;a href=&#34;../windows-on-arm/&#34;&gt;my first impressions of Windows on ARM&lt;/a&gt;. Back then, the platform felt polished but had a few quirks. Now, after a full year of daily use, here’s how it’s held up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year ago, I was curious whether this emerging platform could hold up in day-to-day use, particularly in tech-heavy environments like software development and data science &amp;ndash; for example, creating and running AI models. While the platform felt polished, there were some limitations: hardcore gaming required more than the integrated Adreno GPU, nested virtualization in Hyper-V wasn’t supported, and a few apps were unavailable for ARM, requiring emulation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;hugo.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Hugo title&#34; title=&#34;Hugo title&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-hugo&#34;&gt;What is Hugo?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, Hugo generates websites. More specifically, it creates static HTML, CSS, and JavaScript files from your content and a chosen theme. Your content is written in Markdown, with additional configuration in YAML or TOML. There are hundreds of themes available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;themes.gohugo.io&lt;/a&gt;, most of them freely available under the MIT License.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Think of Hugo as a house builder. The theme you choose acts as a blueprint &amp;ndash; defining layout, size, and structure &amp;ndash; while your content fills in the details: wall colors, trim, and furnishings. Once everything’s in place, the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command builds your site, just like a contractor constructing your house. If you know some HTML, CSS, or JavaScript, you can even modify the blueprints yourself (I did exactly that to add a comment section to my own site, which I describe at the end of this post).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Win10 Is Nearing End-of-Life: What Should You Do Next?</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/win10eol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/win10eol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;win10eol.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Win10 EOL&#34; title=&#34;Win10 EOL&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has officially set the end-of-life (EOL) date for the Windows 10 (Win10) OS to October 14, 2025. This means that as of that date, there will be no more security updates, bug fixes, or official support for most users. While that date may seem far off (I rarely plan what I’m doing this weekend), it’s wise to start planning now, especially if you’re running Win10 on older hardware or aren’t ready (or able) to jump to Windows 11 (Win11).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonstrating the Power of Apple Silicon using Actuated CI</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/arm-ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/arm-ci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;mac_studio.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;Mac Studio&#34; title=&#34;Mac Studio&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you may have read in my previous blog posts, my main developer workstation is an Apple Mac Studio with an Apple Silicon M1 Max CPU. But instead of running macOS on it, I run Linux – specifically Fedora Asahi Remix, which is Fedora Linux for ARM + the native Apple hardware support provided by the Asahi Linux project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I prefer Linux to other operating systems, the main reason I do this is for speed – running Linux natively on my Mac Studio is at least twice as fast for every task compared to running macOS natively on it. Linux is simply faster and more optimized, and it can fully harness the power of the M1 Max.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Janet Jackson&#39;s Denial of Service (DoS) Attack</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/janet-jackson-dos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/janet-jackson-dos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Janet Jackson might not be the first person who comes to mind when you think of a hacker. But she inadvertently created a malicious payload that performed a &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Denial of Service (DoS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; attack on many different hard drive models manufactured in 2005 and later that rotated at a speed of 5400 rpm (rotations per minute).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-did-it-work&#34;&gt;How did it work?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your computer had a 5400 rpm hard drive, all you had to do was play Janet Jackson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OAwaNWGLM0c&#34;&gt;Rhythm Nation music video&lt;/a&gt; and it would unleash an acoustic resonance attack that damaged the hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s Still Your Call: Ethics in the Age of AI</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ethics-in-the-age-of-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ethics-in-the-age-of-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI is rapidly transforming how we work, learn, and communicate. But as it evolves, we face new questions: What decisions should we let AI make? Who is responsible when it gets things wrong? And how do we ensure that the technology reflects – not replaces – our values and ideas?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll explore the ethical dimensions of artificial intelligence (AI) – and ideally, leave with more questions than answers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind the Mac vs PC Rivalry — And Where Linux Quietly Took Over</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/mac-vs-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/mac-vs-pc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;mac-vs-pc.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;Mac vs PC&#34; title=&#34;Mac vs PC&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to computers, most people today use either a Mac or a PC. In this post, I’ll explore how this digital rivalry began, how it shaped modern computing — and how Linux quietly carved out a space of its own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-early-days-roots-of-the-rivalry&#34;&gt;The Early Days: Roots of the Rivalry&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the 1980s, personal computers (PCs) began appearing in homes, schools, and businesses across the world. A wide range of companies entered the market, including Apple, IBM, Tandy, Commodore, Atari, Texas Instruments, and Sinclair. Most of these early machines featured basic text-based interfaces — often just a simple version of the BASIC programming language. But a few notable outliers, like the Apple Macintosh and the IBM PC, ran more sophisticated operating systems that hinted at what modern computing would eventually become.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canada: The Unsung Hero of AI Innovation</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/canadian-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/canadian-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;canada-ai-banner.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Canadian AI Banner&#34; title=&#34;Canadian AI Banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Canada may not be the first country that comes to mind when you think of &lt;a href=&#34;../demystifying-ai/&#34;&gt;artificial intelligence (AI)&lt;/a&gt; and its underlying machine learning (ML) technology. However, Canadians have played &amp;ndash; and continue to play &amp;ndash; a pivotal role in pioneering and advancing the field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, who exactly helped shape the future of AI? Well, there’s one big name that stands out: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geoffrey_Hinton&#34;&gt;Geoffrey Hinton&lt;/a&gt;, a British-Canadian computer scientist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging WSL2 for Systems &amp; Cloud Administration, Cybersecurity, and Software Development</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/wsl2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;desktop.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Win11 Desktop running 3 WSL2 instances&#34; title=&#34;Win11 Desktop running 3 WSL2 instances&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit going on in the Windows 11 desktop pic shown at the top of this post. To see the details, you can pinch zoom the pic if you are on a phone or touchscreen device, or right-click the pic and choose to open it in a new browser tab if you are on a desktop computer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips to Evolve Your Tech Career in the Age of AI</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ai-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ai-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;AI_banner.jpeg#center&#34; alt=&#34;AI banner&#34; title=&#34;AI banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in my &lt;a href=&#34;../demystifying-ai/&#34;&gt;June blog post&lt;/a&gt;, AI is here to stay. It will be something we take for granted in several years as the tools we use evolve to seamlessly accommodate it. Until then, we should still avoid getting caught up in current AI hype, and no &amp;ndash; there won&amp;rsquo;t be future job titles of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI prompt engineer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; once it becomes as ubiquitous as Googling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since AI will overhaul tech-related industries long before others, it&amp;rsquo;s important that tech professionals leverage it as much as possible over the next few years to remain competitive. In other words, AI will not replace humans, but humans who leverage AI will definitely replace those who don&amp;rsquo;t, especially in tech-related industries. Luckily, most tech professionals are well versed in adapting to change and often embrace a &lt;a href=&#34;../growth-mindset/&#34;&gt;growth mindset&lt;/a&gt; that allows them to do so easily. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll outline six tips on how to embrace and leverage AI today in your tech job.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 in Review</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2024-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2024-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to pause and reflect every so often to stay grounded and focused. So, each December I look back on the year&amp;rsquo;s events and summarize them in a blog post. And after doing this again this year, I realize that 2024 was one of reflection, gratitude, and exploration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to go on some epic winter hiking adventures with my dog Pepper in January before she &lt;a href=&#34;../remembering-pepper/&#34;&gt;passed away in February&lt;/a&gt; at the age of 13. Losing a dog is the hardest thing because we form such strong bonds, but she was an amazing dog that had an awesome life and I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for all of it. I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of a pet memorial plaque I saw many years ago that said &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t cry because it&amp;rsquo;s over. Smile because it happened.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; I spread her ashes in the areas she loved most: my back yard, the sports park behind my house, the public park at the end of my street, and in the stream under the bridge my daughter and I often took her to on the Mill Run trail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running an LLM locally using Ollama</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/llms-using-ollama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/llms-using-ollama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are developing or integrating software with a Large Language Model (LLM) to add chatbot or other AI functionality, then you may have the need to host and run an LLM on your local workstation for development or testing. There are several open source LLMs available that you can freely run on your system provided that you have enough resources to do so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LLMs are just inert objects that require special software to allow people and other software to interact with it (called &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;running the model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;). Unfortunately, setting up the software components to run a model is akin to nailing Jello to a tree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing a Fedora Linux ARM VM from a Raw Image</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-arm-raw-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-arm-raw-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many professionals who work in Information Technology (IT) or software development use an ARM-based PC, such as an Apple Silicon Mac, Snapdragon Elite X Windows Copilot+ PC, or an ARM Linux workstation such as the System76 Thelio Astra. Similarly, many students learning IT or software development may also use an ARM-based PC. For all of these people, it&amp;rsquo;s commonplace to deploy Linux virtual machines (VMs) on a PC using hypervisor software to test cloud apps, host server software, or run specialized tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copilot&#43; PC Review: Windows on ARM is finally here</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/windows-on-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/windows-on-arm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;desktop.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Copilot+ PC Desktop&#34; title=&#34;Copilot+ PC Desktop&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in 2017, I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;../get-ready-for-the-chip-wars/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; predicting intense competition between Intel x86-based and ARM-based PCs. And finally, after many years of lukewarm development efforts on the part of Microsoft and Qualcomm, that competition is here with Windows 11 Copilot+ PCs running powerful ARM-based Qualcomm Snapdragon X Elite CPUs with built in graphics and AI acceleration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As shown in the desktop screenshot at the top of this post I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a Copilot+ PC as a productivity and development workstation this month, and I must say that I&amp;rsquo;m thoroughly impressed overall. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll outline why.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Cybersafety for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/cybersafety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/cybersafety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cybersafety.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;Cybersafety&#34; title=&#34;Cybersafety&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Internet is a dangerous place. In this post, I’ll cover five basic Cybersafety tips that anyone (including those who aren&amp;rsquo;t tech-savvy) can use to stay safe online.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-protect-against-viruses-and-malware&#34;&gt;1. Protect against viruses and malware&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most computer &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;viruses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are small sections of code that are embedded into files such as PowerPoint presentations and PDFs. When these files are opened in a software app (e.g., Microsoft PowerPoint or Adobe Reader), the app inadvertently executes the malicious code. Alternatively, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;malware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (short for malicious software) includes apps that often run silently in the background to perform malicious tasks, such as stealing information or encrypting files until you pay a ransom (called &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ransomware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;). As a result, malware is one of the most dangerous threats to computer users today, and many viruses merely download and execute malware from Internet sites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Keep my Linux Textbook Updated for New Versions</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/keeping-linux-books-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/keeping-linux-books-updated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;banner.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;Automation banner&#34; title=&#34;Automation banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back when I wrote the &lt;a href=&#34;../../bio/my-published-books/0-619-13004-0_front.jpg&#34;&gt;first edition&lt;/a&gt; of my Linux textbook in 2002, I spent a massive amount of time planning every detail to ensure it had a strong prerequisite concept flow for those new to Linux usage and administration. I added more content on network services and security in the second edition, and dramatically more in the third edition. The fourth edition introduced Systemd, ZFS, and additional security technologies. The fifth edition added many new server, storage, container, and cloud topics, as well as Git and an appendix that allowed readers to apply their Linux skills to macOS. The sixth edition that was published last year expanded these same topics, as well as added the Z shell, Kubernetes, and another appendix that allowed readers to apply their Linux skills to FreeBSD UNIX. Content-wise, the &lt;a href=&#34;../../bio/my-published-books/979-82140-0080-0_front.jpg&#34;&gt;sixth edition&lt;/a&gt; is arguably the most comprehensive Linux textbook on the market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of RISC-V and Open Hardware</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/risc-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/risc-v/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;risc-v.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;RISC-V banner&#34; title=&#34;RISC-V banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the rise of the Internet in the late 1990s and early 2000s, the software world underwent a paradigm shift towards &amp;ldquo;open source&amp;rdquo; software development. Open source software is any software that is released under a license that gives other software developers access to read and modify the original source code that was used to create the software. In other words, if you publish software under an open source license, you are offering the source code you created to others who can modify it to fix bugs and security loopholes, as well as make feature improvements. Thus, compared to closed source software, open source software evolves much quicker and is more stable and secure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Maintaining a Growth Mindset</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/growth-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/growth-mindset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;growth-mindset.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;Growth mindset&#34; title=&#34;Growth mindset&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in 2020, I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;../seldom-discussed-tech-industry-tips/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; detailing 6 tips for working in the tech industry. And while these tips are sage for any tech worker, there is a 7th tip that applies to life in general: Adopt a &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;growth mindset&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-growth-mindset&#34;&gt;What is a growth mindset?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A growth mindset is a way of viewing challenges and setbacks. People who adopt a growth mindset believe that challenges can always be overcome with time and effort, and that setbacks and failures are valuable learning opportunities that lead to self-improvement and future success. In other words, a growth mindset is a positive, open, and healthy outlook on both learning and life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40 years of Macintosh</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/40-years-of-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/40-years-of-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;apple40.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;Apple 40 years logo&#34; title=&#34;Apple 40 years logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first Apple Macintosh computer was released 40 years ago (January 24, 1984) following an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VtvjbmoDx-I&#34;&gt;epic 1984 Super Bowl commercial&lt;/a&gt; two days earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the first mass-market all-in-one computer with a graphical desktop and mouse navigation, the Macintosh (and the Macintosh brand in general) was positioned to be &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the computer for everyone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;40 years later, the &amp;ldquo;Mac&amp;rdquo; is a household name and Apple is the world&amp;rsquo;s richest company by market cap. But the Mac isn&amp;rsquo;t just a computer, it&amp;rsquo;s essentially Apple&amp;rsquo;s whole line of business. iPhones and iPads run a version of the same macOS UNIX operating system you&amp;rsquo;ll find on your MacBook, iMac, Mac Mini, Mac Studio, or Mac Pro. Ditto for the Apple Watch and Visio Pro, and likely every future product that Apple releases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extending the life of an Intel-based Mac using Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/intel-mac-win11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/intel-mac-win11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2020, Apple introduced the first Macs that used Apple Silicon processors instead of Intel ones, and this transition from Intel to Apple Silicon was completed earlier this year across Apple&amp;rsquo;s entire product line. While Apple promised they&amp;rsquo;d continue supporting macOS on Intel-based Macs for the near future, those of us who remember Apple&amp;rsquo;s previous transitions from M68k-to-PowerPC and PowerPC-to-Intel know full well that this support is going to end sooner than later. Even the last two versions of macOS have far fewer features when run on Intel Macs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 in Review</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2023-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2023-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For me, 2023 turned out to be a year of learning, growth, adventure, and gratitude. And since there&amp;rsquo;s plenty for me to talk about, I&amp;rsquo;ve divided my review into two sections: one that summarizes my professional pursuits, and one that summarizes everything else.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-professional-stuff&#34;&gt;The professional stuff:&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the college front, the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trios.com/programs-courses/technology/&#34;&gt;technology programs&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been pushing since 2020 finally got to market! My favourite one is &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Web Developer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, as it&amp;rsquo;s a radical departure from what we did previously. The whole program is taught exclusively on macOS, has two interlaced capstones, and is carefully crafted to allow students to build solid developer skills using modern industry tooling and processes with zero tests/quizzes (students instead perform weekly assignments). These weekly assignments allow instructors to assess and guide skills development for individual students throughout each course, as well as echo the sprint cadence used within industry that students must become accustomed to. We also have a new &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IT Professional (Infrastructure, Cloud &amp;amp; Cybersecurity)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; program that restructures and augments many of the topics in our previous IT Professional program to allow for expansion into the areas of cloud and cybersecurity (both of which are key industry focal points today).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Raspberry Pi Home Server</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/pi-home-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/pi-home-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pi4.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;Raspberry Pi 4&#34; title=&#34;Raspberry Pi 4&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi has been the most popular &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;single board computer (SBC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; among computer hobbyists for the past decade. It can be used to perform a wide variety of very different tasks, such as running graphical apps, streaming media, performing home automation, and monitoring humidity levels in a greenhouse. This is largely made possible by the Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s many interfaces (including GPIO, USB, HDMI, and wired/wireless Ethernet), as well as its ability to run the highly-customizable Linux operating system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essential keyboard shortcuts (Windows/macOS/Linux/UNIX)</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;hands.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;Hands on keyboard&#34; title=&#34;Hands on keyboard&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following are some shortcuts that I believe all desktop users should be familiar with. It is not a complete list by any means, and does not include virtual desktop or app pinning shortcuts as I felt those were beyond the scope of common desktop shortcuts. If you feel I omitted a common shortcut, email me (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jason.eckert@trios.com&#34;&gt;jason.eckert@trios.com&lt;/a&gt;) and I&amp;rsquo;ll add it to the list!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-windows-shortcuts&#34;&gt;1. Windows shortcuts&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Windows (⊞) key on your keyboard has the Windows logo printed on it. Modern keyboards use the newer Windows logo with four equally-sized squares, while older keyboards use a Windows logo with four slanted or curved squares.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Distro Hopping is a Bad Idea</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/distro-hopping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/distro-hopping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;distros.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Linux distros&#34; title=&#34;Linux distros&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-distro-hopping&#34;&gt;What is distro hopping?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; community, it&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon to install and use several different Linux distributions (or distros) over time - a process called &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;distro hopping&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. After all, there are hundreds of different distros available - and because each one is often geared to provide the optimal experience for a specific user or use-case (e.g., gaming), it&amp;rsquo;s become commonplace to assume that there must be a specific Linux distro out there that will suit your individual needs. Consequently, most Linux users believe that you should choose a Linux distro using the same process as choosing a wardrobe or eyewear frames. And that means trying on many different Linux distros to see how they look ;-)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running a Mainstream Linux Distro Natively on Apple Silicon: Fedora Asahi Remix First Impressions</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/fedora-asahi-remix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/fedora-asahi-remix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a year and a half since the &lt;a href=&#34;https://asahilinux.org/&#34;&gt;Asahi Linux&lt;/a&gt; project allowed us to run Arch Linux natively on our Apple Silicon computers. And while my overall experience has been excellent, the Asahi Linux project is switching their flagship Linux distribution (distro) &lt;a href=&#34;https://asahilinux.org/2023/08/fedora-asahi-remix/&#34;&gt;from Arch to Fedora&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why the switch from Arch to Fedora? You could argue that Fedora is a much more popular mainstream distribution compared to Arch, or that Linus Torvalds himself uses Fedora already on his Apple Silicon-based Macbook using the Asahi boot components and drivers. But the main reason is that there have been many &lt;a href=&#34;https://social.treehouse.systems/@marcan/109971521711413167&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; surrounding the maintenance of ARM packages for Arch Linux, and that the Fedora team is both capable and willing to provide provide the support needed to provide a truly polished Linux experience on modern Macs (the main goal of the Asahi Linux project). By moving to Fedora, the Asahi team can focus on reverse engineering Apple hardware while the Fedora team can focus on maintaining the distribution itself on the Apple Silicon platform. This combination of Fedora with the Asahi boot components and drivers for Apple Silicon is called &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fedora Asahi Remix&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Leverage Music for Maximum Tech Productivity</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/leveraging-music-for-tech-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/leveraging-music-for-tech-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;music-work.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;Dude somewhat working&#34; title=&#34;Dude somewhat working&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of us who work in technology fields such as software development, systems administration, and cybersecurity often &lt;a href=&#34;https://maximumble.thebookofbiff.com/comic/1249-headphones/&#34;&gt;listen to music while we work&lt;/a&gt; at our computer. After all, music stimulates many parts of our brains, including the limbic system responsible for alertness, emotion, and memory. Psychologists have also shown that music also reduces anxiety and blood pressure, as well as improves mood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, to make the most out of it, you must carefully plan your music strategy. Unfortunately, all of the blogs and YouTube videos I&amp;rsquo;ve seen that cover this process are terrible - they usually focus on music theory concepts the average person will not know or care about, and offer little practical advice. So, in this post I&amp;rsquo;ll get straight to the point about how you can get the most out of your music as a tech professional.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first textbook is now in its sixth edition</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-sixth-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-sixth-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;first-and-sixth.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;First and sixth edition of my Linux textbook&#34; title=&#34;First and sixth edition of my Linux textbook&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;ve written &lt;a href=&#34;../../bio/my-published-books/&#34;&gt;many textbooks&lt;/a&gt; on different topics over the past two decades, my favourite subject area by far is Linux. After all, Linux has evolved to be one of the most foundational topics in tech education. Information Technology (IT) fields such as server/network administration, cloud administration, cybersecurity, and software development now require a solid grasp of the Linux operating system.&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;sixthedition.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;CompTIA Linux+ and LPIC-1 Guide to Linux Certification, Sixth Edition&#34; title=&#34;CompTIA Linux+ and LPIC-1 Guide to Linux Certification, Sixth Edition&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve now been teaching tech for 25 years!</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/25-years-teaching-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/25-years-teaching-tech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bookshelf.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;Bookshelf&#34; title=&#34;Bookshelf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month marks the 25th anniversary of my teaching Information Technology (IT) courses for &lt;a href=&#34;https://trios.com&#34; title=&#34;triOS College&#34;&gt;triOS College&lt;/a&gt; in Ontario, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in 1998 I was well on my way to becoming an academic bum that kept on taking university courses forever. But I had a wife and child and needed to think more responsibly. So, as my spring university semester was ending, I applied for an instructor job that my grandmother saw in a newspaper ad and thought I&amp;rsquo;d be perfect for. After an interview and demo teach, I got the job and started the following Monday&amp;hellip; April 20, 1998.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux is making Apple Great Again</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-is-making-apple-great-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-is-making-apple-great-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;maga.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;Make Apple Great Again hat&#34; title=&#34;Make Apple Great Again hat&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MAGA pun aside, Linux is doing more for Apple hardware than macOS right now&amp;hellip; at least in the eyes of some old UNIX nerds like me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the Southern California Linux Expo (SCaLE) earlier this month, the closing keynote was given by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facesofopensource.com/ken-thompson/&#34; title=&#34;Ken Thompson&#34;&gt;Ken Thompson&lt;/a&gt; (co-creator of the UNIX operating system and the Go programming language). During the Q&amp;amp;A session following that keynote, Ken was asked &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your operating system of choice, today?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; While you can watch it &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/live/kaandEt_pKw?feature=share&amp;amp;t=3470&#34; title=&#34;here&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, his response was:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Linux ARM64 Workstation</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ultimate-linux-arm64-workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ultimate-linux-arm64-workstation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-all-started-this-month-last-year&#34;&gt;It all started this month last year&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In March 2022, the alpha release for Asahi was made available and I immediately installed it on a Mac Mini with an 8-core Apple Silicon (ARM64) M1 processor. Asahi is a Linux distribution that can run natively on Apple Silicon-based Macs due to some slick reverse engineering provided by members of the open source community. Moreover, running Asahi is perfectly legal because Apple formally allows booting non-macOS operating systems on their Apple Silicon platform.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fun Facts About Linux</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-fun-facts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-fun-facts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;linux-banner.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Linux banner&#34; title=&#34;Linux banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below are 26 questions that detail fun and obscure facts about the Linux operating system. Regardless of how much you&amp;rsquo;ve used Linux in the past, there&amp;rsquo;s likely a few or more that you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t know. Try answering each one from memory (or give it a good guess!) and then expand the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show me the answer!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; section to see if you are correct. PERFECT SCORES WIN A PRIZE!!! If you knew the correct answer to all 26 of these questions off the top of your head, send me an email and I&amp;rsquo;ll send you a link to download a free (yes FREE!) copy of Fedora Linux ;-)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Time I Yoga-Balled an Apple Store Employee</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-time-i-yoga-balled-an-apple-store-employee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-time-i-yoga-balled-an-apple-store-employee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in the late 2000s, my teenage daughter and I went to a local mall one weekend to do some shopping. As usual, I insisted we drop into the Apple store before leaving.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The store itself was quite busy. There were people playing with nearly every item on display at the tables near the front of the store, and even more people hovering around those people to catch a glimpse of what they were doing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 in Review</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2022-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2022-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;raybans.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;Ray Bans&#34; title=&#34;Ray Bans&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2022 was definitely an interesting year. COVID was given far less attention and we started living with it much like we live with the flu virus. Mask requirements were dropped, and many social events have resumed. Crazy COVID conspiracy theories and uproar are distant memories (at least for me).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still teaching IT classes remotely, which has resulted in better educational outcomes compared to the physical classroom. Working with operating systems and IT software within virtual machines on home PCs promotes tinkering and resourcefulness while allowing students to continue and expand upon class work at any time. Being able to revisit class videos afterwards is a huge bonus that everyone enjoys, as is the lack of commute-related stress. Since our IT programs include several CompTIA certifications, I decided to write a bunch of them this year, including the biggest one: CompTIA Advanced Security Practitioner (CASP+). I&amp;rsquo;m also planning on writing 5 more of them in the first half of 2023 because I have the exam vouchers from the CompTIA Instructor Network program.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reboot your mind once a day</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/tech-workers-should-meditate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/tech-workers-should-meditate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;meditation.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;Meditation&#34; title=&#34;Meditation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any IT sysadmin will tell you that if you don&amp;rsquo;t schedule time for computer maintenance, your systems will schedule it for you. The same is true for the human mind. After all, humans are the most powerful computer out there (and the only one that can be mass produced by unskilled labour ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When starting out in a tech field, we are intrinsically motivated to spend long hours trying to make a name for ourselves - after all, there&amp;rsquo;s no better feeling than mastering a new skill to level up in a knowledge industry. I remember this &amp;ldquo;sleep is for the weak&amp;rdquo; mindset fondly, but we do a lot of damage to our bodies during this period of our lives and the stress eventually catches up. Luckily, there is an easy solution. And no, it&amp;rsquo;s not drugs. It&amp;rsquo;s 20 minutes of mindfulness meditation every morning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RISCy business: The long and convoluted rise of today&#39;s dominant computing platform</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/riscy-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/riscy-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;RISC.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;RISC timeline&#34; title=&#34;RISC timeline&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;risc-vs-cisc&#34;&gt;RISC vs CISC&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, most computing platforms were built with the burden of software in mind. To ensure that a software program could be written easily and with fewer instructions, additional circuitry was added to the central processing unit (CPU) to compensate. This was referred to as complex instruction set computing (CISC). CISC architecture is still common today thanks to the x86 architecture used by Intel and AMD CPUs in most workstations and servers. Unfortunately, the added circuitry within CISC CPUs equated to added cost and complexity - both of which made it more expensive to evolve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How modern open source projects work</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/modern-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/modern-open-source/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;source.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;May the source be with you&#34; title=&#34;May the source be with you&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By definition, &amp;ldquo;open source&amp;rdquo; has little to do with how software is actually created.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instead, open source refers to how the source code for a software development project is distributed and consumed by software developers working on other projects. It is essentially a blanket term that refers to any software that makes its source code available to others. To be open source, the software project must be released under an open source license, of which there are two main categories: Copyleft and Permissive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Linux Certification Has Evolved Over The Years</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-certification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;LinuxDesk.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Banner&#34; title=&#34;Banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because organizations continually adopt new technologies, the need for skilled IT professionals to support those technologies is always increasing. Technology certification has been the most common skills benchmark used for hiring and promotion in the IT industry since the early 1990s, with Linux certification being one of the most sought-after. After all, knowing how to use, configure and administer the Linux operating system is prerequisite for a wide variety of different IT job roles, including server administrators, cloud administrators, devops engineers, site reliability engineers, cybersecurity analysts, penetration testers, and software developers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-booting Asahi Linux on your Apple Silicon Mac</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/asahi-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/asahi-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Asahi_M1.jpeg#right&#34; alt=&#34;Asahi M1&#34; title=&#34;Asahi M1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-asahi-linux&#34;&gt;What is Asahi Linux?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Asahi (&lt;a href=&#34;https://asahilinux.org/&#34;&gt;https://asahilinux.org/&lt;/a&gt;) is a Linux distribution based on Arch Linux ARM that you can install natively on Apple Silicon Macs with an M1- or M2-based CPU. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it daily as a software development workstation for over 3 months now on an M1 Mac Mini (16GB RAM, 500GB SSD), and it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;unbelievably&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; fast. It is 100% funded by Patreon and developed full-time by Hector Martin with many other contributors. You can watch &lt;a href=&#34;https://twit.tv/shows/floss-weekly/episodes/680&#34; title=&#34;this interview&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about the project, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=igYgGH6PnOw&#34; title=&#34;this video&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; to learn how the Apple Silicon platform is reverse-engineered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Swag in the Tech Industry</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-power-of-swag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-power-of-swag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-swag&#34;&gt;What is swag?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z9eIgg0ArDg&amp;amp;t=10s&#34; title=&#34;swag&#34;&gt;swag&lt;/a&gt; is any branded freebie that you get from a vendor, and it&amp;rsquo;s been used for marketing at tech industry events and showcases since the 1970s. Some common types of swag include stickers, mugs, water bottles, pins, luggage tags, plushies, squishies, t-shirts, socks, hats, tote bags, throw blankets, lanyards, sunglasses, lip balm, custom Lego sets, branded card/board games, journals/notebooks, sticky notes, phone stands, USB power banks, cables/accessories, USB thumb drives, and Bluetooth thingy&amp;rsquo;s. Branded items you receive from your own organization could also be called swag, but since they are often more expensive and targeted towards employee retention, I&amp;rsquo;ll omit them entirely in this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>macOS for Linux admins (2022 refresh)</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/macos-for-linux-admins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/macos-for-linux-admins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in my CompTIA blog post All About Linux and Linux+ ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comptia.org/blog/all-about-linux-and-linux&#34;&gt;https://www.comptia.org/blog/all-about-linux-and-linux&lt;/a&gt; ), Linux is essentially an open-source UNIX operating system. And since nearly all of the concepts, commands and files are identical between UNIX and Linux, anyone who works with Linux could easily administer a UNIX system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macOS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; operating system that runs on Apple computers is a flavor of UNIX.  Thus, most of the concepts that you use when administering a Linux system are also applicable to macOS. It’s not uncommon to find Apple laptops running macOS within organizations today, or even Apple desktops within certain departments, such as Marketing, where they are often used for graphics and desktop publishing. Consequently, when applying for IT administration and support jobs that require a macOS skillset, Linux is a big benefit!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ontario&#39;s Computer Part 2: The LEXICON Server</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/lexicon-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/lexicon-computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;LEXICON.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;LEXICON&#34; title=&#34;LEXICON&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I described in &lt;a href=&#34;../../myblog/icon-computer/&#34; title=&#34;Ontario&#39;s Computer: The Burroughs ICON&#34;&gt;my previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, the Burroughs ICON was a very cool UNIX-like computer developed by the Ontario governement for use within schools during the 1980s and early 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But because ICON computers were all diskless workstations, they were completely useless without a network and LEXICON file server. After all, the QNX operating system and programs that ran memory-resident on each ICON had to first be downloaded from the LEXICON across an ARCNET network. Moreover, when users logged into QNX on their ICON, they were actually logging in as a user account on the LEXICON and accessing the files within their home directory on the LEXICON&amp;rsquo;s hard drive. When users printed documents, they printed to the shared printer connected to the LEXICON.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ontario&#39;s Computer: The Burroughs ICON</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/icon-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/icon-computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ICON_logos.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;ICON logo&#34; title=&#34;ICON logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nicknamed the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bionic beaver&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the ICON was a Canadian computer funded by the Ontario government and used in schools province wide. It was designed by CEMCorp (Canadian Educational Microprocessor Corporation) and manufactured by Burroughs (later renamed to Unisys). Moreover, it ran the QNX UNIX-like operating system, which was also developed in Canada by two University of Waterloo students.&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;ICON.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;ICON&#34; title=&#34;ICON&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you took a computer programming course in high school during the 1980s or early 1990s, you likely remember learning C, BASIC or Pascal on the ICON, as well as many UNIX commands that would pay off later in college or university. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t, you probably remember the ICON as a cool looking steel monstrosity that had an indestructible keyboard and trackball (that everyone tried to spin as fast as they could).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuring the i3 Window Manager</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/configuring-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/configuring-i3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-use-the-i3-window-manager&#34;&gt;Why use the i3 window manager&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a Linux user, you&amp;rsquo;re probably using a desktop environment that looks like Windows (e.g. KDE Plasma) or macOS (e.g. GNOME). But these desktop environments use a great deal of resources and are cumbersome when it comes to flexibility and navigation between applications and code. To solve these problems, most software developers and Linux/UNIX administrators install and use a tiling window manager.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While there are many different tiling window managers available, i3 is the most common one. It is easy to configure, and has great documentation available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://i3wm.org/docs/userguide.html&#34;&gt;https://i3wm.org/docs/userguide.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of RISC architecture</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/power-of-risc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/power-of-risc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;risc-hackers-movie.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;Hackers Movie Quote&#34; title=&#34;Hackers Movie Quote&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This part of the 1995 &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hackers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; movie shown above is right on par for the time. After all, by the mid 1990s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced Instruction Set Computer (RISC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; processors were seen as the future of computing by most in the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By using a simplified instruction set, computers with RISC processors at the time could perform tasks in a quarter of the time compared to computers that had a traditional &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complex Instruction Set Computer (CISC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; processor. RISC processors also required less circuitry, which allowed manufacturers to easily add more functionality, such as crypto accelerators, memory management controllers and specialized floating point arithmetic units.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPARCbook teardown</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/sparcbook-teardown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/sparcbook-teardown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;s3000_ad.gif#right&#34; alt=&#34;SPARCbook 3000ST ad&#34; title=&#34;SPARCbook 3000ST ad&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in 2019, I picked up a rare SPARC-based laptop from the 1990s running Solaris UNIX (marketed as the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ultimate UNIX portable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; on the Tadpole website in 1997). You can read my blog post on it here: &lt;a href=&#34;../../myblog/sparcbook3000st-the-coolest-90s-laptop/&#34; title=&#34;SPARCbook 3000ST: The coolest 90s laptop&#34;&gt;SPARCbook 3000ST: The coolest 90s laptop&lt;/a&gt;. It occasionally shows up on Hacker News, and I get plenty of comments whenever I post it on Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021 in Review</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2021-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2021-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While 2020 introduced a slew of changes to everyone&amp;rsquo;s personal and professional lives, these changes were considerably less pronounced for those of us working in tech fields. After all, most software engineering and server/cloud configuration was already performed remotely before the pandemic using long-standing processes/tools. Adapting to online tech teaching in the college was a welcome challenge, and also more relevant for the industry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As 2020 was ending, we all knew that 2021 would bring vaccine rollouts but not a complete return to normalcy. I was very interested to see how the pandemic shakeup would transform the workplace and our use of technology in 2021, but also knew that 2021 would be more like season 2 of 2020. Consequently, I decided to make the most out of the more delightful aspects of 2020, including work-from-home, online tech conferences, and local outdoor activities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Quickstart</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/kubernetes-quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/kubernetes-quickstart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past two decades, we&amp;rsquo;ve shifted from running servers bare metal to running them almost exclusively within virtual machines (VMs). More recently we&amp;rsquo;ve seen another shift to running servers within containers. Like VMs, containers are servers that contain a unique filesystem, IP stack and software. But unlike VMs, containers do not contain a full operating system or operating system kernel. Instead they rely on an underlying operating system that runs the container using a &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;container runtime&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, such as Docker. Consequently, containers are much smaller than VMs and ideal for running software within cloud environments where resource utilization must be kept to a minimum to control costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing a fast Linux server on an M1-based Mac</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/installing-linux-server-on-mac-m1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/installing-linux-server-on-mac-m1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest worries that IT users have regarding Apple&amp;rsquo;s new ARM-based M1 platform is the ability to run &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;virtual machines (VMs)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of other operating systems using hypervisor software. And while it&amp;rsquo;s possible to run virtual machines of both Windows and Linux operating systems made for the Intel platform on the M1, the performance cost of translating Intel instructions to ARM is high (even with the optimizations Apple has within their M1 CPU). Luckily, the most common VM that an IT systems administrator or developer will install is Linux, and ARM versions of Linux have been mainstream for well over a decade now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ARM on the desktop is here to stay</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/arm-on-the-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/arm-on-the-desktop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;arm.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;ARM Powered logo&#34; title=&#34;ARM Powered logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in the 1990s, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced Instruction Set Computing (RISC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; architecture was widely seen as the future. UNIX workstations from Silicon Graphics and Sun Microsystems boasted powerful RISC CPUs at the time, but were prohibitively expensive and died out in the early 2000s as a result. Only the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acorn RISC Machine (ARM)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; architecture used in low-power devices (e.g. PDAs) survived past the early 2000s, and only because of the rise of mobile devices that relied on battery power.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a great time to be a developer</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/it-is-a-great-time-to-be-a-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/it-is-a-great-time-to-be-a-developer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;developer.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;Developer&#34; title=&#34;Developer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a developer for over 3 decades. I remember &lt;code&gt;prompt&lt;/code&gt; statements in dBASE III, M68k Assembly and those awful Borland tools. Documentation was provided in large printed binders and often left a lot to the imagination.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Things got better in the late 1990s and early 2000s, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the late 2000s when things really started to heat up. Sun Microsystem&amp;rsquo;s early 1990s slogan &amp;ldquo;The network is the computer&amp;rdquo; became a reality with the rise of cloud computing, object storage and slick frontend/backend stacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNIX/Linux is now a core skill for anyone working in tech</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-is-now-a-core-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-is-now-a-core-skill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;techworker.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Tech Worker&#34; title=&#34;Tech Worker&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you had asked me in the 1990s whether most people in the tech world would be using a UNIX or Linux shell to manage their servers, I would have chuckled and said &amp;ldquo;No.&amp;rdquo; But two decades later we find ourselves in a world where 96% of the cloud is comprised of Linux servers running Web apps made with open source frameworks, and the majority of software development is done on UNIX (macOS) or Linux workstations. Nearly all network hardware, security appliances, smart appliances, cars, wearables and IoT devices also run UNIX or Linux, as do our smartphones and tablets. Want to secure your systems or network, or test your security using ethical hacking? You&amp;rsquo;ll need UNIX or Linux to do that as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity in a Nutshell</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/cybersecurity-in-a-nutshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/cybersecurity-in-a-nutshell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;hacker.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Hacker&#34; title=&#34;Hacker&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, Cybersecurity is an umbrella term that encompasses all aspects of computer, network and data security. While Cybersecurity-specific job roles are commonplace in larger organizations, smaller organizations often require that existing IT roles perform Cybersecurity-specific tasks. And since Cybersecurity is only going to grow in importance over time, anyone working in IT should have a solid knowledge of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what-does-cybersecurity-involve&#34;&gt;So what does Cybersecurity involve?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can divide cybersecurity into four main areas today:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The future looks a lot like mainframe computing</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/mainframe-computing-is-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/mainframe-computing-is-the-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ibm.jpeg#center&#34; alt=&#34;IBM mainframe&#34; title=&#34;IBM mainframe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mainframe computers, like the IBM one shown above, were the first digital computers that started appearing in big companies during the 1950s. They were room-sized behemoths of circuitry and steel primarily used to generate balance sheets and income statements. And while IBM still sells a small number of mainframe computers today, they only enjoyed mainstream popularity until the late 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While early mainframes were only accessed by the people who managed it, most mainframes of the 1970s and 1980s ran programs that were accessed by remote users via a dumb terminal. Dumb terminals were not standalone computers; they had a display and keyboard, but merely allowed you to interact with a central mainframe computer across a network connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering the Zen of TrackPoint</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/mastering-the-zen-of-trackpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/mastering-the-zen-of-trackpoint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lenovo (formerly IBM) ThinkPad laptops are widely known for three things:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An amazing keyboard (often touted as the best for professional work)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rugged build quality (it&amp;rsquo;s hard to kill a Thinkpad: &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/OMilj81s9SI&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/OMilj81s9SI&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The TrackPoint, which has been standard on ThinkPads since the first model in 1992&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;trackpoint.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;TrackPoint&#34; title=&#34;TrackPoint&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-trackpoint&#34;&gt;What is a TrackPoint?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, it is an alternative to using a mouse or trackpad on laptops. To ensure that your index fingers can easily reach it, it&amp;rsquo;s situated in the middle of the keyboard between the G, H and B keys.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The computer that saved Apple</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-computer-that-saved-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-computer-that-saved-apple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;imacbb.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;iMac Bondi Blue&#34; title=&#34;iMac Bondi Blue&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The very first iMac model (shown above) was released in 1998, came in one colour called Bondi Blue, and had a semi-translucent case that allowed you to see the components inside. It had a 233MHz PowerPC G3 CPU, 32MB of RAM, CD-ROM drive, and shipped with MacOS 8.1 (soon upgraded to MacOS 9 - the last version before Apple moved to Mac OS X).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While passing by a convenience store in my home town of Hespeler, I muttered in distaste when I noticed that someone had dumped a lot of furniture and various other household items next to the already-full dumpster at the back. But just as I was about to look away, I noticed something familiar. Peeking out of the top of a Rubbermaid tub was what looked like the rear of an old iMac. When I walked over to it, I noticed that it was a Bondi Blue iMac in mint condition, with the original keyboard and mouse. So I took it home, turned it on, and it booted to life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seldom discussed tips for working in the tech industry</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/seldom-discussed-tech-industry-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/seldom-discussed-tech-industry-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;jasontechtips.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;jason tech tips&#34; title=&#34;jason tech tips&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of blog posts on the Web that give sage advice for anyone working in the tech industry. However, most of them focus on the same topics: time management, resourcefulness, continuous learning, verbal and written communication skills, caffeine consumption, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss 6 tech industry tips that are rarely discussed online, but that are equally (if not more) important from my experience over the past three decades in this industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Z shell features that will encourage you to switch from Bash</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/moving-from-bash-to-zsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/moving-from-bash-to-zsh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;tuxzsh.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;tux zsh shell&#34; title=&#34;tux zsh shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The command line interface on your system is provided by a shell. And while there are dozens of different shells available to choose from, nearly every UNIX and Linux system over the past two decades has used the feature-rich Bash shell as the default login shell.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although the Bash shell still remains the most common login shell used on UNIX and Linux systems, macOS and a few Linux distributions (e.g. Kali) have switched their default shell to the Z shell (&lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt;), and this trend is likely to continue. The Z shell has been around for three decades, and is the second most popular shell next to Bash.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I love teaching online</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/why-i-love-teaching-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/why-i-love-teaching-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;onlineteaching.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;OnlineTeaching&#34; title=&#34;OnlineTeaching&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the pandemic hit earlier this year, schools around the globe quickly embraced online teaching to continue their curriculum. While online teaching wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely new in this space, it certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t the norm. This meant that many teachers had to adapt quickly, as these 2 funny videos illustrate:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CCe5PaeAeew&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CCe5PaeAeew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zy_y9yOrgxk&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zy_y9yOrgxk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;ve loved every part of this transition because I absolutely love teaching tech courses online.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grant you, I&amp;rsquo;ve had some practice prior to 2020, as well as a general interest in how the Web could be used for education. Back in the early 2000s, I designed and wrote all of the online Linux curriculum for Caldera (including the HTML and Perl scripts that hosted it). It was an early stab at online education that had as many faults as it did benefits, but I learned a great deal during the process. Years later, I got to refine what I learned during my online computer science courses at Nova Southeastern, as well as the Train-the-Trainer courses I taught for CompTIA. By this time, technology had caught up to the needs of education, and online education was quite mature with a set of common best practices and technologies that everyone implemented.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of technology</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Technology is a crazy ride, and like that lyric in the Talking Heads song &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once in a Lifetime&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;you may ask yourself, well, how did I get here?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck, because this post is a no-nonsense, give-me-the-big-picture timeline of what the heck happened in the technology landscape these past 50 years. Of course, not every little detail is in there. Just those that are actually important (in my expert opinion, of course ;-) Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity in the early 1990&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/cybersecurity-in-the-90s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/cybersecurity-in-the-90s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in the late 1980&amp;rsquo;s and early 1990&amp;rsquo;s, I remember collecting MS-DOS computer viruses. I’d download them from an online Bulletin Board System (BBS) and store them on floppy disks in compressed format to prevent them from executing. For fun, some friends and I would occasionally release them on one of our systems to see what they did, and then reinstall MS-DOS  afterwards. Most viruses didn’t do very much, but some others (e.g. BBkiller) would remove or modify the contents of files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most people don&#39;t want a computer</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past few decades, people of all ages across North America have become technology-literate in some way or another. Many of them weren&amp;rsquo;t introduced to technology via desktop or laptop computers, but instead through a smartphone or tablet. Similarly, many desktop and laptop users have switched to using their smartphone or tablet over the past decade to interact with the online world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After all, smartphones and tablets are incredibly easy to use. You open an app to do what you want (social media, shopping, taking pics of food, etc.), and the rest can be done in a Web browser. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter where your files are stored locally because they&amp;rsquo;re easily searchable, and they&amp;rsquo;re automatically synced to the cloud so that you don&amp;rsquo;t lose them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open does not always mean Open Source</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/open-does-not-always-mean-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/open-does-not-always-mean-open-source/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;open.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;Open Source vs Open standards&#34; title=&#34;Open Source vs Open standards&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the technology world today, the term &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is most commonly associated with &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Source refers to software released under a license that gives other software developers access to modify the original Source code that was used to create the software. This, in turn allows other software developers worldwide to quickly identify and fix bugs and security loopholes, as well as make feature improvements to the software. Consequently, Open Source software evolves more rapidly than other (&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closed Source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) software, and is considered the gold standard for software today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracing difficult shell scripts</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/tracing-difficult-shell-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/tracing-difficult-shell-scripts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;comic.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;UNIX/Linux comic&#34; title=&#34;UNIX/Linux comic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re an IT systems administrator, developer or devop working with Linux/UNIX shell scripts, you&amp;rsquo;re likely going to come across some that are not well documented and difficult to trace (read and understand) as a result.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While these scripts discourage others from tracing them, you can easily trace even the most difficult shell scripts if you follow good tracing procedures. Moreover, by tracing a difficult shell script, you build your knowledge of specific Linux/UNIX components, as well as scripting in general.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UNIX Philosophy in 2019</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-unix-philosophy-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-unix-philosophy-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;unixpres.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;UNIX Presentation&#34; title=&#34;UNIX Presentation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, I did a presentation for WWITPRO that detailed the UNIX philosophy and its relevance today. Given the subject matter, I decided to do the presentation in PostScript on my SPARCbook running Sun Solaris 2.5.1. This blog post details the content of the presentation for posterity!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-unix&#34;&gt;What is UNIX?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, UNIX is an operating system that was created by Ken Thompson in 1969 that was rewritten shortly thereafter in Dennis Ritchie’s C programming language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSH Foo</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ssh-foo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ssh-foo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I gave a presentation at a local LUG (which is a Linux User’s Group, for anyone who hasn’t heard of those before) on the subject of SSH Foo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In UNIX circles, we refer to tricks of the trade as “Kung Fu” or just “Fu” (which sounds rude), so it is spelled “Foo” ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I’ll summarize my SSH Foo talk! Be aware that this is not an introduction  to SSH, but a more advanced look at some interesting SSH features for those who are already comfortable with it. As such, I&amp;rsquo;ve kept to point form here to allow you to  skim to the parts you are most interested in!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three reasons why incubators breed failure</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/three-reasons-why-incubators-breed-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/three-reasons-why-incubators-breed-failure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;incubator1.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;incubator1&#34; title=&#34;incubator1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These past few years, I’ve provided various types of support for some tech incubators in the Kitchener-Waterloo region where I live (it’s a complex arrangement that I won’t go into within this post, but mostly involves helping people with technology implementation issues related to software).  It’s not hard to find tech incubators nowadays - they’ve become quite popular this past decade, and larger cities often have several incubators of various sizes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the cloud grew up around Linux</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-the-cloud-grew-up-around-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-the-cloud-grew-up-around-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cloudy.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;cloudy&#34; title=&#34;cloudy&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open source software has had a powerful effect on computing. When the ARPANET/NSFNET was sold to different companies in the 1990s to create the commercial Internet, nobody expected it to grow as fast as it did. It was the open source Apache Web server running on the open source Linux (and BSD UNIX) operating system that ultimately allowed the Internet to grow quickly and attract the attention of the world.  Apache on Linux allowed anyone with a computer and Internet connection to implement a Web server to serve Web pages as part of the World Wide Web of Internet resources. In short, if there was no open source Web server or operating system freely available in the 1990s, the rise of the Internet would have been dramatically slower or even non-existent until the 2000s. The Internet and the World Wide Web grew up around open source and Linux.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A simple guide to git</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-simple-guide-to-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-simple-guide-to-git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;git1.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;git1&#34; title=&#34;git1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, Git is a version control system that can be used to keep track of the changes that you make to files over time - it allows you to revert files to a previous state, or see who made changes to a file at different times if several people are working the those files collaboratively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Git was original developed back in 2005 by Linus Torvalds (the creator of Linux) to aid in making changes to the Linux kernel, but has since become the most common open source version control system used today. You can run Git on most platforms, including Windows, Linux and macOS. Although people primarily use it today for version controlling software projects, you can use it to provide version control for any files on your system.  In this blog post, I’ll use it to provide version control and central access for Linux shell scripts (something that is very useful for Linux administrators).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devops Demystified</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/devops-demystified/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/devops-demystified/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;devops1.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Devops1&#34; title=&#34;Devops1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week, my friend Scott Elliott did a great guest presentation at the college where he talked about, amongst other things, devops. Moreover, I’ve been involved myself in the setup and configuration of two software development workflows (which technically makes me a devop); one was in 2017 for a tech startup in Kitchener, and the other one was earlier this year for a much larger project at the University of Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halt and Catch Fire</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/halt-and-catch-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/halt-and-catch-fire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;haltandcatchfire.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Halt and Catch Fire&#34; title=&#34;Halt and Catch Fire&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Halt and Catch Fire is an AMC television series that ran for four seasons from 2014-2017, and covers the culture and pivotal aspects of the computing industry from 1983 (just after the release of the IBM PC) to 1994 (when the Internet and World Wide Web exploded).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can binge watch it on Netflix if you like today, and trust me - you won’t be disappointed!  Halt and Catch Fire is the best drama I’ve ever seen - an emotional rollercoaster like no other.  The characters are unforgettable, the acting is nothing short of phenomenal, and the entire series has an incredible message about technology and human progress that you only get once you see the final episode!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons I&#39;ve learned from teaching 20 years of IT</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/20-years-of-teaching-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/20-years-of-teaching-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;20years.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;classroom&#34; title=&#34;classroom&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I actually started teaching on April 13th 1998 (20 years ago today).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was my final year as a student at the University of Waterloo, and as I was finishing up writing my final exams I realized that I needed to actually go out and get a real job to support my family (I was married with a daughter at the time).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prior to that, I had worked on some very cool technology projects for various companies (including some big names like Microsoft, DEC and SUN), as well as worked for the University as a Web developer and sysadmin. I also worked for many years as a teaching assistant and courseware editor for Peter Chieh&amp;rsquo;s nuclear chemistry course&amp;hellip;.after all, most of my academic background was in science, which is where most of the computer science talent was back in the 1990s!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The history of IT certification</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/history-of-it-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/history-of-it-certification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cert1.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;cert1&#34; title=&#34;cert1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nearly everyone working in an Information Technology (IT) field has at least one IT-related certification. This is because IT certification is commonly used as a skills benchmark for hiring and promotion, and it’s been that way for a long, long time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So where did all this certification stuff start?  If you look online, there isn’t even a Wikipedia page that can give you that answer - like many things in the technology world that predated the Internet, it just wasn’t important enough to keep track of in the Internet Age that started in the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Essentials for SysAdmins</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/powershell-essentials-for-sysadmins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/powershell-essentials-for-sysadmins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PowerShell is essentially a scripting language and shell (command prompt) that you can use on Windows systems.  It’s basically Microsoft’s way of getting a powerful UNIX/Linux/Mac-like shell on the Windows platform (long overdue!).  The first versions of PowerShell were pretty horrific, but it’s come a long way since then.  PowerShell v4 and later is pretty decent (Win10 comes with PowerShell v5).  Luckily, PowerShell v4 comes with Windows Server 2012, and since this post is geared towards sysadmins, I’ll focus everything on Windows Server 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft ReFS vs Oracle ZFS - FIGHT!</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/refs-vs-zfs-fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/refs-vs-zfs-fight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;refszfs1.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Fight&#34; title=&#34;Fight&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past, most IT admins have put their faith in systems and SANs (Storage Area Networks) that use RAID (Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks) technology.  RAID can be used to combine hard disks together into simple volumes (called RAID-0, or JBOD) that aren’t fault tolerant, but can also be used to create mirrored volumes where both drives are identical in case one fails (called RAID-1), or striped volumes with parity where data is written across several disks with parity information that can be used to calculate the missing data if a drive fails (called RAID-5).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of Information Technology</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/evolution-of-info-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/evolution-of-info-tech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;people.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;people&#34; title=&#34;people&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a Dean for the technology faculties of a private college in Canada, I’m always looking to make our programs more aligned to the industry - my motto is: always look forward and never look back!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, when it comes to Information Technology (IT), I regularly find that the general perception of IT jobs is stuck in the past by at least a decade.  I can’t tell you how many times I’ve met people who think that IT guys are stuck in the back closet of some company doing some menial job, such as re-soldering chips on a computer motherboard much like working on the engine of an old car.  &lt;em&gt;{shiver}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eBook pilot</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ebook-pilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/ebook-pilot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ebookpilot.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;class&#34; title=&#34;class&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is my class with their new Kindle DXs. Notice the absence of heavy textbooks on the desks!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;update&#34;&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, while it was cool to carry around all of our textbooks in PDF format on our Kindle DXs, the pilot ultimately led to us not adopting eBooks exclusively. Simply put, many of our students just preferred the ease of printed books. eBooks may become the norm in the future, but probably only when everyone carries a laptop with them, and can access a second monitor for it in the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I created the Internet</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/i-created-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/i-created-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;theinternet.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;The Internet&#34; title=&#34;The Internet&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Complete with blinking light! It&amp;rsquo;s amazing what you can make with a soldering iron and the spare electrical parts you have in your basement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are wondering what the heck I am talking about, just watch the BBC sitcom “The IT Crowd” Series 3 Episode 4.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>War Games shell scripting fun</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/war-games-shell-scripting-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/war-games-shell-scripting-fun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;wargames.png#right&#34; alt=&#34;War Games&#34; title=&#34;War Games&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While my daughter and I sat across from each other in Starbucks drinking coffee and PIN messaging each other in Leetspeak using our BlackBerries (yes, I realize how drastically nerdy this is), the thought occurred to us that a simple shell script could easily be used to simulate the War Operation Plan Response (WOPR) supercomputer from the movie War Games (1983).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, we analyzed the frame-by-frame output from the movie and recreated the output on the Sun Enterprise 450 in my classroom running Red Hat Linux.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to please your IT department</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-to-please-your-it-dept/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-to-please-your-it-dept/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;itdept.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;IT dept&#34; title=&#34;IT dept&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you call us to have your computer moved, be sure to leave it buried under half a ton of postcards, baby pictures, stuffed animals, dried flowers, bowling trophies and children’s art. We don’t have a life, and we find it deeply moving to catch a fleeting glimpse of yours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don’t write anything down. Ever. We can play back the error messages from here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When an IT person says he’s coming right over, go for coffee. That way you won’t be there when we need your password. It’s nothing for us to remember 700 screen saver passwords.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Energize IT conference</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-energize-it-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-energize-it-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;stage.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;Microsoft stage&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft stage&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, I attended the Microsoft Energize IT Conference at the Convention Centre in Toronto.  Having been to many Microsoft conferences in the past, I was reluctant to attend since most of them were a biased propaganda show for sales people and managers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Energize IT was a typical Microsoft conference: lots of money, free food and swank.  When the keynote presentations started, it looked promising.  The first few speakers emphasized the need for feedback from the audience such that Microsoft can adapt to the changing needs of their customers, as well as the need for a sense of “community” amongst us. And to make things even better, there were power bars at each table in the auditorium for laptop use as well as free wireless access (I brought my laptop and was able to check my emails during the boring parts of the presentation).   From people’s facial expressions and body language, everyone seemed engaged.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1. What do I do?</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/what-do-i-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/what-do-i-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;headshot.jpg#right&#34; alt=&#34;summit&#34; title=&#34;summit&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Besides drinking vast quantities of caffeine and spending most of my free time enjoying the outdoors, I have taught, developed, and managed various technology courses at triOS College in Ontario (Canada) since 1998 in both our college and corporate training divisions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in 2011, I took on a different title of Dean of Technology to salvage our video game programs, and it turned into a more strategic role where I was able to help shape the development of our Information Technology (IT), developer, and video game programs. It also allowed me to build some exciting opportunities for our students, run over a dozen sponsored game jams and hackathons, communicate program information to others in the college, as well as meet with vendors, employers, internship hosts, and other colleges. My goal was to &amp;ldquo;walk the talk&amp;rdquo; in every facet of technology education, and I definitely achieved that early on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5. Tech T-Shirt Slogans</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techshirts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techshirts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;shirt2.png&#34; alt=&#34;shirt pic&#34; title=&#34;shirt pic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Anthropomorphize computers. They hate that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The proper way to declare war in software development is &lt;code&gt;var war;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I void warranties&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I read your email&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Linux isn&amp;rsquo;t magic. It&amp;rsquo;s sudo-science.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kids: Don&amp;rsquo;t try this at ~&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Code poet&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Byte Me&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I see dead pixels&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd /pub; more beer&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No, I will not fix your computer&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is no place like 127.0.0.1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is no place like ::1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bow before me for I am root&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6. Tech Humour and Puns</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techhumour/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/techhumour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;shaqbill.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;joke&#34; title=&#34;joke&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I feel someone needs to start a house-call backup business where someone could pull up to your home (or business) in a car that has a big NAS box in the back, and then perform off-site backups across Ethernet for a fee. They could call it NASCAR.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I was Voldemort I would have hidden a horcrux in HP&amp;rsquo;s documentation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NFTs make excellent gifts. After all, they&amp;rsquo;re GIF certificates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7. Three Unconventional Tips for Career Success</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/gradspeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/info/gradspeech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;success.png#center&#34; alt=&#34;career success&#34; title=&#34;career success&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-dont-turn-down-an-opportunity-because-it-isnt-the-job-you-want&#34;&gt;1. Don&amp;rsquo;t turn down an opportunity because it isn&amp;rsquo;t the job you want&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Career progression is never a straight line, and good opportunities don&amp;rsquo;t actually have the words &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;good opportunity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; written in bold letters on them &amp;ndash; you never know where they will lead you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, back around the year 2000 I was asked to teach a corporate Linux course on the weekends. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to give up my weekends for a month, and quite frankly I thought it would be a boring waste of my abilities and time. But I did it anyways, and one of the amazing students in my class worked for Compaq and introduced me to SHARCnet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
