<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/internet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Quickstart</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/kubernetes-quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/kubernetes-quickstart/</guid>
      <description>Over the past two decades, we&amp;rsquo;ve shifted from running servers bare metal to running them almost exclusively within virtual machines (VMs). More recently we&amp;rsquo;ve seen another shift to running servers within containers. Like VMs, containers are servers that contain a unique filesystem, IP stack and software. But unlike VMs, containers do not contain a full operating system or operating system kernel. Instead they rely on an underlying operating system that runs the container using a container runtime, such as Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An overview of cloud buzz words</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/cloud-buzz-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/cloud-buzz-words/</guid>
      <description>As this Dilbert comic eloquently illustrates, there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of cloud buzz words thrown around today. But as strange and complex as they may sound (even to seasoned developers and system administrators), they are not difficult to understand. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through the different components and features of the cloud, explaining the associated buzz words along the way.
What is the cloud? Back in the early 1990s, when the US government sold off parts of their ARPAnet and NSFnet to private companies (later called Internet Service Providers, or ISPs) to create the public Internet, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything exciting about the Internet at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work-from-home is the new BlackBerry</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/work-from-home-is-the-new-blackberry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/work-from-home-is-the-new-blackberry/</guid>
      <description>I vividly remember the first time I was issued a BlackBerry smartphone back in the 2000s for work. I&amp;rsquo;d read emails while in line at the Pita shop during lunch hour, formulating a plan and response before I returned to my desk to reply. For emails that required a quick response, I&amp;rsquo;d hammer out a response on the BlackBerry keyboard while in line. And having access to my Outlook calendar on the BlackBerry meant that I could view, schedule and prioritize my tasks anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future looks a lot like mainframe computing</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/mainframe-computing-is-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/mainframe-computing-is-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Mainframe computers, like the IBM one shown above, were the first digital computers that started appearing in big companies during the 1950s. They were room-sized behemoths of circuitry and steel primarily used to generate balance sheets and income statements. And while IBM still sells a small number of mainframe computers today, they only enjoyed mainstream popularity until the late 1980s.
While early mainframes were only accessed by the people who managed it, most mainframes of the 1970s and 1980s ran programs that were accessed by remote users via a dumb terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relating Silicon Valley to the Toronto-Waterloo Corridor</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/silicon-valley-toronto-waterloo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/silicon-valley-toronto-waterloo/</guid>
      <description>Silicon Valley is an HBO comedy series that aired from 2014-2019. It follows a group of software engineers as they journey from creating their own apps in a home-based tech incubator in California&amp;rsquo;s Silicon Valley to creating a new decentralized Internet in their own venture capital-funded tech company.
From the beginning, its creators (Mike Judge and Alec Berg) aimed to make the series an entertaining and accurate depiction of Silicon Valley tech culture, icons and events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The computer that saved Apple</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-computer-that-saved-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-computer-that-saved-apple/</guid>
      <description>The very first iMac model (shown above) was released in 1998, came in one colour called Bondi Blue, and had a semi-translucent case that allowed you to see the components inside. It had a 233MHz PowerPC G3 CPU, 32MB of RAM, CD-ROM drive, and shipped with MacOS 8.1 (soon upgraded to MacOS 9 - the last version before Apple moved to Mac OS X).
While passing by a convenience store in my home town of Hespeler, I muttered in distaste when I noticed that someone had dumped a lot of furniture and various other household items next to the already-full dumpster at the back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to WireGuard VPN</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/an-introduction-to-wireguard-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/an-introduction-to-wireguard-vpn/</guid>
      <description>1. Why WireGuard? When it comes to encrypting traffic between systems, there are a wide variety of different Virtual Private Network (VPN) software available, some of which have been used since the 1990s. Each of them focus on different encryption algorithms and flow control strategies, alongside mechanisms for providing for secure authentication and negotiating encryption keys. Unfortunately, this complexity often translates to more problems, slower traffic, as well fewer use cases and supported operating systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 in review</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2020-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/2020-in-review/</guid>
      <description>I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking - 2020 sucked! Worst year ever! The COVID-19 pandemic, no social gatherings, no dine-in restaurants, no gyms, the US Trumpster fire, and most importantly to those of us in the tech world: Red Hat terminating CentOS development.
Of course, most people will remember 2020 for the pandemic, and that&amp;rsquo;s completely understandable. None of us have experienced a pandemic in our lifetime, and both our society and economy were not prepared to deal with it gracefully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I love teaching online</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/why-i-love-teaching-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/why-i-love-teaching-online/</guid>
      <description>When the pandemic hit earlier this year, schools around the globe quickly embraced online teaching to continue their curriculum. While online teaching wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely new in this space, it certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t the norm. This meant that many teachers had to adapt quickly, as these 2 funny videos illustrate:
 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CCe5PaeAeew https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zy_y9yOrgxk  However, I&amp;rsquo;ve loved every part of this transition because I absolutely love teaching tech courses online.
Grant you, I&amp;rsquo;ve had some practice prior to 2020, as well as a general interest in how the Web could be used for education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of technology</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>Technology is a crazy ride, and like that lyric in the Talking Heads song Once in a Lifetime, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;you may ask yourself, well, how did I get here?&amp;rdquo;
If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck, because this post is a no-nonsense, give-me-the-big-picture timeline of what the heck happened in the technology landscape these past 50 years. Of course, not every little detail is in there. Just those that are actually important (in my expert opinion, of course ;-) Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most people don&#39;t want a computer</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</guid>
      <description>In the past few decades, people of all ages across North America have become technology-literate in some way or another. Many of them weren&amp;rsquo;t introduced to technology via desktop or laptop computers, but instead through a smartphone or tablet. Similarly, many desktop and laptop users have switched to using their smartphone or tablet over the past decade to interact with the online world.
After all, smartphones and tablets are incredibly easy to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So, you think online conferencing is new?</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/so-you-think-online-conferencing-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/so-you-think-online-conferencing-is-new/</guid>
      <description>The city that I live in (Cambridge, Ontario) was formed as an amalgamation of three smaller towns (Hespeler, Preston and Galt) in 1973. Hespeler gets its name from Jacob Hespeler, who built an impressive industrial empire in the town in 1845. Through his widespread influence, he secured railway access, as well as attracted engineering talent from as far away as Europe. By the start of World War I, Hespeler housed the largest textile mill in the British Empire, and had an electric passenger railway (Grand River Railway) that allowed easy transit to the rest of the region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The old Web was fun</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-old-web-was-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-old-web-was-fun/</guid>
      <description>I was around during the birth of the web in the early 1990s and have enjoyed every twist and turn since then. Even before creating my own personal website and blog (this site) in 1998, I maintained the Department of Science website at UW (originally http://sciborg.uwaterloo.ca).
And while I’ve enjoyed watching the evolution of the web, I still think the old web was more fun. In this blog post, I’ll tell you why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the most out of your online course</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/getting-the-most-out-of-your-online-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/getting-the-most-out-of-your-online-course/</guid>
      <description>The COVID-19 virus has forced colleges and universities in Ontario to quickly move their stuff to an online format to allow classes to continue using social isolation.
As a learner, this means that you’ll be immersed in a new learning format that is very different from a physical classroom environment. Both physical and online learning have their own unique advantages, and you’ll likely be engaging in both over the course of your career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips to survive teaching an online course</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/tips-to-survive-teaching-an-online-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/tips-to-survive-teaching-an-online-course/</guid>
      <description>The COVID-19 virus has forced colleges and universities in Canada to quickly move their stuff to an online format to allow classes to continue using social isolation. One teacher even wrote a funny song about it: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CCe5PaeAeew
I’m luckier than most, since I’ve been doing online seminars and classes for a wide variety of different organizations for many years now. Most of these sessions have been Train the Trainer (TTT) classes where I teach a course to other technical instructors worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you should use technology less</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/why-you-should-use-technology-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/why-you-should-use-technology-less/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few years, I’ve taken to using technology less and less in my daily life.
 I leave my phone in the car when going to a party or social event. I’ll only fetch it if I want to take a picture, and only after appreciating the moment I’d like to capture to the fullest. When I listen to music on my phone (via headphones) during the long walks I take to get exercise and relax, I don’t check my phone at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What it&#39;s like a year after quitting Facebook</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/what-its-like-a-year-after-quitting-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/what-its-like-a-year-after-quitting-facebook/</guid>
      <description>Just under a year ago, I quit Facebook. Yup. After a decade of using it frequently, with over 10,000 posts and 7,000 pictures.
It was the best decision I made.
The original premise of Facebook has always appealed to me: connect with others you know in real life, but online, in order to share pictures and information to keep current. But it also has a lot of negatives:
 It often becomes your main method of communication to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Nokia tells us about the Internet in 2008</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/what-nokia-tells-us-about-the-internet-in-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/what-nokia-tells-us-about-the-internet-in-2008/</guid>
      <description>While cleaning out a drawer last night, I came across my old, beloved Nokia N810 Internet appliance that I bought in early 2008. This thing was sexy and entirely made of aluminum. It had a touchscreen (and stylus), backlit slide-out keyboard, expandable SD storage, GPS and front-facing webcam running Maemo Linux on an ARM CPU.
The N810 came out shortly after the iPhone in 2007, and just before Android phones started hitting the market en mass in 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three reasons why incubators breed failure</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/three-reasons-why-incubators-breed-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/three-reasons-why-incubators-breed-failure/</guid>
      <description>These past few years, I’ve provided various types of support for some tech incubators in the Kitchener-Waterloo region where I live (it’s a complex arrangement that I won’t go into within this post, but mostly involves helping people with technology implementation issues related to software). It’s not hard to find tech incubators nowadays - they’ve become quite popular this past decade, and larger cities often have several incubators of various sizes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the cloud grew up around Linux</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-the-cloud-grew-up-around-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-the-cloud-grew-up-around-linux/</guid>
      <description>Open source software has had a powerful effect on computing. When the ARPANET/NSFNET was sold to different companies in the 1990s to create the commercial Internet, nobody expected it to grow as fast as it did. It was the open source Apache Web server running on the open source Linux (and BSD UNIX) operating system that ultimately allowed the Internet to grow quickly and attract the attention of the world. Apache on Linux allowed anyone with a computer and Internet connection to implement a Web server to serve Web pages as part of the World Wide Web of Internet resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain for IT pros</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/blockchain-for-it-pros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/blockchain-for-it-pros/</guid>
      <description>IT professionals are often asked to describe technologies to others within their organization, and this includes buzz words they may have heard in some tech article or trade magazine:
There’s definitely no shortage of these buzz words in the tech industry - “the cloud,” “the Web 2.0,” “XaaS,” “CyberSecurity,” and of course “bitcoin” and “blockchain” are layered as thick as possible within articles and blogs to bolster clicks, likes and shares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halt and Catch Fire</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/halt-and-catch-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/halt-and-catch-fire/</guid>
      <description>Halt and Catch Fire is an AMC television series that ran for four seasons from 2014-2017, and covers the culture and pivotal aspects of the computing industry from 1983 (just after the release of the IBM PC) to 1994 (when the Internet and World Wide Web exploded).
You can binge watch it on Netflix if you like today, and trust me - you won’t be disappointed! Halt and Catch Fire is the best drama I’ve ever seen - an emotional rollercoaster like no other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 years of Facebook humour</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/10-years-of-facebook-humour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/10-years-of-facebook-humour/</guid>
      <description>While most of my posts are pictures (funny pictures, persona pictures, memes, etc.), I’ve also got lots of funny text posts. I got a chuckle out of reading them again, so I thought I’d share them here for others to enjoy!
Here they are, sorted from newest to oldest:
If you want to rapidly get through a crowded area, just carry a clipboard and try to make eye contact with people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Wide Web turns 25 years old today</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/www-turns-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/www-turns-25/</guid>
      <description>On August 6, 1991, Tim Berners-Lee created a post detailing his World Wide Web project on a newsgroup called alt.hypertext in order to entice others to collaborate with him and create and host Web pages for the World Wide Web. However, it wasn’t until August 23, 1991 that it was made publicly accessible for the world to see. You could argue that August 6 is the real birth of the World Wide Web, but most websites and news aggregators acknowledge August 23 as the true birth of the World Wide Web, including Facebook, which included it as a news item today for everyone!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look back at the dotcom bubble</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-dotcom-bubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-dotcom-bubble/</guid>
      <description>Just over a decade ago, the dotcom bubble burst, and for the next 3-4 years, the IT industry (and IT job market) was in a slump.
During the last presentation I did for Game On 2.0 on August 29th, one of the audience members asked me what the dotcom bubble actually was. I supplied the standard Web answer of “overspending in the IT market” and “mismanagement of IT resources” (or something like that).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reddit took down my website!</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/reddit-took-down-my-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/reddit-took-down-my-site/</guid>
      <description>Yup - I woke up Saturday to find the message above when I visited my website. I’ve used Primus (Planet Domain) for the past 8 years as a hosting provider, and I’ve never had any issues whatsoever - including reaching my bandwidth cap.
For starters, I was a little concerned, so I logged into my cpanel and checked out the AWSTATS first:
Holy crap! Did I just get too much traffic this month?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marshall McLuhan was right</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/marshall-mcluhan-was-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/marshall-mcluhan-was-right/</guid>
      <description>Everyone understands, to some degree, the impact that technology has on our lives. However, if you are an avid reader of “idea” books (for lack of a better word), then you also know that some people understand it poorly at best.
Take, for example, the book The Shallows by Nicholas Carr. Carr argues that the Internet has reduced our ability to carefully reason through problems and use our imagination. And plenty of people have taken the time to carefully point out the flaws in his views.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the term &#39;cloud&#39; was invented</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-the-term-cloud-was-coined/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/how-the-term-cloud-was-coined/</guid>
      <description>Back in the 1990s, you could look smart my talking about the “Information Superhighway” (the Internet). In the early 2000s, the catch-phase of the day was “eCommerce” (buying crap on the Internet), and in the late 2000s non-technical managers would often toot about “Web 2.0” (an imaginary Internet that basically is the current Internet, but with more content).
Around 2010, non-technical managers, CIOs, and executives were struggling to find a new BS phrase to call the Internet that will make them look good in meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QNX on a moon rover</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/qnx-on-a-moon-rover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/qnx-on-a-moon-rover/</guid>
      <description>Back in September 2011, a group of McMaster business and engineering students started a project aimed to build a moon rover that would be run by the QNX operating system on a BlackBerry PlayBook - a Canadian initiative with Canadian technologies (QNX is 100% Canadian). Here is a link to the original article on CrackBerry.com from the beginning of the project: https://crackberry.com/forums-new-group-aims-put-blackberry-playbook-powered-rover-moon
I reached out to them because of that article since I’ve had experience with QNX and PlayBook development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOPA and PIPA</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/sopa-and-pipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/sopa-and-pipa/</guid>
      <description>With the massive SOPA/PIPA website content blackout on January 18th (including major sites such as Wikipedia), the general public suddenly became far more educated on digital freedom issues.
The music and movie industry has amassed a fortune in the last 50 years selling music and movies before the dawn of the Internet. Back then, if you wanted music, you had to buy it on some physical medium such as a cassette tape or CD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google like a pro</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/using-google-like-a-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/using-google-like-a-pro/</guid>
      <description>Google is an extremely powerful set of tools (not just the search engine - Google apps as well!). However, few people really know how to find what they want using it. So here are a few tips you can use when using Google:
Putting quotes around a set of words tells Google to search for those words specifically as a single item - for example, to search only for cell phone radiation you could enter:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BCE, CE, and the new IE</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/bce-ce-ie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/bce-ce-ie/</guid>
      <description>I Google everything. What I find annoying is this: When you Google something that existed before the Internet and has no ongoing importance today (such as local landmarks that have since disappeared), there is literally NOTHING on the Internet about it.
For example, Leisure Lodge was a very large and glorious hall on the outskirts of Preston (now a part of Cambridge, Ontario) that was THE place to go from the 1950s to 1970s - they had their own big band group (the John Kostigian orchestra), and in the 1970s, they were the biggest disco joint around (they even hosted the Miss Nude World Competition one year).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funny Internet Shakespeare typo</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/funny-internet-shakespeare-typo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/funny-internet-shakespeare-typo/</guid>
      <description>I’m currently finishing the 3rd edition of my Guide To Linux Certification for Cengage. In Chapter 7, I used the following text from Shakespeare in the section on the stream editor (sed):
 Two households, both alike in dignity, In fair Verona, where we lay our scene, From ancient grudge break to new mutiny, Where civil blood makes civil hands unclean. From forth the fatal loins of these two foes A pair of star-cross’d lovers take their life; Whole misadventured piteous overthrows Do with their death bury their parents’ strife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jaron Lanier on technology</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/jaron-lanier-on-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/jaron-lanier-on-technology/</guid>
      <description>Jaron Lanier is a technologist who is known for coining the term “virtual reality” in the 1980s (he started VPL Research - the first virtual reality company).
I saw him speak during on the of the debates at the Quantum to Cosmos festival last year (a Pi Institute event in Waterloo, Ontario), and quickly Googled him (since he was the only person during the debate who actually said anything worth listening to).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright in Canada</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/copyright-in-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/copyright-in-canada/</guid>
      <description>Thirty years ago, people bought music on a record&amp;hellip;.a tangible thing like any other item for sale in a store. Now, people can download information (text, music, movies, etc.) from the Internet effortlessly. This copying of information has threatened the business models of many large and powerful companies such as music labels and movie producers. And these companies have reacted to their shrinking profits by abusing copyright and suing their customers rather than changing their business models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BlackBerry then and now</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/blackberry-then-and-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/blackberry-then-and-now/</guid>
      <description>You know - most technologies change drastically over time. As a result, I got my hands on an old BlackBerry 950 model from 1998 (the 850/950 series were the original BlackBerry smartphones on the 800/900 MHz Mobitex networks, respectively).
The problem is this: It really hasn’t changed that much. Aside from the color and graphics, the BlackBerry 950 running BlackBerry Device Software 2.5 had pretty much the same applications and functionality as the BlackBerry 8830 running BlackBerry Device Software 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I created the Internet</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/i-created-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/i-created-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>Complete with blinking light! It&amp;rsquo;s amazing what you can make with a soldering iron and the spare electrical parts you have in your basement.
If you are wondering what the heck I am talking about, just watch the BBC sitcom “The IT Crowd” Series 3 Episode 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netscape RIP 1994-2008</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/netscape-rip-1994-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/netscape-rip-1994-2008/</guid>
      <description>When I read my Google news today and found out that AOL is no longer going to develop and support Netscape as of February 2008, the first thing that came to mind was: What the heck? I thought Netscape was already dead!
I always equated Netscape with older systems such as Windows 9x and SCO Unixware 7.1.2 (the only web browser that ran on its crappy GUI). I haven’t heard anyone who has used the browser in years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anniversary of the World Wide Web</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/anniversary-of-the-world-wide-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/anniversary-of-the-world-wide-web/</guid>
      <description>Do you remember the dawn of the Internet in the mid 1990s? Everyone was talking about the “Information Superhighway” (a cheesy term for the Internet back then) and how it would change everyone’s life. Then people starting talking about the World Wide Web (WWW) and email and facebook.
Still today, many people don’t know how to properly define the World Wide Web and the Internet. At dinner parties with non-geek friends, I like to bring this up by asking, “So, can anyone here tell me what the Internet and World Wide Web are?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server closet Buddha shrine</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/server-closet-buddha-shrine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/server-closet-buddha-shrine/</guid>
      <description>For the past 2 years, I have had a Buddha Shrine in the server closet in my office. I carefully researched proper Buddha Shrine requirements and styles on Google before I chose the above arrangement (Buddha must be elevated and surrounded by objects that represent tokens of life).
Why did I do this? Simple. To speed up our current Internet access and reduce the number of times that we need to reboot/reset classroom routers (when caches fill up, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Years security resolutions for 2006</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/new-years-security-resolutions-for-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/new-years-security-resolutions-for-2006/</guid>
      <description>1. Don’t give personal information to obtain documents on the web Many sites want you to register to get a free document or certain web page. What do you think they use your information for? Spam, spam and more spam. If you want to get these documents without putting in your personal information, simply put the URL for the site in http://bugmenot.com and get past the registration!
2. Protect against Viruses Use Firefox - Many spyware/malware/viruses have code that targets Internet Explorer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
