<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:33:10 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;What it&#x2019;s like a year after quitting Facebook&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, September 20, 2019&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Just under a year ago, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/12BF0F02-9173-4AC0-939E-D8CB973074F7"&gt;I quit Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;. Yup. After a decade of using it frequently, with over 10,000 posts and 7,000 pictures.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;It was the best decision I made.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;The original premise of Facebook has always appealed to me: connect with others you know in real life, but online, in order to share pictures and information to keep current. But it also has a lot of negatives: &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	It often becomes your main method of communication to others. &#xD;	&#x2022;	People who are manipulative in your life use it to be more so.&#xD;	&#x2022;	You often friend others you don&#x2019;t know. &#xD;	&#x2022;	You end up spending tons of time scrolling through posts, and check for new ones frequently during the day. &#xD;	&#x2022;	You are constantly seeing posts from outside your friend network that are specifically crafted to influence your thought process.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;So, what happens when you quit for a year?&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	You feel like you&#x2019;ve regained a much healthier relationship with the world around you. &#xD;	&#x2022;	You spend less time using technology, and the time you do spend is not wasted.&#xD;	&#x2022;	The people that matter keep talking to you (yes, actually talking, and not stalking).&#xD;	&#x2022;	If you need to text someone, you actually text their phone number (that they gave you in person) instead of using Facebook Messenger, or send them an email.&#xD;	&#x2022;	You become more perceptive when talking with others (subtle nuances are appreciated, and so on).&#xD;	&#x2022;	You leave your phone at home or in the car before going to social events, because you prefer to give your 100% at the event. &#xD;	&#x2022;	You notice people checking their phone in line at Starbucks and feel pity for them.&#xD;	&#x2022;	You realize that &#x201C;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;If you're not paying for it, you're not the customer - you're the one being sold.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#x201D;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Have I quit all social media? No. There are some other social media that I still use for very short periods of time during the day. I still use LinkedIn to build my professional reputation, and Twitter to follow fun people in my professional field. The quality of what I read on these two sites is well worth the very small amount of time I spend on them. And I still post the odd picture I want to share with others on Instagram.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;So, if you&#x2019;re thinking of ditching Facebook, here&#x2019;s my honest advice:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Don&#x2019;t ask anyone whether you should do it. &#xD;Just do it. &#xD;And be in control of how you communicate and when you use technology.&#xD;It&#x2019;s quite liberating.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="20_What_its_like_a_year_after_quitting_Facebook_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
