<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:41:45 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;We finally have technology for the masses&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Wednesday, November 18, 2015&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Although it&#x2019;s been a relatively boring year as far as technology WOWs go, there has been one very interesting feature of technology this year: 2015 is the first year where we are truly seeing &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;technology for the masses&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; for the first time, and it&#x2019;s largely due to hardware manufacturers, open source developers, and Microsoft:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Adequate hardware for running modern applications and operating systems is now cheap to manufacture. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; AMD and Intel are making inexpensive lower end versions of their modern CPUs with integrated graphics that are well suited for typical computer use.  Moreover, other component manufacturers are combining multiple technologies into a single inexpensive chip to lower costs - for example, a single chip can now provide for Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, and Ethernet functionality for under $1.&#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open source (completely free) software is everywhere now. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; What this means is that you don&#x2019;t need to spend money on software - you can ALWAYS find an open source application that will meet your needs.  Of course, this doesn&#x2019;t apply to the big blockbuster games....but those games are designed for high-end, expensive computers only.&#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Microsoft released Windows 10.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;  Windows 10 works extremely well with low-end hardware, and is the first version of Windows that is very easy/intuitive to use (it feels like Mac OS).&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;If you have ever helped a non-technical family member purchase an Internet-capable computer in the past few decades, you probably had to choose really cheap hardware to get it within their budget - it was likely a desktop computer instead of a laptop computer, and you needed to provide a lot of free tech support to help them set it all up.  &#xD;&#xD;However, this year was the first year where you could walk into a Best Buy or Staples and see rows of laptops for under $500 with an AMD K6/K8 or Intel Core i3/i5 CPU running Windows 10.  A quick poke around, and you&#x2019;d also find that the build quality of these laptops were pretty good too!  &#xD;&#xD;So, now you can just help your relative pick a single machine that fits their budget (no extra cables or peripherals) and they can use Windows 10 to download any other open source software they need.  And if they are ultra-cheap, they can take their laptop to any McDonalds or Starbucks to get free Wi-Fi ;-)&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="18_2015_-_Technology_is_finally_good_AND_cheap_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
