<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>about me on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/categories/about-me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in about me on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jasoneckert.github.io/categories/about-me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1. What do I do?</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/what-do-i-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/what-do-i-do/</guid>
      <description>Besides drinking vast quantities of caffeine and spending most of my free time enjoying the outdoors, I have taught, developed, and managed various technology courses at triOS College in Ontario (Canada) since 1998 in both our college and corporate training divisions.
Back in 2011, I took on a different title of Dean of Technology to salvage our video game programs, and it turned into a more strategic role where I was able to help shape the development of our Information Technology (IT), developer, and video game programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. My published books</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/my-published-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/my-published-books/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps one of my more famous achievements is the authoring of several textbooks for Course Technology, Cengage, Nelson, Thompson/Delmar and Wiley. I&amp;rsquo;ve listed their details in chronological order here (oldest to newest) with cover pictures below:
Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification (ISBN: 0-619-13004-0) front rear Guide to UNIX System Administration (ISBN: 0-619-13041-5) front rear Linux+ In Depth (ISBN: 1-59200-062-2) front rear MCSE Guide to Managing a Microsoft Windows Server 2003 Network (ISBN: 0-619-12029-0) front rear dedication Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification - 2nd Edition (ISBN: 0-619-21621-2) front rear Linux+ 2005 In Depth (ISBN: 1-59200-728-7) front rear Novell&amp;rsquo;s Guide to CompTIA&amp;rsquo;s Linux+ (Course 3060) (ISBN: 1-4188-3730-X) front rear SUSE Linux Enterprise Server Administration (Course 3037) (ISBN: 1-4188-3731-8) front rear Advanced SUSE Linux Enterprise Server Administration (Course 3038) (ISBN: 1-4188-3732-6) front rear Microsoft Windows Vista Guide (ISBN: 1-4188-3757-1) front rear dedication SUSE Linux Enterprise Desktop Administration (ISBN: 1-4283-2227-2) SUSE Linux Enterprise Server Security (Course 3075) (ISBN: 1-4283-2223-X) front rear Microsoft Official Academic Course (MOAC): Exchange Server 2007 Exam 70-236 (ISBN: 978-0-470-38029-1) front rear Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification - 3rd Edition (ISBN: 978-1-418-83721-1) front rear SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 11 Administration (ISBN: 978-1-111-54003-6) front rear Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification - International Edition (ISBN: 978-1-111-54153-8) Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification - 4th Edition (ISBN: 978-1-305-10716-8) front Linux+ and LPIC-1 Guide to Linux Certification - 5th Edition (ISBN: 978-1-337-56979-8) front Hands-On Windows Server 2019 - 3rd Edition (ISBN: 978-0-357-43615-8) front dedication Linux+ and LPIC-1 Guide to Linux Certification - 6th Edition (ISBN: 979-8-214-00080-0) front dedication Hands-On Windows Server 2022 - 4th Edition (ISBN: 979-8-214-01160-8) Available Dec 2024!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Personal Interests</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/personal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/bio/personal/</guid>
      <description>Parenting I am a happily divorced proud father of one. I’ve pretty much raised my daughter since she was 5 years old on my own, and yes, I’ve made school lunches, threw kids parties, went to great places (Ontario Science Centre, ROM, SportsWorld, Storybook Gardens, Disney World and more!), spent vacations camping/cottaging, and watched far too many Land Before Time movies. The picture on the left is my daughter while we were vacationing at Disney World in Florida over a decade ago.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
