<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:32:38 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Making use of old(er) technologies&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Saturday, December 3, 2016&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Since I don&#x2019;t have a comment section on my blog (which is a good thing), it&#x2019;s not uncommon for people to send me emails regarding my blog posts.  Some emails are from people who enjoyed reading my article and wanted to let me know, while others are from people who wanted to give me comments/feedback, share similar experiences, or want permission to use it somewhere (BTW - everything I write online is open source, so there&#x2019;s no need to ask for permission).&#xD;&#xD;I actually received half a dozen emails already from my last blog post (which is far more than normal), and one of them was:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hi Jason!&#xD;You may remember me from my Linux email back in July.  If not, thats fine too.&#xD;I wanted to drop you a line about your blog post on technologists.  &#xD;I&#x2019;m curious as to why you still want to use an old PowerBook to do PowerPoint presentations.  I have a G4 PowerBook too, but it&#x2019;s just a dust collector because its dirt slow by todays standards, it takes forever to boot, and no Web browsers are supported on it, and Office runs far slower on it than on any newer laptop like the cheap Asus netbook I bought last year for $200.  &#xD;Don&#x2019;t take this the wrong way, I liked the article a lot, and I agree with your points, but I&#x2019;m curious as to why you still use the PowerBook.  Is it just nostalgia or what?&#xD;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;I thanked the person for their email and said that I think my response would make a good blog post, so here we are! :D&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Firstly, there are some valid points in that email.  &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Although my PowerBook G4 was the last generation before Apple switched to Intel, by today&#x2019;s standards, a 1.5GHz PowerBook G4 with 1.25GB of RAM and a 5400RPM PATA/IDE hard disk really is slow to be honest.  &#xD;&#xD;And because the latest OS that Apple released for the laptop was 10.5 (which is ancient compared to the latest version, 10.12), support for pretty much everything app-wise went south long ago.   For example, after ignoring the warning that &#x201C;your Web browser is no longer supported&#x201D;, you&#x2019;ll quickly notice that browsing the Web sucks because newer parts of Web sites render very slowly at times.  Those sites were designed for faster computers and modern operating systems that evolved alongside the Web.  Moreover, the computer takes almost 2 minutes to fully boot up and 5-10 seconds to open a PPT from scratch while the hard drive is chugging away. Painful is a good word to describe the user experience, and I have no intention of using a computer like that just because of nostalgia.  &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Using older technologies in a way that isn&#x2019;t useful for productivity is part of the hobbyist realm only.  &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;For example, the Commodore 128 shown to the right has a homebrew wireless network card that is allowing it to ping Google.  Of course, you&#x2019;d never use a Commodore 128 for anything Internet-related today because it&#x2019;s too old.  Even trying to check email using a text-based email client is not productive by any definition. &#xD;&#xD;However, people create these things as a hobby only - whether it be the vintage Commodore community or the Arduino community or the Raspberry Pi community, it&#x2019;s just tinkering and fun.&#xD;&#xD;By the way, the World Of Commodore convention where I took this picture is running this weekend in Mississauga!&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;So, basically, I had to do something to make the PowerBook useful. &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;The first thing I did was install Debian Linux on it like I mentioned in this &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/F759B53F-F7EF-4F4F-8297-845613E70DAE"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; from last year.  After all, Linux is small and fast, and runs well on less hardware, right?  Well, I found that getting things like external projectors to work well with OpenOffice was like nailing Jello to a tree in Linux running on Apple hardware.  Plus, it was heavy, and wasn&#x2019;t really that fast or enjoyable to use, so it didn&#x2019;t get much use at all.&#xD;&#xD;But I really liked this laptop, and its small size was perfect for giving presentations. So I decided to make two important modifications to it before reinstalling Mac OS 10.5:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Modification #1:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; I removed the heavy lithium cells from the removable battery enclosure, reassembled the battery enclosure and put it back into the PowerBook.  Although this means I have to use the power adapter during presentations, it made the PowerBook incredibly light and a pleasure to use!  The battery enclosure is still in the PowerBook, it&#x2019;s just empty.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Modification #2:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; I replaced the 5400RPM Toshiba hard drive with a 32GB PATA/IDE MLC-based SSD drive.  Since the machine will only be used for PPTs, 32GB was more than enough since Mac OSX and Office take less than 9GB, and at a price of $40 shipped from China, it was a cheap modification.  &#xD;&#xD;Although the PATA/IDE bus and Mac OS 10.5 don&#x2019;t support the TRIM feature of SSDs, PATA/IDE SSDs have the equivalent functionality in their controller - coupled with fast MLC flash (compared to the slower TLC flash you find in budget SSDs),  I thought that this would make a big difference in the speed of the computer, and I was 100% correct!  &#xD;&#xD;The PowerBook now fully boots in under 15 seconds, and it only takes about 1-2 seconds to open a PPT from scratch.  In fact, even Web browsing is fairly fast (although you still get the warning that your browser is no longer supported).  In other words, it&#x2019;s now as fast as a cheap modern laptop or netbook, and I only had to spend $40.  Best of all, I made my beloved PowerBook into a useful machine by today&#x2019;s standards.  It&#x2019;s actually a very nice PowerPoint machine ;-)&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="3_Making_use_of_old%28er%29_technologies_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
