<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:32:38 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The Legacy of Commodore Computer&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Wednesday, December 7, 2016&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Newer generations probably haven&#x2019;t even heard of a Commodore computer. &#xD;But for my generation - the generation that created the Internet, the World Wide Web, and modern computing - Commodore was often our first love, and what drove us into computing and technology.  If it weren&#x2019;t for Commodore, I wouldn&#x2019;t have pursued computer science and followed the path that led me to where I am today - instead, I may have become a chef or an accountant or a lawyer.  Who knows.....&#xD;&#xD;Not only was the 1980s an amazing decade, it was the dawn of personal computing.  In 1980, if you wanted a color computer to play games and write programs on, you had to fork over a few thousand dollars for an Apple II.  As a result, most people didn&#x2019;t have a computer at home at the beginning of that decade.  A few hobbyists had them, and schools often had one or two in their library, but that was it.  Then, in 1981, a company called Commodore released a color computer called the VIC-20 for $299 that was almost as powerful as an Apple II.  Why?  Because the founder of Commodore Computer, Jack Tramiel, wanted to make computers for the masses, not the classes as shown in this tribute I found on the Internet:  &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Suddenly, everyone I knew had a VIC-20 at home.  Games and software for it started pouring in like crazy from all around the world. The very next year, Commodore released the infamous Commodore 64 that simply blew away the Apple II hardware in every way possible for an introductory price of $599.  It was also the first computer to do image processing (a.k.a. sprite processing) in the hardware, allowing for very rapid game development.  And as the cost of manufacturing it went down over the next year, so did the price, until it was a mere $199.  Commodore killed the market.  Everyone had a Commodore VIC-20, or the ultra-powerful Commodore 64, and the available software library eclipsed that of all other computers combined at the time.  In other words, if you wanted a piece of software, you could always get it for Commodore.  Still today, the Commodore 64 retains the record for the best selling computer of all time......ever!&#xD;&#xD;My school had a whole lab of Commodore 64s that we used extensively.  However, the Commodore that my parents bought for the family when I was growing up was the Commodore 128 (a beefed up Commodore 64 with more RAM, dual CPUs and a ton of extra functionality).   The lead engineer who created the Commodore 128 was Bil Herd, who gave a presentation at the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tpug.ca/world-of-commodore-16/presentations/"&gt;World of Commodore conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; in Mississauga last weekend - the picture at the top of this blog post is of him at the conference.  It&#x2019;s definitely a bit of a surreal feeling to meet the maker of the home computer you used when growing up ;-)&#xD;&#xD;On the second day of the conference, they screened the documentary  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;8-bit Generation: The Commodore Wars&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/rqrFnW"&gt;https://goo.gl/rqrFnW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;).&#xD;&#xD;The documentary will be officially released on Steam later this month.  It details the early days of the personal computer revolution with specific focus on Commodore.  It&#x2019;s narrated by Bil Herd, and chalked full of interviews from people such as Jack Tramiel (Commodore), Steve Wozniak (Apple), Al Alcorn (Atari), Nolan Bushnell (Atari), Jeff Minter (Llamasoft), Chuck Peddle (MOS), John Roach (Tandy), and much much more.&#xD;&#xD;The documentary was both incredibly nostalgic and educational for me.  I got to see how and why Commodore made such an impact on my generation, and it gave me a heightened appreciation for that time in my life.  That being said, this documentary isn&#x2019;t just for my generation - it&#x2019;s for everyone. After all, Commodore played an incredibly important historical role. They brought computers to the masses for the first time in history, inspiring millions of people to embrace computers and technology in general.  And by doing so, they jumpstarted the personal computing revolution!&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="7_The_Legacy_of_Commodore_Computer_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
