<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200627" date="2020-06-28 02:22:00 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;My foray into competitive arcade gaming&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Saturday, July 25, 2015&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Humans have been playing games for thousands of years - after all, playing games is fundamental to human development and learning.  On a basic level, the term &#x201C;competitive gaming&#x201D; refers to when people compete against others to win a game, whether it be a simple game of Chess, or a large game competition.  Today, however, competitive gaming often refers to those who compete on a regional or worldwide level within a video game.&#xD;&#xD;Competitive gaming is a massive endeavor that requires a great deal of time and effort.  And in order to understand competitive gaming, you have to first understand why anyone would undertake such a massive endeavor.&#xD;&#xD;At a fundamental level, you can play games to:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	a)	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Have a good time&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (have fun, get thrills, be entertained, etc.), or&#xD;	b)	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Achieve something&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (get rewards, get points, get to the end of the game, etc.)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;While many games cater to both factors, our human brains treat them very differently.&#xD;In other words, playing a game to achieve something doesn&#x2019;t necessarily mean that you&#x2019;re having a good time.  And having a good time playing a game doesn&#x2019;t mean that you&#x2019;re necessarily achieving something.&#xD;&#xD;When it comes to competitive gaming, &#x201C;achieving something&#x201D; is the primary motivator that allows someone to spend a massive amount of time and effort.  It&#x2019;s also the at the core of most gaming addiction too - for example, a gamer with a gaming addiction may HAVE to play a bit longer in Farmville to get to the next bonus, or HAVE to spend more time in World of Warcraft to build up their character.  For competitive gamers, they HAVE to get the top score on a particular video game to be the best in their region/country/world.  Having a good time doesn&#x2019;t factor into it very much at all - it&#x2019;s the achievement they are searching for that drives them.&#xD;&#xD;Now, let&#x2019;s switch gears to my favorite type of gaming: retro arcade gaming.&#xD;&#xD;At their heart, retro arcade games are games full of simple and fun gameplay mechanics that allow someone to have a good time for about 2-3 minutes (the average time that arcade game designers target before the average player loses their 3 lives.....and their quarter ;-).  Whether it&#x2019;s eating dots in Pac-man, or avoiding cars in Frogger, there are plenty a cheap thrill to be had with one quarter on a retro arcade game!&#xD;&#xD;Another side effect of having simple mechanics is that retro arcade games have patterns and strategies that can be learned easily if you play them again and again (just as Adam Sandler says in the movie &#x201C;Pixels&#x201D; that came out this week).  These patterns and strategies attract the more tenacious players who want to spend many more quarters to master the game and get a top score.&#xD;&#xD;All of this can be summed up with Bushnell&#x2019;s Law (named after Nolan Bushnell, the founder of Atari): &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;All the best games are easy to learn and difficult to master. They should reward the first quarter and the hundredth.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;In the 1980s, there were some players who had access to a lot of quarters and played the arcade games at their local video arcade competitively to get top scores.  There are at least a few documentaries on these gamers, including &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Chasing Ghosts: Beyond the Arcade &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;(2007)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The King of Kong: A Fistful of Quarters&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (2007).&#xD;&#xD;However, for most of us that didn&#x2019;t have unlimited funds back in the early 1980s, competitive gaming wasn&#x2019;t possible.  After all, it took a lot of quarters to get good! Today, competitive retro arcade gaming is starting to resurface again because arcade machines from the 1980s and 1990s are relatively cheap to purchase and restore....and you don&#x2019;t need quarters when you have the keys to the coin door of the arcade game!  &#xD;&#xD;I got into collecting and restoring arcade games back in 2012 and since got the competitive gaming bug. The game that did it for me was Galaga.  I loved Galaga back in the 80s, but didn&#x2019;t play it enough to get very good at it.  That all changed when I picked up a working Galaga cabinet for $90 and put it in my basement.  Not only did I enjoy playing the game for short periods of time (it&#x2019;s a VERY fun game), I loved to learn and master the patterns and mechanics in each level.  &#xD;&#xD;I started making milestones for myself - the first was to break 150,000 points, the second was to get past all 8 challenge stages (after which they repeat), and the third was to break a million points (the score rolls over after 999,999).  I achieved all of these milestones within a month (playing at least a few times per day and encoding techniques into muscle memory), and then my focus shifted to doing it with different difficulty settings and losing a minimal number of ships.  &#xD;&#xD;Was I having fun while trying to reach my milestones?  No.  I was focused, and I&#x2019;m sure my blood pressure was a bit higher than usual.  But when I achieved a milestone for the first time, I was incredibly happy for days afterwards.....after all, I was playing to achieve something, and I did.  With competitive gaming, the joy comes AFTER you win ;-)&#xD;&#xD;Not all Galaga games were focused and competitive during this time - I played many times a week (usually seated at my Galaga cocktail) just for fun and to try different moves.  And I did really have fun - after completing all 8 challenge stages (about 300,000 points for those interested), I always let my remaining ships die and would go back upstairs for a drink.&#xD;&#xD;But the lure of competitive gaming isn&#x2019;t easy to shake.  I ended up buying 4 more Galaga machines with different form factors (upright, cabaret, cocktail table), and set each one to different difficulty levels to keep me out of my comfort zone.  After 3 years, I had beaten the world record by a large margin on Tournament settings (5 lives, hardest difficulty).  Other arcade collectors in the local game community who saw me play past a million points without losing a ship constantly told me I should go to Funspot with a video camera and go for the world record.  &#xD;&#xD;At one point, I was ready to do it (it was scheduled for this August), but some things happened that changed my mind.  &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Firstly, word got out that I was going for a world record.  That led to people calling me (mostly from the US) who wanted me to break the record at their place or venue - they wanted &#x201C;exclusivity&#x201D; - and I remember thinking to myself &#x201C;It&#x2019;s just a freaking video game.&#x201D;  &#xD;	&#x2022;	Secondly, I started not to enjoy the competitive side of Galaga as much.  I spent most of 2015 playing focused/competitive Galaga on a wide variety of different machines just so that I could be assured of beating the world record.  I wasn&#x2019;t having fun, and I already achieved more than the world record score several times previously, so there was no milestone to hit that was driving me forward.  &#xD;	&#x2022;	Thirdly, I got a Burgertime arcade machine (an incredibly fun and silly game that is coveted amongst collectors).  It may sound absurd, but playing Burgertime the night I got it was the pivotal moment that put everything into perspective and made my realize that something was wrong with what I was doing with Galaga.  I&#x2019;ve achieved a lot of great things in my life that make getting a high score on Galaga look like child&#x2019;s play, and the reason I collect and play these games is because I love the fun gameplay, patterns and strategies.  So what was I doing with this competitive crap?!?  I cancelled my plans the next day and went to Sonny&#x2019;s for a burger and fries with the dog. &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;There&#x2019;s nothing wrong with setting milestones and being a competitive gamer on a particular arcade machine, but there&#x2019;s a point where you have to limit yourself - a point where you say &#x201C;this is what I want to get out of this game.&#x201D;  This happy medium is essentially the one thing that is different from competitive gaming and gaming addiction - those who are addicted to a particular game can&#x2019;t step back and define their happy medium.&#xD;&#xD;I should note that I still enjoy learning new patterns and strategies.  I&#x2019;m currently spending a large amount of time playing Burgertime and Dig Dug doing just that and lovin&#x2019; it.  I just don&#x2019;t think I&#x2019;ll ever be in a position to get close to a world record on them.  But that&#x2019;s OK - I&#x2019;m playing these games for myself :-)&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="25_My_foray_into_competitive_arcade_gaming_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
