<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200627" date="2020-06-28 02:21:53 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The weird world of arcade collecting...&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Monday, November 25, 2013&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;If you asked me why I collect arcades, I&#x2019;d probably say something like &#x201C;it&#x2019;s fun&#x201D; and &#x201C;it allows me to relax &#x201C; and &#x201C;it allows me to think about things easily&#x201D; and &#x201C;it keeps my mind focused and sharp&#x201D; and then I&#x2019;d probably get frustrated because it&#x2019;s near impossible to describe why I collect arcades......and tell you to just watch this video of Molly Atkinson because I identify perfectly with her reasons for collecting pinball machines (just replace &#x201C;pinball&#x201D; with &#x201C;arcade&#x201D; in my case): &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/60632624"&gt;http://vimeo.com/60632624&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &#xD;&#xD;And while there are some people that I&#x2019;ve met in the arcade community that are very similar to myself (and Molly), the arcade community is much more varied.&#xA0; This is probably because you can get arcade machines much cheaper today than you can get pinball machines, so there is a much larger group of people who buy them.&#xA0; And yes, some of them are pretty weird ;-)&#xD;&#xD;I recently read Rob O&#x2019;Hara's book "Invading Spaces: A Beginner&#x2019;s Guide to Collecting Arcade Games" (2008), and he describes a few arcade collector stereotypes in one of his chapters, so I thought it would be fun to expand on this list with the help from some CGCC (Classic Game Collectors Canada) forum members. &#xD;&#xD;So here is the expanded list of different arcade collector stereotypes for you to enjoy (I&#x2019;m more of a combination of Molly, #3, and #6).&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. The Opportunist&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &#x2013; Often only have 1 or 2 arcades, but believe they can pay for their kid&#x2019;s university education by selling them.&#xA0; Their machines are continually listed on Kijiji for several years and they wonder why no one replies. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. The Player&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &#x2013; These collectors are in it to play the games with their buddies. Who needs an Xbox when you have arcades?&#xA0; They often have several arcades, do little-to-no work on them because they regularly trade or sell them in order to get new ones and keep things fresh. Consequently, they usually own a pickup truck and have a garage. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. The Professional Player &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#x2013; These collectors often have a few games that they play incredibly well and could probably beat the Twin Galaxies record if they wanted to.&#xA0; They play hard and often, and tune their machines for the gameplay.&#xA0; It isn&#x2019;t uncommon for them to have a spare PCB just in case there are problems with the current one, and they&#x2019;ll drop some serious coin on parts if they need to.&#xA0; A true vidiot. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;4. The Hoarder &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#x2013; These collectors have a LOT of arcades that they rarely play. Quantity over quality is the general idea here, so don&#x2019;t expect too many popular games, or games that are in good condition. They could be on a future reality TV show... &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;5. The Hacker &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#x2013; These collectors buy whatever they can get cheap, and Frankenstein or mod the crap out of it.&#xA0; For these people, an Asteroids cab with a Pengo bezel and NeoGeo marquee running a 60-in-1 board alongside an LCD monitor they found in the garbage is a beautiful thing. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;6. The Restoration Expert&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &#x2013; These collectors often have popular arcade games (e.g. Pac-man, Defender, etc.), and get their kicks out of stripping them down and restoring them to their former glory inside and out. They usually have a big workshop, and end up selling the machine some time after restoring it for a fair price in order to fund the next restoration project. These guys are the absolute best people to buy an arcade from if you have the money. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;7. The Worshipper &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#x2013; These collectors often buy popular arcade games in bad shape for little money, and spend years trying to keep them as original as possible.&#xA0; They typically don&#x2019;t play their arcades, since they are &#x201C;collector items.&#x201D;&#xA0; As a result, the machines get turned on only for a few moments when friends come over, but are quickly turned off in case the additional stress causes the power supply, PCB or monitor to die. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;8. The Multicader &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#x2013; These collectors often buy a single nice arcade cabinet (or fix one up), and throw in a nice multicade board (e.g. a 412-in-1) or a good MAME PC and JPac board. Drilling a few extra holes for the additional buttons in the original control panel doesn&#x2019;t bother them because they just want a nice arcade machine that plays a ton of games for their kids, themselves, and when friends and family come over. They may also do one up for a friend or family member too, but you won&#x2019;t find a ton of machines in their home. &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;9. The Multicade Entrepreneur&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &#x2013; To fund other purchases, these collectors often buy a bunch of old arcade cabinets in any condition, Windex them, throw in a 60-in-1 multicade PCB, and sell them to others. There&#x2019;s darn good money to be made doing this (depending on your area). NOTE: There is also a category of collectors who can be described as "Jealous of The Multicade Entrepreneur" &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;10. The Shady Re-seller / Ambulance Chaser &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;- More interested in money over the hobby, trying to troll-flip-steal-lie their way around true players/collectors. No integrity. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;11. The Underprivileged Player &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#x2013; Like #2 (The Player), these collectors are in it to play the games with their buddies and often have several arcades. However, they do little-to-no work on them primarily because they have limited repair skills. They often buy junk, hoping that it will be gold, and don't own a truck or have a garage. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;12. The Eternal Optimist &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;- These collectors acquire cheap "fixer-uppers" of their favorite games and all the parts to restore them. However, they don't actually have any time to actually restore or play them. Plus, they usually don't own a pickup or van, since that would simply mean drowning in 4 times as many projects...&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="25_The_weird_world_of_arcade_collecting..._files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
