<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:32:49 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Installing a Ms.Pac-man multigame save kit&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, March 18, 2018&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;If you&#x2019;ve read other parts of my site, you already know that I collect vintage arcade games.  &#xD;&#xD;Back in January, I traded some stuff for some arcade parts, and one of the things I got was a brand new Pac-man/Ms.Pac-man Multigame High Score Save Kit from HighScoreSaves.com (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.highscoresaves.com/pacman-ms-pacman-multigame-high-score-save-kit.html"&gt;https://www.highscoresaves.com/pacman-ms-pacman-multigame-high-score-save-kit.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;).  My daughter came over for dinner that same day, and since she thought it was neat, we decided to install it in my Ms. Pac-man cocktail table and see if it worked.  It did.....and it was awesome!&#xD;&#xD;The kit itself consists of a bunch of replacement chips on small circuit boards, as well as a replacement daughter board (the small circuit board that contains the Z80 CPU on a Ms. Pac-man game).  And each of these circuit board and daughter board replacements are interconnected via a series of ribbon cables:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;My daughter and I pulled the original circuit board out of the game and made sure we documented the original components just in case it didn&#x2019;t work and we had to revert back to them.  Next, we replaced all the necessary components, added the ribbon cables and stuck it back in the Ms. Pac-man cocktail table:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;As soon as we powered it on it worked perfectly!  It took us a little while to figure out that you had to hold down the 1-player start button for a few seconds in order to get to the game choice screen though:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Now, I can play far more than Ms.Pac-man on this old arcade machine, including the fast versions, and it will save my high scores in a high score table (original Pac-man/Ms.Pac-man games never had a high score table).  Plus, there are a ton of settings you can tweak for each game, including the ability to start at level 255 so you can see the infamous &#x201C;kill screen&#x201D;, or even fix the infamous kill screen bug to allow you to go past level 255 too!  &#xD;&#xD;Since we installed this kit, I&#x2019;ve played this arcade machine more than I&#x2019;ve ever played it in the past - I absolutely love the Plus and Fast versions of each game, as well as the ability to permanently save top scores. So, if you have an original Pac-man or Ms.Pac-man arcade machine, I highly recommend installing this kit to make it even more fun than it was before!&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="18_Installing_a_Ms.Pac-man_multigame_save_kit_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
