<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:40:43 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The rise and fall of the Canadian arcade&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Saturday, January 19, 2013&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Laura June of The Verge published a great article on Wednesday entitled &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;For Amusement Only: the life and death of the American arcade&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; - you can read it here:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/1/16/3740422/the-life-and-death-of-the-american-arcade-for-amusement-only"&gt;http://www.theverge.com/2013/1/16/3740422/the-life-and-death-of-the-american-arcade-for-amusement-only&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;There are some excellent points that Laura makes in this article and some great visuals and interviews in the associated video documentary on the same page.&#xA0; However, there were some important things about the rise and eventual demise of video arcade culture that she left out.&#xA0; I&#x2019;ll summarize her great article and add those things, as well as discuss what was similar and dissimilar between American and Canadian arcades.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#1 - Summary of For Amusement Only: the life and death of the American arcade:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Video arcades were an evolution of pinball arcades, and many video game arcades had at least a few pinball machines.&#xA0; They were noisy, dark (to see the screen better), didn&#x2019;t sell food or drink, and often didn&#x2019;t have an age restriction.&#x2028;&#xD;	&#x2022;	Video arcades were found nearly everywhere, including shopping malls and roller rinks. They were safe places where kids and teenagers could hang out. &#x2028;&#xD;	&#x2022;	1978-1982 saw video arcades proliferate across the country and turn huge profits.&#xA0; However, the growth was too much - there were too many arcades, and many arcades bought more games than their players could support.&#xA0; &#x2028;&#xD;	&#x2022;	The mid-1980s saw a big slump in the arcade industry and home video game industry in general.&#xA0; The Nintendo NES brought back the home video game industry, and the introduction of the Street Fighter II arcade game in 1991 brought back many of the arcades during the 1990s.&#x2028;&#xD;	&#x2022;	Today, there are very few arcades left, and those that are left usually focus on redemption games (simple physical skill games that dispense tickets that players use to win prizes), or use arcade games as a novelty to draw customers (e.g. the Barcade - a bar with retro arcades that makes their $$ on drinks only). &#x2028;&#xD;	&#x2022;	Video arcades suffered a constant stigma that dated back to gambling and pinball machines.&#xA0; Although studies have showed that video games have a multitude of benefits, society has largely focused on portraying video games in a negative light (e.g. video game violence, corruption of youth, Rock&#x2019;n&#x2019;Roll, blah, blah, blah).&#x2028;&#xD;	&#x2022;	Parents had a laid-back attitude about what their kids did during the day until the late 1980s, but in the 1990s, society balked at having places where kids could hang out alone with other kids.&#xA0; And this included video arcades.&#x2028;&#xD;	&#x2022;	Games became much more expensive over time - instead of a quarter, games started costing $1, which is very expensive for 3 minutes of play.&#x2028;&#xD;	&#x2022;	Kids started playing more and more video games at home - one arcade owner said that his kids spend their money only on iPad games.&#x2028;&#xD;	&#x2022;	The main people interested in buying arcade games today are collectors who grew up with the games and want them in their home.&#x2028;&#xD;	&#x2022;	Nolan Bushnell (founder of Atari and Chuck E. Cheese&#x2019;s) thinks that society has lost something with the death of the American arcade (or what he calls &#x201C;loosely-formed clubhouses&#x201D;).&#xA0; He thinks that arcades will come back, but in a radically different form.&#xA0; Nearly everyone else disagrees with him though.....&#x2028;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#2 - Additional points about the rise and death of arcade culture:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;I love all of the points within the article, however, there are some additional things I&#x2019;d like to add.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Firstly, when it comes to the rise of the video arcade, there were other factors that led to its massive growth during 1978-1982.&#xA0; It was the dawn of the personal computing era, and a time of intense optimism with technology of any kind.&#xA0; People wanted to play with technology, and video arcades were a way to do that without having a home computer.&#xA0; Moreover, those who did buy a home computer primarily bought it to play video games (the other stuff was really a nice bonus) - this boosted both the home computer industry and the video game industry to amazing new heights, which ultimately encouraged people to attend arcades to play video games in a social atmosphere.&#xA0; Up until arcade games, kids and teenagers really didn&#x2019;t have anything other than bike riding and sports to do in a social atmosphere.&#xA0; In other words, video games added a whole new dimension to the social atmosphere for kids and teenagers - one that was mentally stimulating too!&#xD;&#xD;Secondly, when it comes to the death of the arcade, I definitely agree with the reasons mentioned in this article, but I&#x2019;d like to add a few more key points:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Arcade games in the early 1980s were extremely technologically advanced compared to home computers and video game consoles - as a result, the video games in the video arcade were massively better than their home counterparts.&#xA0; However, by the early 1990s, home computers and video game consoles started to get very powerful, and by the late 1990s, video arcades really had nothing to offer (graphics, gameplay) beyond what you could get at home.&#xA0; And most people had a home computer or game console by that time.&#x2028;&#xD;	&#x2022;	Consequently, the social atmosphere of the video arcade was replaced by a home-based social atmosphere.&#xA0; Kids just went over to their friend&#x2019;s houses to play video games, and when games started using the Internet for cooperative play, people stayed at home and played online with their friends.&#x2028;&#xD;	&#x2022;	Additionally, in the 1990s, games got longer and cheaper.&#xA0; You could buy a Sonic game for $25 and get over 100 hours of play out of it with your friends.&#xA0; Or you could buy a game like Myst on your PC and get 200 hours of play out of it.&#xA0; Or you could go to a video arcade and blow $10 in half an hour on games that cost $1 to play.&#xA0; &#x2028;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;I&#x2019;d also like to mention something about the death of the American arcade that I haven&#x2019;t seen covered in any article I&#x2019;ve read:&#xA0; the intense optimism associated with the arcade era really hasn&#x2019;t disappeared.&#xA0; It simply changed focus.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;In the 1980s, arcades had massive appeal because they brought together the best of technology in a social atmosphere.&#xA0; It was the dawn of the computing era.&#xA0; By the 1990s, most kids and teenagers had a computer and/or a powerful video game console, and spent their time exploring the plethora of bleeding-edge games that could run on them.&#xA0; The intense optimism was still there, but focused on a newer technology.&#xA0; I remember seeing LucasArts&#x2019; Day of the Tentacle and thinking how movies and video games would merge in the future.&#xA0; It was just as exciting as going to a video arcade and visualizing a future like the one shown in the movie Tron.&#xA0; Collaborative play?&#xA0; Sure - you just brought your friends over to your house to play the video games together.&#xA0; Competition?&#xA0; Sure - bragging rights were done at school, or in competitions, on in the dozens of video game magazines that started in the 1990s.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;This evolved rapidly, and by the early 2000s, computer and console games were quite advanced both in graphics and in gameplay.&#xA0; And this evolution was just as motivating to players as the arcade experience of the 1980s. I remember getting Halo on the Xbox as soon as it came out and playing it for 14 hours straight with a friend of mine in my living room.&#xA0; The game&#x2019;s story line, artificial intelligence and graphics were out of this world - talk about optimism!&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Today, technology is also making leaps and bounds in the mobile space - almost everyone has a smartphone and can play their games on it.&#xA0; Plus, computer and console games have evolved into the ultra-realistic works of art I always knew they would.&#xA0; Want to play with others?&#xA0; Invite them over to your place or play with them across the Internet anywhere in the world.&#xD;&#xD;So......the arcade spirit is not dead - kids, teenagers, and even adults get just as excited about playing games today.&#xA0; They possess the key ingredient that made arcades so attractive: intense optimism about games and technology.&#xA0; However, they play these games using advanced technology in their homes with others in the same room or across the Internet.&#xA0; Nolan Bushnell&#x2019;s &#x201C;loosely formed clubhouses&#x201D; still exist today - they are just online and worldwide, and you can choose which clubhouse to join on Internet.&#xA0; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;The video arcade is online today.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;As a result, the death of the American arcade is as much about changes in culture as it is about changes in technology.&#xA0; Technology has changed dramatically over the past three decades, and the way we interact with it today doesn&#x2019;t fit the arcade model of the early 1980s.&#xA0;&#xA0; And that isn&#x2019;t such a bad thing when you think about it.&#xD;&#xD;Moreover, &#x201C;death&#x201D; is a strong word.&#xA0; Are the arcade games of the American arcade really dead? Maybe the crappy ones....but the good ones are alive and well.&#xA0; For example, kids and teenagers love Pac-man today.&#xA0; They love Asteroids.&#xA0; And they love Galaga.&#xA0; Why?&#xA0; Because they can play them on their computers, consoles and especially their smartphones!&#xA0; And because the 8-bit games of the early 1980s have simple, addictive, gameplay, they are well suited to playing on a mobile device in a subway, on a game console while waiting for supper, or within a browser on a computer when you are bored.&#xA0; The kids love them today as much as they did in the 1980s, and there is an added respect for retro games since they were the precursors to the awesome games of today.&#xA0; Today, we have the option to play many different types of games - not just the big ones with amazing graphics and long gameplay.&#xA0; Games like Minecraft (with 1980s-style pixelated graphics) are just as popular.&#xA0; There is, and always will be, room for the arcade classics of the 1980s - we just play them on different devices today.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#3 - How did Canadian arcades differ from American arcades?&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;In general, many Americans don&#x2019;t really know much about Canada, or have some sort of grudge against Canadians.&#xA0; The same is true when it comes to arcade gaming.&#xA0; In the book &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Supercade&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; by Van Burnham, after a Canadian beat the Ms. Pac-Man world record in 1998, Billy Mitchell (holder of the Pac-Man record) said that he &#x201C;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;felt that the Canadians were Johnny-come-latelys and needed to be put in their place.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#x201D;&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;In reality, however, nothing could be further from the truth.&#xA0; Canadians were not Johnny-come-latelys to the video arcade scene.&#xA0; During the golden age of video arcades, we had them all over the place in Canada - they looked the same, they operated the same way, they had the same arcade games, and the kids who went to them wore the same clothes and spoke the same language (bad English).&#xA0; There were video arcades in strip malls and downtown, and arcade machines in pretty much every corner store, roller rink, pizza parlor, movie theatre, bar and shopping mall.&#xA0; We played outside, and we rode our bikes or skateboards to the corner store to buy junk food and play arcade games until supper time when our parents expected us back. Kids and teenagers were just as crazy about arcade games in Canada as they were in the U.S. (the first arcade game I played was Space Invaders outside the K-Mart in the local mall).&#xA0; This shouldn&#x2019;t be too surprising since Canadians have the exact same computers, game consoles, movies, television, McDonalds, and culture. The only real cultural difference is that we call Coke &#x201C;pop&#x201D; instead of &#x201C;soda.&#x201D;&#xD;&#xD;While Laura&#x2019;s article said that most American arcades didn&#x2019;t sell food or drink, most of the Canadian ones I attended did.&#xA0; The arcade in the American movies &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Joysticks&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (1983) and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;War Games&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (1983) also sold food and drink, so I imagine that there were a fair chunk of arcades in the U.S. that did as well.&#xD;&#xD;One difference between Canada and the U.S. surrounds the video game crash of the mid 1980s.&#xA0; In Canada, we didn&#x2019;t experience as much of a drop in arcade popularity during the 1980s.&#xA0; I remember some arcades that closed their doors, but the majority of them stayed open and remained busy during the 1980s.&#xA0; A lot of this has to do with the way that Canadians run businesses in general.&#xA0; As a smaller country with high taxes, we are much cheaper and less likely to take risks than Americans.&#xA0; As a result, it was rare to find arcades that bought more machines than they could justify by their player base. &#xD;&#xD;Moreover, by the late 1980s, I remember there being a huge growth in arcades in my area, and this only amplified in the early 1990s (thank you Street Fighter II).&#xA0; Arcades were insanely popular in the late 1980s and early 1990s in Canada.&#xA0; However, by the mid 1990s, the decline of the arcade was very apparent.&#xA0; Just like the U.S., home games replaced the arcade by the late 1990s, and today arcades are extremely rare.&#xA0; I know of only two arcades in all of Ontario Canada, besides Chuck E. Cheese, Sony Playdium, and Dave &amp; Busters.&#xA0; Very similar to what was said in Laura&#x2019;s article.&#xA0; That being said, I still see arcade machines in some pizza parlors, highway rest stops, and bars, but they are usually crappy ones like Big Buck Hunter, or sit-down driving games.&#xD;&#xD;Perhaps the biggest difference between U.S. and Canadian arcades revolves around the stigma attached to the video arcade.&#xA0; Canadians are far more accepting and far less critical of new things.&#xA0; We often look at the bitter social debates people have over the silliest things in the U.S. with mild amusement.&#xA0; Consequently, there was very little stigma surrounding video arcades in Canada during the 1980s and 1990s.&#xA0; No towns tried to make them illegal or restrict them like many did in the U.S., and parents generally thought they were a good thing that stimulated hand-eye coordination.&#xA0; And I am glad for that ;-)&#xD;&#xD;Like the American arcade, the Canadian arcade of the 1980s and 1990s is dead, and I don&#x2019;t think it will ever return.&#xA0; There are still plenty of arcade game collectors, such as myself, who buy the remnants of the arcade era they remember and loved.&#xA0; And because arcade machines are largely unwanted, this is actually a very good time to buy arcades, both in the U.S. and in Canada.&#xA0; I bought my first arcade machine (a 1990 RAIDEN arcade) for $200 a year ago - and I thought it was a steal given its amazing shape.&#xA0; But you can find the same deals everywhere today.&#xA0; People just don&#x2019;t want arcades.&#xA0; If that isn&#x2019;t a surefire sign that the arcade is dead, I don&#x2019;t know what is. &#xD;&#xD;But, as I mentioned in the previous section, the arcade spirit is not dead.&#xA0; Nor are the arcade games of the 1980s and 1990s.&#xA0;&#xA0; We just live in a different time, and it&#x2019;s easier and better to play those games using modern technologies.&#xA0; In 50 years, I&#x2019;m confident that people will still get as excited about games and technology as we did in the arcades of 1982.&#xA0; And in 50 years, I&#x2019;m sure that people will still be playing Pac-man, Asteroids, and Galaga.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="19_Entry_1_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
