<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:56:36 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Are video games art?&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, April 12, 2013&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;When it comes to whether video games are art, people are very divided.&#xA0; One one side, you have people who argue that it isn&#x2019;t a proper art form because it doesn&#x2019;t fit the mold that other, more mature, art forms fit into.&#xA0; On the other extreme, you have people who argue that video games are a wholly new art form.&#xA0; Then there are people like Jim Preston (a game designer) who think that the whole question is silly:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;To think that there is a single, generally agreed upon concept of art is to get it precisely backwards. Americans' attitude towards art is profoundly divided, disjointed and confused; and my message to garners is to simply ignore the "is-it-art?" debate altogether.&#x2028;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;I&#x2019;ve always agreed with Jim Preston, and in this post, I&#x2019;ll detail why.&#xD;&#xD;Those who see video games as an art form, are often reluctant to consider them a &#x201C;true&#x201D; art form.&#xA0; In other words, people often consider video games a &#x201C;lesser&#x201D; art form next to more traditional art forms such as literature, painting, film &amp; music. &#xD;&#xD;The silly thing is that video games are ALL of those traditional art forms combined in a format that allows for interactivity.&#xA0; In other words, video games are a mixture of different art forms that are combined using gameplay mechanics.&#xD;&#xD;So, why do people still argue that video games are not art?&#xA0; I imagine that it is their lack of understanding of the video game medium itself - their desire to over generalize video games into something that fits a particular mold, when in reality, video games are as diverse and complex as human society.&#xA0; These same people often try to generalize human society as well ;-)&#xD;&#xD;But seriously.....if we were to define video games as art, we&#x2019;d need to have some sort of solid definition of what art is.....and people disagree vehemently on the definition of art.&#xA0; For me, art is one of those things that is nearly impossible to describe, but you know it when you experience it.&#xA0; When you see a picture or hear a song that stirs emotion that the designer intended, you think "Wow - that is art!"&#xA0; And I&#x2019;ve had many &#x201C;Wow - that is art!&#x201D; moments playing video games over the years.&#xA0; Just think of when Halo came out - stunning visuals of an alien landscape, stirring music, and a plot that made you feel like you were in the middle of a sci-fi novel.&#xA0; Halo is art.&#xD;&#xD;The classifications that we've traditionally applied to other works of art don't necessarily fit the video game mold.&#xA0; And why should they?&#xA0; Gamers today have this immense vocabulary that describes the features of the games that they play - they can describe at length why a particular RPG (Role Playing Game) is better at fostering communication compared to another, or why a specific FPS (First Person Shooter) makes you feel as if you are fighting a lost war in some foreign time and country.&#xA0; It's as complex as the vocabulary used to describe the features of an impressionist painting or orchestral piece. So why would there be a need to attempt to describe video games using traditional art terminology?&#xA0; We&#x2019;ve already got that terminology....&#xD;&#xD;So, in many ways, I agree with Jim Preston - we should avoid talking about video games as art in the traditional sense altogether.&#xA0; Video games are an immersive medium that allows far more freedom of expression than traditional art forms.&#xA0; They can be abstract.&#xA0; They can be real.&#xA0; They can allow the player to experience empathy, reverence, excitement, sadness, joy, and relaxation.&#xA0; Visuals, gameplay and music combine together to make that happen in a way that is unique to video games.&#xD;&#xD;Not only are video games art, they are a new kind of medium that begs for a more impressive label.&#xA0; So instead of calling them art, we could call them art++&#xA0; ;-)&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="12_Entry_1_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
