<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:32:44 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Revisiting the coolest 80s arcade - Tempest&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, September 1, 2017&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;&#xD;If you grew up in the 80s, you probably played a game on an &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;arcade machine&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  After all, arcade machines were everywhere - movie theaters, shopping malls, pizza parlors, convenience stores, and even dedicate video arcades that provided nothing but arcade machines and refreshments.  &#xD;&#xD;Those that played a lot of arcade games were affectionately called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;vidiots&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  &#xD;&#xD;I was a vidiot.&#xD;&#xD;And the arcade game that had the coolest graphics and gameplay in the 80s was &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Atari&#x2019;s Tempest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.  &#xD;&#xD;As you can see to the left, it even had the coolest artwork and cabinet shape of any arcade machine at the time - the angular design and spacey graphics made it stand out next to other arcade machines.  When it comes to arcade manufacturers, Atari was always the one that made sure that their cabinets drew plenty of visual interest!&#xD;&#xD;Designed by the same guy who created the equally popular Atari Missile Command arcade game (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dave Theurer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;), Tempest was different in that it boasted bleeding edge &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;vector graphics&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; that are stunning even by today&#x2019;s standards!&#xD;&#xD;To produce these vector graphics, Tempest didn&#x2019;t use a standard TV cathode ray tube (CRT) display like most other video games of the time.  Instead, it used a special &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;vector CRT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; that was more like a multi-color oscilloscope - it drew lines on the screen instead of pixels.  Vector CRTs were much more expensive to produce, and pretty much died out in the 80s since they didn&#x2019;t have a large market outside video games.  Of the 800+ arcade games produced during the 1970s and 1980s, only 33 were vector-based.&#xD;&#xD;Unlike most other vector games, Tempest was also designed from ground up with the features of color vector graphics in mind.  In short, your player sits at the edge of a 3D tunnel-like vector-generated platform - you spin your player around the platform and shoot enemies that are rapidly coming out of the tunnel at you.  After destroying the enemies, you warp using a 3D zoom effect to the next level, which will use a different tunnel-like platform layout.  &#xD;&#xD;To get a better idea of the gameplay and graphics, watch this video of me playing Tempest in my basement on &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;YouTube:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/o4FaCrx7gfQ"&gt;https://youtu.be/o4FaCrx7gfQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;Tempest is also heavily featured in the 1984 movie &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Night of the Comet&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, where Catherine Mary Stewart plays a cabaret (mid-sized) Tempest arcade machine in the movie theatre she works at, and prides herself on monopolizing all the high score entries.  Near the beginning of the movie, she gets upset that someone with the initials DMK placed a score on the high score table, and the identity of DMK is revealed at the end.  The high score on the Tempest arcade machine in the movie is &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;296,844&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;I love seeing how arcade games are reflected in pop culture, such as movies.  As a result, I made it my goal to make sure I got a score that was higher than the high score in the movie.  With lots of practice, I managed to do it (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;298,026&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; as shown to the left)!&#xD;&#xD;This was no small feat, because after powering on a Tempest arcade machine, the latest level you can start at is level 9.  And to get more than 290,000 points, you have to get to level 36!  &#xD;&#xD;Luckily, Tempest arcade machines have a small amount of non-volatile RAM that permanently stores the top three scores, so my high score will be there every time I turn on the machine ;-)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_Entry_1_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
