<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nature on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/nature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nature on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/nature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Your Hiking Experience</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/hiking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/hiking/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved exploring nature on a good hike, whether it be with other people, my dog, or solo. Hiking builds both physique and mental clarity, and the &amp;ldquo;hiker&amp;rsquo;s high&amp;rdquo; is pure bliss.
There are many things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years that have helped me maximize my own hiking experience. Some I learned from trial-and-error, while others I learned from fellow hikers, my own physician, or from online hiking forums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Trails</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/trails/city/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/trails/city/</guid>
      <description>rare Charitable Research Reserve (Cambridge) The rare Charitable Research Reserve is a community-based urban land trust. They maintain a series of amazing trails within the Blair/Galt area of Cambridge along the south side of the Grand River. The trails along the river are part of a gorgeous escarpment that contains exposed rock and fossils from the Silurian period. There are also trails across alvars and open fields with two Osprey towers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trails in Algonquin Provincial Park</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/trails/algonquin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/trails/algonquin/</guid>
      <description>Mizzy Lake Trail This is the trail where you can see the most wildlife in Algonquin park. You&amp;rsquo;ll wind through 11km of lakes, marshes and forests. My daughter and I saw massive turtles, were followed by otters who mocked us, and even stood 2 feet away from a moose who crossed our path when she realized her foal was on the other side. The pic at the top of this page is of my daughter resting shortly after we found the remains of a grey jay (now officially called a Canada jay) that was likely eaten by a pine marten.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
