<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:40:24 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;RIM is dead.  Long live RIM.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, December 16, 2011&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The worst possible news for RIM right now is a delay in bringing some sort of modern product to market.&#xA0; In other words, delaying their QNX &#x201C;killer&#x201D; smartphone.&#xA0; But that is exactly what they announced last night - QNX phones won&#x2019;t be ready until the end of 2012.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;The problem is that they are already behind their competitors with little chance at turning the company around and maintaining a big presence in the smartphone market.&#xA0; This delay will pretty much cripple their chances of catching up with iPhone and Android.&#xD;&#xD;I sort of feel sorry for RIM though - they are a bureaucratic mess at all levels that really doesn&#x2019;t know how to change fast enough to meet market needs because they never had to before.&#xA0; Apple and Android come along and ate their cake.&#xA0; Poor RIM.&#xD;&#xD;On the other hand, there is part of me that doesn&#x2019;t feel sorry for those RIMtards because their success in the past developed into a culture of extreme arrogance at all levels (spawned from the top of course ;-).&#xA0; You know the old saying:&#xA0; What goes around, comes around.&#xA0; And payback is a bitch.&#xD;&#xD;And speaking of payback, check out the headlines I found on Google News today from this past month:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;RIM's Holiday Slogan: "Ho Ho Holy Crap, We're Desperate"&#xD;&#xD;RIM&#x2019;s Dim Chance of Staying Alive&#xD;&#xD;iPhone Crowned New King Of The Enterprise&#xD;&#xD;RIM Announces Two More SnoozeBerrys&#xD;&#xD;RIM's BlackBerry branding decisions still confusing&#xD;&#xD;How low can RIM go?&#xD;&#xD;App Developer Support Dwindling for RIM, Suggests Survey&#xD;&#xD;iPhone Boots BlackBerry from Business World&#xD;&#xD;RIM's decline prompts calls for company break up&#xD;&#xD;Rim Skids Redux&#xD;&#xD;Does RIM still have a chance of turning things around?&#xD;&#xD;RIM: It's Time For A Change At The Top&#xD;&#xD;Not much silver lining for RIM fans&#xD;&#xD;Blackberry Maker Takes Another Wallop As It Slips Below Book Value&#xD;&#xD;RIM's Struggles Continue Amid Issues, Product Delays&#xD;&#xD;RIM's Stock Falls Below Book Value &#xD;&#xD;BlackBerry Outage Prompts Class Action Suit &#xD;&#xD;BlackBerry maker's shares fall to seven-year low&#xD;&#xD;RIM hit with consumer lawsuits over BlackBerry outage&#xD;&#xD;Apple discovers last unkicked spot on RIM's ass, kicks it&#xD;&#xD;BlackBerry 'on a knife edge'&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;RIM share target slashed as PlayBook price falls&#xD;&#xD;The Only Reason to Use a PlayBook Is DOS&#xD;&#xD;Apple surpasses BlackBerry in enterprise&#xD;&#xD;BlackBerry Is Being Beaten at Its Own Game -- by the iPhone &#xD;&#xD;BlackBerry 7 sales seen slowing, iPhone 4S &amp; Android bad news for RIM &#xD;&#xD;Has RIM Lost Its Way?&#xD;&#xD;RIM in a Downward Motion After Analyst Bashing&#xD;&#xD;No Christmas in RIMville&#xD;&#xD;Blackberry's Research in Demotion&#xD;&#xD;RIM story could get worse, Wall Street says&#xD;&#xD;Pressure Mounts on RIM&#xD;&#xD;Investors punish RIM for grim outlook&#xD;&#xD;BlackBerry 10 Phone Delay: Is This the End of RIM? &#xD;&#xD;RIM offers dismal outlook, shares tumble&#xD;&#xD;Voices Grow for RIM Management Shakeup&#xD;&#xD;How Apple's iPhone and Google's Android Left BlackBerry in the Dust&#xD;&#xD;RIM is earning a reputation as the successor to Microsoft as the "biggest loser" in &#xD;smartphone sales&#xD;&#xD;RIM reaps grim 2011&#xD;&#xD;Still Grimm at RIM&#xD;&#xD;Why Is RIM Going Dim?&#xD;&#xD;RIM investor confidence 'in the pits'&#xD;&#xD;Time for a leadership change at RIM&#xD;&#xD;A look at troubles for BlackBerry and its maker&#xD;&#xD;A True Race To The Bottom For Nokia And RIM&#xD;&#xD;Stop Lying to Your Customers, RIM&#xD;&#xD;Everyone Has Ideas to Resurrect Research in Motion &#x2014; Does RIM?&#xD;&#xD;Want a BlackBerry 10 phone? Don't hold your breath&#xD;&#xD;Chances of a Research In Motion Turnaround Slim: Analyst&#xD;&#xD;CNBC's Jon Fortt: "RIM's Guidance is Awful"&#xD;&#xD;RIM's Forecast Misses Estimates as BlackBerry Loses Luster&#xD;&#xD;RIM will end year with less than 1% of global tablet market: IDC&#xD;&#xD;Whither, RIM? Looks like nowhere but down&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="16_RIM_is_dead._Long_live_RIM._files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
