<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:57:17 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Restoring a Galaga arcade machine&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Thursday, August 14, 2014&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;A while ago, I picked up a Galaga control panel (with new overlay), coin door, bezel and marquee in excellent condition from two arcade collectors that I know.  &#xD;&#xD;The reason these parts existed without the cabinet was likely because Galaga cabinets were made of pressboard - over time, the wood swells due to humidity, and water damage accelerates this dramatically!  Since most arcades you find today were likely moved around a lot and stored in some dingy warehouse at one time, it&#x2019;s hard to find a Galaga arcade cabinet in excellent condition, so people often remove the parts and ditch the cabinet itself.&#xD;&#xD;The same is not true of Ms. Pac-man cabinets, since they were made of plywood.  Even if they were stored in a dingy warehouse, they are likely in good, restorable shape.  And better yet, Ms. Pac-man cabinets have the exact same dimensions as a Galaga cabinet!  After all, they were both manufactured at the exact same time by Midway, and in the same factory.&#xD;&#xD;So when a friend of mine wanted to get rid of his Ms. Pac-man cabinet to make way for a pinball machine, I bought it off of him and started the restoration.  To the right is a picture of the machine after we moved it into my basement (we removed the monitor before moving to make it much lighter!).&#xD;&#xD;First things first, I stripped off all parts down to the wood, applied pro bond wood filler to the bottom edges to strengthen them, added new leg levelers,  and then painted the entire cabinet (inside and out!) using a flat black high-grade enamel that doesn&#x2019;t require priming.&#xD;&#xD;Next, I added new t-molding, some new old stock (NOS) kickplate art, and the restored coin door (with a new Midway plate) as shown below:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Next, I added the rest of the hardware (latches, brackets, speaker, grills, etc.) and hooked up the marquee and light.  Then I applied some nice new side art that a friend of mine printed up - he actually has some professional printing equipment that produces better art than you can buy on the Internet - just check out the quality:&#xD;&#xD;Next up, I added the Wells-Gardiner monitor and wired up the guts.  I have an original Galaga board in it in excellent condition, but I built a new wiring harness and wired it up to a nice Sony switching power supply, conditioner and isolation transformer (needed for the monitor).  &#xD;&#xD;I mounted the Galaga boards to the side using a Happ PCB mount on a piece of plywood (to leave enough room for the video connector that is on the back), and mounted the rest (power supply, isolation transformer, etc.) to a piece of plywood at the bottom of the cab:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Next, I mounted added the CRT plexi and insert and turned it on.  And voila!  Everything worked (just had to turn the sound down ;-)&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;After adding the bezel and control panel, it looked pretty good, and looks great next to my Missile Command upright and Asteroids cabaret:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="14_Restoring_a_Galaga_arcade_machine_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
