<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20190818" date="2019-08-18 21:41:31 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Microtransactions - then and now&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, August 17, 2014&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;It&#x2019;s not hard to find a parent today who complains about how the games on their kid&#x2019;s phone, tablet or computer keep asking for money.  &#xD;&#xD;Many games today are free (or very cheap) to download and play, but offer virtual items and add-ons of various types that cost extra.  While these items are normally inexpensive (most are a dollar or two), the amount of extra items that you buy within these games adds up pretty quickly.  You can easily burn $20 in virtual items in a short period of time, and you don&#x2019;t get anything tangible in return.....just more ability or extra gameplay within the game itself.  &#xD;&#xD;Essentially, this monetization model follows the good old &#x201C;first one is free&#x201D; model where game developers encourage people to play the game (after all, it&#x2019;s free!).  After players install the game and get hooked, they&#x2019;ll want more, and that&#x2019;s when costs for virtual items or additional levels come into play.  These costs are often called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;microtransactions &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;because you are only spending a small amount of money (e.g. $0.99), but you are doing so at frequent intervals throughout the game. &#xD;&#xD;What parents often forget is that this model has been around since the dawn of video games.  Take the good old video arcade in the late 1970s and early 1980s, for example.  Game developers back then strived to make a game that followed these two golden rules:&#xD;    #1 A game should be easy to learn but difficult to master (also called Bushnell&#x2019;s Law) &#xD;    #2 A game should provide about 3 minutes of gameplay per quarter (for a good player)&#xD;&#xD;If you walked into an arcade in the early 1980s, you&#x2019;d drop a quarter into Pac-man, lose all three of your lives within a minute (for the average player), and then insert another quarter to play another game or Pac-man, or move to another game and put in a quarter for about a minute of gameplay.  You&#x2019;d burn through $5 in quarters within the hour and beg your parents for more money.  Or, if you were like me, you&#x2019;d spend all of your paper route money on arcade games, and then beg your parents for more money.   You could easily drop more than $20 on arcade games in a single week.&#xD;&#xD;Essentially, arcade games required that the player drop a small amount of money into the arcade machine at frequent intervals just like microtransactions today. And what did you get for your quarters?  Just a short period of fun gameplay.  Nothing tangible.  I&#x2019;m sure that my parents complained to others about how arcade games kept asking for money.&#xD;&#xD;Sure, there are other, &#x201C;but-it-now&#x201D; games out there that you can play on your PC or console that cost $70-80 and don&#x2019;t offer microtransactions (or other downloadable content).  Players buy these expensive-but-successful games because they know they&#x2019;ll get 50+ hours of gameplay out of it.  However, there are also plenty of equally-successful games that are free but contain microtransactions to maintain gameplay, and you&#x2019;ll find these games on nearly every platform today, including PC, console, mobile tablet/phone, and so on.  &#xD;&#xD;In the end, both the &#x201C;but-it-now&#x201D; and microtransaction game models exist so that game developers can make money (yes, it actually costs money to develop a game!).  Which model you choose as a game developer largely depends on the game type and intended audience.  But the microtransaction model is the oldest monetization model in the game industry, and one that likely isn&#x2019;t going away any time soon.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="17_Entry_1_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
