<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200225" date="2020-02-25 20:57:18 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Looking back at the arcade bootleg industry&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Monday, August 25, 2014&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Back in golden age of video games (1970s &amp; 1980s), there was no copy protection on arcade games.  Since the arcade game program itself was stored on removable ROM (Read Only Memory) chips on the PCB, anyone who had the right hardware could easily extract the ROM chips and read the game program.&#xA0; &#xD;&#xD;Many people did just that - they would take a copy of the game, build a PCB to hold the game that was similar to the original, and make a few small programs to do anything that was stored in a custom chip on the original game PCB.&#xA0;&#xA0; The end result was a bootleg arcade game PCB that was identical (or 99% identical) to the original arcade game PCB.&#xD;&#xD;Bootleg PCBs were much cheaper for arcade owners to buy since the people who made the bootleg boards didn&#x2019;t have any costs associated with creating the game - they just needed to create the custom PCB......which could be done in mere weeks, since most original arcade games also listed the PCB schematics within the manual.&#xA0; Plus, bootleg PCB manufacturers only went after popular selling games to maximize their profit!  You&#x2019;ll find bootlegs of Space Invaders, Pac-man, Ms. Pac-man, Galaga, Centipede, Q*bert, Arkanoid, Tetris, and many many more....&#xD;&#xD;In Canada, arcades and other businesses were more cost-conscious....plus, FBI bootleg warning stickers had no effect whatsoever since that was a U.S. thing.  As a result, it wasn&#x2019;t hard to find bootleg arcade games at your local arcade, pizza parlour, convenience store or shopping mall.&#xD;&#xD;The most common way that arcade operators implemented bootleg games was to buy a bootleg PCB and matching bootleg marquee and put them in either:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	A generic arcade cabinet &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;                        or &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	An existing arcade cabinet that wasn&#x2019;t making money because the game fell out of style (this is called a &#x201C;conversion&#x201D; in arcade-speak)&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Examples of these can still be seen today - the picture below left is a bootleg Tetris game installed in an Atari Liberator arcade cabinet at a local game store (Liberator was a terrible game that didn&#x2019;t make money, but Tetris was quite profitable), and the picture below right is a bootleg Galaga game in a generic arcade cabinet at a local burger joint next to a Ms. Pac-man cabinet that contains a bootleg Ms. Pac-man PCB (likely to replace the original Ms. Pac-man PCB when it died).  Ironically, Galaga and Ms. Pac-man are the two most commonly bootlegged games from the golden age of video games (the Gallag machines in the picture at the top of this post are common bootleg versions of Galaga).&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Although less common, some arcade games were sold as a complete package, including a custom arcade cabinet!  These games were often sold under a different name.  For example, one of the most common bootlegs of Space Invaders in Canada was &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jatre Spectre&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/BA54AEDB-3A30-4102-B029-FFF4A88F90E9"&gt;see my earlier post about it here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;).   &#xD;&#xD;It was also common to find arcade games made by Sidam (an Italian bootleg arcade manufacturer). Sidam made a bootleg of Centipede called &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Magic Worm&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; that looked very cool - the picture to the right is a Magic Worm cabinet that was upgraded to a Multicade (the trackball was replaced with a joystick and buttons).&#xD;&#xD;The Magic Worm PCB shown below is a good example of how bootleggers had to work around proprietary chips. Since the POKEY sound chip used in the original Atari Centipede game was proprietary and not available for purchase, Sidam had to use the AY-3-8910A sound chip instead and make some minor modifications to the game program to work with it.   The CPU (MOS 6502) is the long vertical chip in the lower left of the picture below, and the AY-3-8910A is the shorter vertical chip to the right of it.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;From a player perspective, it didn&#x2019;t matter whether you dropped your quarter into an original or bootleg arcade game - you got the same fun gameplay experience.   However, from an arcade operator perspective, the much cheaper bootleg arcade games meant that you could purchase more arcade machines in total.  And this ultimately led to more arcade machines in places around town that wouldn&#x2019;t have had them otherwise.  As a result, arcade bootlegs weren&#x2019;t necessarily a bad thing - arcade manufacturers still made a fortune from selling their games, and bootleg manufacturers expanded the arcade presence in the marketplace.  And in the end, it was all just fun and games ;-)&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="25_Looking_back_at_the_arcade_bootleg_industry_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
