<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="6CD99A98-03EA-45F6-9464-3BE6AB01739F">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20200628" date="2020-06-28 12:32:19 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;What I have learned about blogging&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Thursday, August 7, 2014&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;I started blogging back in 2005, about the same time I started expanding my personal website.  I didn&#x2019;t know much about blogging back then, other than it stood for &#x201C;web log&#x201D;, and was generally considered &#x201C;good&#x201D; and &#x201C;the way of the future&#x201D; thanks to Internet consensus at the time. &#xD;&#xD;My early blog posts were short and uninteresting, but I stuck with it, evolved my blogging techniques, and along the way learned what makes a good blog post, the types of things that shouldn&#x2019;t be in blogs, and how to maintain a blog over a long period of time.  In this blog post, I&#x2019;m going to share what I&#x2019;ve learned by explaining my seven golden blog rules:&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#1 Treat a blog as an information spreading tool.  &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	A blog is essentially a multi-purpose information spreading tool that fills a gap where other tools don&#x2019;t.  This means that blogs are not an all-purpose online communication tool that can replace other forms of online communication.  &#xD;	&#x2022;	People simply read blogs to learn information or garnish new views on events or topics.  People read blog posts that they&#x2019;ve found in Google search results on a particular topic, and often share links to blog posts they&#x2019;ve found useful on social media sites. &#xD;	&#x2022;	A blog should not be a personal diary.  Don&#x2019;t create a blog post that has information of interest only to you.  People on the Internet really don&#x2019;t care that much about you....they want information that is useful for them.&#xD;	&#x2022;	A blog is not a social media tool like Facebook or Twitter.  Don&#x2019;t create a blog post whose purpose is to share a cheeky picture you found online - Facebook and Twitter are for that.  Blog posts are a way of spreading information, not cat pictures.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#2 Make sure your blog post has a good topic and is a worthwhile read.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Remember that blog posts show up in Google results, and rank higher in the results list if other people read them and refer to them on other websites.  As a result, choose a topic that is near-and-dear to you, but offers information or viewpoints that aren&#x2019;t already rampant across the Internet.  &#xD;	&#x2022;	Blogging for posterity sake is a good use of a blog (after all, blog stands for &#x201C;web log&#x201D;).  This could include summarizing events (conferences, presentations, industry events, anniversaries of historic significance, etc.), or relaying well-researched information on topics that aren&#x2019;t  necessarily well-known or well-known from your particular viewpoint.  For example, I&#x2019;ve done several blog posts about obscure technologies, vintage computers and rare arcade games,  If you Google &#x201C;Pinbo&#x201D; (a rare game by Jaleco in 1984), my Pinbo review blog post will definitely be in the search results since there is very little online about that game.  If someone wants to learn about Pinbo, they&#x2019;ll likely read my blog.  Similarly, my post about the origin of the no-shoot cheat in the famous arcade game Galaga has been referred to by many other sites (including Reddit, whose traffic to that particular page took down my website last year). &#xD;	&#x2022;	Another good use for a blog post is to relay your opinion/critique regarding a particular topic to others (e.g. why you think the DMCA is evil).  However, make sure you treat the reader as if they know very little of your topic beforehand - provide background information, and explain your rationale in as clear and detailed a manner as necessary (e.g. what is the DMCA, how copyright started and evolved, how copyright is abused today, etc.).&#xD;	&#x2022;	Make sure you give your readers enough content to make it a worthwhile read. A good blog post should take far longer to create than it should take to read. I&#x2019;ve written blog posts that have taken many hours to write, often split across several days.  That being said, I&#x2019;ve written short blog posts (under 100 words) that I consider equally good.....but my best blog posts are often over 1000 words.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#3 Make your blog post easy to read&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Remember that the main purpose of blogs are to convey information, and it should be effective at doing so. &#xD;	&#x2022;	Ensure that your blog post isn&#x2019;t unnecessarily wordy or difficult to understand.  Be as direct and succinct as possible, and use short form and bullets where appropriate. &#xD;	&#x2022;	Also make sure your blog post has a good visual style, and include pictures as much as possible.  By having well-placed pictures throughout your blog post, you&#x2019;ll entice the reader, make the read more enjoyable, as well as support key points in your blog post.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Many people today read blog posts they&#x2019;ve Googled on their phone or tablet - as a result, it&#x2019;s very important to make sure your blog is mobile-friendly.  This means choosing a page width that is narrow and clean text fonts that are easy to read from a distance (like my blog ;-) &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#4 Write in proper English!!!&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	This is a blog post, not a text message.  Don&#x2019;t write like you&#x2019;re an idiot because most people will think you are.....and won&#x2019;t read past the first few sentences.  Why write a blog post if no one will read it other than yourself?  Diaries are for that.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Now, you can have the odd bad form for fun (like the !!! in my title above, for example) - it doesn&#x2019;t have to be perfect by any means, but it should be something that people think would be worthwhile sharing with others. &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#5 Edit, edit and edit your blog post before uploading to your website&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	No matter how good you are, you&#x2019;ll find broken sentences, typos, and sections that just don&#x2019;t make sense when you read through a blog post you just typed.  And no one wants to read a crappy blog post......so re-read, and edit your blog post several times to make sure everything is grammatically &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;CORRECT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, has a solid &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;STRUCTURE&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;FLOWS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; from beginning to end!  &#xD;	&#x2022;	And just like I&#x2019;ve done in the previous bulleted point, add emphasis and color to ensure that the points you are trying to convey are coming across the way you want them to.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#6 Promote your blog&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	Each time you finish a new blog post, post a link to it on Facebook, Google+, Twitter, and so on.  After all,  you want people to read your blog.....you spent time and effort writing it!&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;#7 Revisit and revise previous blog posts &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Revisiting&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; previous blog posts is essentially revisiting key topics that you spent a great deal of effort on in the past.   As you build up a large number of blog posts, revisiting them can become a source of inspiration for new blog posts or a source of information for other events (e.g. presentations). &#xD;	&#x2022;	&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Revising&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; previous blog posts may sound like you are changing history, but that is a good thing in many cases.  &#xD;	&#x2022;	You may find a better picture for a past blog post that you wish to incorporate, or you may wish to expand on or correct a particular point in a previous blog post after learning new information.  &#xD;	&#x2022;	You may also want to update broken hyperlinks in your blog post (many hyperlinks change over time),  or delete a blog post that really shouldn&#x2019;t have been posted in the first place (perhaps it was better as a Facebook rant).&#xD;	&#x2022;	If it is a personal viewpoint that is a product of the time period, you may want to avoid editing it and instead add an afterword section with new information - this will preserve what you were thinking about at the time as well as keep the blog post current.&#xD;	&#x2022;	Whatever the situation, don&#x2019;t be afraid to improve your previous blog posts - if you&#x2019;ve followed my advice in this post, your blog posts are a valuable source of information for others and worthy of updating.  &lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="7_What_I_have_learned_about_blogging_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="619px" height="398px"/>
</content>
