<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/microsoft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft on Jason Eckert&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Installing a Fedora Linux ARM VM from a Raw Image</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-arm-raw-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-arm-raw-image/</guid>
      <description>Many professionals who work in Information Technology (IT) or software development use an ARM-based PC, such as an Apple Silicon Mac, Snapdragon Elite X Windows Copilot+ PC, or an ARM Linux workstation such as the System76 Thelio Astra. Similarly, many students learning IT or software development may also use an ARM-based PC. For all of these people, it&amp;rsquo;s commonplace to deploy Linux virtual machines (VMs) on a PC using hypervisor software to test cloud apps, host server software, or run specialized tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copilot&#43; PC Review: Windows on ARM is finally here</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/windows-on-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/windows-on-arm/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2017, I wrote a blog post predicting intense competition between Intel x86-based and ARM-based PCs. And finally, after many years of lukewarm development efforts on the part of Microsoft and Qualcomm, that competition is here with Windows 11 Copilot+ PCs running powerful ARM-based Qualcomm Snapdragon X Elite CPUs with built in graphics and AI acceleration.
As shown in the desktop screenshot at the top of this post I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a Copilot+ PC as a productivity and development workstation this month, and I must say that I&amp;rsquo;m thoroughly impressed overall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Artificial Intelligence (AI)</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/demystifying-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/demystifying-ai/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re tired of all of the Artificial Intelligence (AI) buzz recently, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. Most of us in the tech industry are as well. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll outline what AI is and how it works, why you&amp;rsquo;re hearing so much AI hype nowadays, and how AI functionality will eventually be built into the software products we use.
So, what is AI? Firstly, AI is nothing new. The term itself was coined in 1955 by John McCarthy as a way to discuss how computers could make decisions based on inputs and logic provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending the life of an Intel-based Mac using Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/intel-mac-win11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/intel-mac-win11/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2020, Apple introduced the first Macs that used Apple Silicon processors instead of Intel ones, and this transition from Intel to Apple Silicon was completed earlier this year across Apple&amp;rsquo;s entire product line. While Apple promised they&amp;rsquo;d continue supporting macOS on Intel-based Macs for the near future, those of us who remember Apple&amp;rsquo;s previous transitions from M68k-to-PowerPC and PowerPC-to-Intel know full well that this support is going to end sooner than later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential keyboard shortcuts (Windows/macOS/Linux/UNIX)</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Following are some shortcuts that I believe all desktop users should be familiar with. It is not a complete list by any means, and does not include virtual desktop or app pinning shortcuts as I felt those were beyond the scope of common desktop shortcuts. If you feel I omitted a common shortcut, email me (jason.eckert@trios.com) and I&amp;rsquo;ll add it to the list!
1. Windows shortcuts The Windows (⊞) key on your keyboard has the Windows logo printed on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first textbook is now in its sixth edition</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-sixth-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/linux-sixth-edition/</guid>
      <description>While I&amp;rsquo;ve written many textbooks on different topics over the past two decades, my favourite subject area by far is Linux. After all, Linux has evolved to be one of the most foundational topics in tech education. Information Technology (IT) fields such as server/network administration, cloud administration, cybersecurity, and software development now require a solid grasp of the Linux operating system. The first textbook I wrote (Linux+ Guide to Linux Certification) was in 2001 for Course Technology (now Cengage).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISCy business: The long and convoluted rise of today&#39;s dominant computing platform</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/riscy-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/riscy-business/</guid>
      <description>RISC vs CISC Traditionally, most computing platforms were built with the burden of software in mind. To ensure that a software program could be written easily and with fewer instructions, additional circuitry was added to the central processing unit (CPU) to compensate. This was referred to as complex instruction set computing (CISC). CISC architecture is still common today thanks to the x86 architecture used by Intel and AMD CPUs in most workstations and servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of technology</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>Technology is a crazy ride, and like that lyric in the Talking Heads song Once in a Lifetime, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;you may ask yourself, well, how did I get here?&amp;rdquo;
If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck, because this post is a no-nonsense, give-me-the-big-picture timeline of what the heck happened in the technology landscape these past 50 years. Of course, not every little detail is in there. Just those that are actually important (in my expert opinion, of course ;-) Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most people don&#39;t want a computer</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</guid>
      <description>In the past few decades, people of all ages across North America have become technology-literate in some way or another. Many of them weren&amp;rsquo;t introduced to technology via desktop or laptop computers, but instead through a smartphone or tablet. Similarly, many desktop and laptop users have switched to using their smartphone or tablet over the past decade to interact with the online world.
After all, smartphones and tablets are incredibly easy to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft turns 45</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-turns-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-turns-45/</guid>
      <description>On April 4th 1975, a small company called Microsoft was founded in Albuquerque, New Mexico. They would later become the most pivotal company in the technology world, and their co-founder Bill Gates would become the world’s most prolific philanthropist.
Like many tech companies, Microsoft has had a colourful past. Started by two whiz kids (Paul Allen and Bill Gates), they started by selling operating system and supporting software.
Xenix UNIX (later sold to SCO) was their first operating system product in 1980, followed closely by MS-DOS in 1981 (which they originally purchased from Tim Paterson).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Gates steps down today</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/bill-gates-steps-down-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/bill-gates-steps-down-today/</guid>
      <description>Today is Bill Gates’ last day at the helm of the largest software company in history: Microsoft. Bill, thanks for creating and running a company that has transformed the industry like no other - I wish you the best!
Although I am not a huge fan of proprietary software today or some of the things that Microsoft has done (e.g. FUD) and is currently doing (e.g. Vista), I have always had a large amount of respect for Microsoft’s role in industry - in the early 1990’s, I really wanted to work for Microsoft like everyone else, and I was an early Windows advocate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of 2007</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-end-of-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-end-of-2007/</guid>
      <description>It has truly been an exciting year, and I wish to take a few moments to reflect on some of the most important events of 2007 in geekdom:
Halo 3 being released (I love that game)
Microsoft pissing off millions with Vista
The death of SCO (may they rot in hell)
Apple releasing the iPhone and iPod touch (the next generation interface for everything)
The introduction of the Nokia N810 Internet Tablet running Linux (drool&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Energize IT conference</title>
      <link>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-energize-it-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-energize-it-conference/</guid>
      <description>Today, I attended the Microsoft Energize IT Conference at the Convention Centre in Toronto. Having been to many Microsoft conferences in the past, I was reluctant to attend since most of them were a biased propaganda show for sales people and managers.
Energize IT was a typical Microsoft conference: lots of money, free food and swank. When the keynote presentations started, it looked promising. The first few speakers emphasized the need for feedback from the audience such that Microsoft can adapt to the changing needs of their customers, as well as the need for a sense of “community” amongst us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
