<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft on Welcome to My Site!</title>
    <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/microsoft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft on Welcome to My Site!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jasoneckert.github.io/tags/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of technology</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/a-brief-history-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>Technology is a crazy ride, and like that lyric in the Talking Heads song Once in a Lifetime, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;you may ask yourself, well, how did I get here?&amp;rdquo;
If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck, because this post is a no-nonsense, give-me-the-big-picture timeline of what the heck happened in the technology landscape these past 50 years. Of course, not every little detail is in there. Just those that are actually important (in my expert opinion, of course ;-) Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most people don&#39;t want a computer</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/most-people-dont-want-a-computer/</guid>
      <description>In the past few decades, people of all ages across North America have become technology-literate in some way or another. Many of them weren&amp;rsquo;t introduced to technology via desktop or laptop computers, but instead through a smartphone or tablet. Similarly, many desktop and laptop users have switched to using their smartphone or tablet over the past decade to interact with the online world.
After all, smartphones and tablets are incredibly easy to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft turns 45</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-turns-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-turns-45/</guid>
      <description>On April 4th 1975, a small company called Microsoft was founded in Albuquerque, New Mexico. They would later become the most pivotal company in the technology world, and their co-founder Bill Gates would become the world’s most prolific philanthropist.
Like many tech companies, Microsoft has had a colourful past. Started by two whiz kids (Paul Allen and Bill Gates), they started by selling operating system and supporting software.
Xenix UNIX (later sold to SCO) was their first operating system product in 1980, followed closely by MS-DOS in 1981 (which they originally purchased from Tim Paterson).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Gates steps down today</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/bill-gates-steps-down-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/bill-gates-steps-down-today/</guid>
      <description>Today is Bill Gates’ last day at the helm of the largest software company in history: Microsoft. Bill, thanks for creating and running a company that has transformed the industry like no other - I wish you the best!
Although I am not a huge fan of proprietary software today or some of the things that Microsoft has done (e.g. FUD) and is currently doing (e.g. Vista), I have always had a large amount of respect for Microsoft’s role in industry - in the early 1990’s, I really wanted to work for Microsoft like everyone else, and I was an early Windows advocate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of 2007</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-end-of-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/the-end-of-2007/</guid>
      <description>It has truly been an exciting year, and I wish to take a few moments to reflect on some of the most important events of 2007 in geekdom:
  Halo 3 being released (I love that game)
  Microsoft pissing off millions with Vista
  The death of SCO (may they rot in hell)
  Apple releasing the iPhone and iPod touch (the next generation interface for everything)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Energize IT conference</title>
      <link>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-energize-it-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jasoneckert.github.io/myblog/microsoft-energize-it-conference/</guid>
      <description>Today, I attended the Microsoft Energize IT Conference at the Convention Centre in Toronto. Having been to many Microsoft conferences in the past, I was reluctant to attend since most of them were a biased propaganda show for sales people and managers.
Energize IT was a typical Microsoft conference: lots of money, free food and swank. When the keynote presentations started, it looked promising. The first few speakers emphasized the need for feedback from the audience such that Microsoft can adapt to the changing needs of their customers, as well as the need for a sense of “community” amongst us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>